<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 18:21:43 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[HTTPCLIENT-1873] Kerberos delegation no longer working after HTTPCLIENT-1736 patch in version 4.5.3</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HTTPCLIENT-1873</link>
                <project id="12310360" key="HTTPCLIENT">HttpComponents HttpClient</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;In version 4.5.3, the following fix got applied to the httpclient library:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HTTPCLIENT-1736&quot; title=&quot;TGT is forwarded to server when using Kerberos authentication&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HTTPCLIENT-1736&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HTTPCLIENT-1736&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; do not request cred delegation by default when using Kerberos auth.&lt;br/&gt;
  Contributed by Oleg Kalnichevski &amp;lt;olegk at apache.org&amp;gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it says &quot;by default&quot;, when looking at the affected code it&apos;s not the case (i.e.: there is no way to request if we want it).  From our tests and my understanding of Kerberos, if a user account is not allowed to be used for delegation, then you can still request delegation, but when creating the user token, it&apos;ll simply not be applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins&gt;Affected area&lt;/ins&gt;:&lt;br/&gt;
In the class &quot;GSSSchemeBase&quot;, in the method &quot;createGSSContext&quot;, we need the following line added back:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;gssContext.requestCredDeleg(true);&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;b&gt;OR&lt;/b&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you insist of leaving it off for a reason I&apos;m not aware of, having a way, maybe through a system property, to say that we want it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IMHO, one of the main reason for using Kerberos in an enterprise environment is to be able to make use of delegation (double hop scenarios).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment>Windows,Linux</environment>
        <key id="13106055">HTTPCLIENT-1873</key>
            <summary>Kerberos delegation no longer working after HTTPCLIENT-1736 patch in version 4.5.3</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="4" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Minor</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="-1">Unassigned</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="UlrichColby">Ulrich Colby</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>easyfix</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 14:29:07 +0000</created>
                <updated>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 17:55:23 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 09:39:23 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>4.5.3</version>
                    <version>4.5.4</version>
                                    <fixVersion>5.0 Alpha3</fixVersion>
                                    <component>HttpClient (classic)</component>
                    <component>HttpClient (Windows)</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                    <workratio workratioPercent="0"/>
                                    <progress percentage="0">
                                    <originalProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#89afd7"/>
                                            </originalProgress>
                                                    <currentProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#51a825"/>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#ec8e00"/>
                                            </currentProgress>
                            </progress>
                                    <aggregateprogress percentage="0">
                                    <originalProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#89afd7"/>
                                            </originalProgress>
                                                    <currentProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#51a825"/>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#ec8e00"/>
                                            </currentProgress>
                            </aggregateprogress>
                                    <timeoriginalestimate seconds="7200">2h</timeoriginalestimate>
                            <timeestimate seconds="7200">2h</timeestimate>
                                        <comments>
                            <comment id="16186095" author="olegk" created="Fri, 29 Sep 2017 17:12:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Could you please raise a PR at Github with the changes you are proposing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16188045" author="ulrichcolby" created="Mon, 2 Oct 2017 13:44:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Oleg,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure!  I created the following PR against the 4.5.x branch: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UlrichColby/httpcomponents-client/pull/1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/UlrichColby/httpcomponents-client/pull/1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ulrich&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16188566" author="ulrichcolby" created="Mon, 2 Oct 2017 18:25:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As requested, PR against the &quot;5.0alpha2-RC1&quot; tag: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UlrichColby/httpcomponents-client/pull/2&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/UlrichColby/httpcomponents-client/pull/2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16189424" author="olegk" created="Tue, 3 Oct 2017 09:08:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=UlrichColby&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;UlrichColby&quot;&gt;UlrichColby&lt;/a&gt; I know next to nothing about Kerberos. I need help here. Your change pretty much reverts &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HTTPCLIENT-1736&quot; title=&quot;TGT is forwarded to server when using Kerberos authentication&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HTTPCLIENT-1736&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HTTPCLIENT-1736&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. How about using a constructor parameter defining whether or not Kerberos delegation should be used?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=kspang&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;kspang&quot;&gt;kspang&lt;/a&gt;, if you still care, could you please help us work out the best way to keep everyone happy (or at least content)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16189508" author="kspang" created="Tue, 3 Oct 2017 10:19:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As I read the code, the call to &lt;tt&gt;gssContext.requestCredDeleg&lt;/tt&gt; overrides the default in the &lt;tt&gt;krb5.conf&lt;/tt&gt; file on the system. I would say that the &lt;tt&gt;generateGSSToken&lt;/tt&gt; function should use the default, and if an application needs to override the default, it should use its own &lt;tt&gt;krb5.conf&lt;/tt&gt; file and set the property &lt;tt&gt;java.security.krb5.conf&lt;/tt&gt; to point to it. Alternatively, the application could extend the &lt;tt&gt;SPNegoScheme&lt;/tt&gt; class and override &lt;tt&gt;generateGSSToken&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, in my opinion there should be no call to &lt;tt&gt;gssContext.requestCredDeleg&lt;/tt&gt; at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I extended the class, because I needed to change not just this behaviour, but also to specify a server principal different from &quot;HTTP&quot;. There may be more things that people would want to tweak, so specifying constructor parameters for them all is probably impractical. Maybe some config object could be passed to the constructor.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16189929" author="ulrichcolby" created="Tue, 3 Oct 2017 16:23:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Karsten and Oleg,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do use a KRB5 file, what you say makes sense, however, my tests show something a little different happening.  First, without setting the java.security.krb5.conf property, it&apos;s supposed to use C:/windows/krb5.ini by default on Windows, or /etc/krb5.conf on Linux.  To confirm it&apos;s using it, if I turn on sun.security.krb5.debug=true, place a bad KDC server in the KRB5.ini, I see the failure to connect to it on the debug logging and finally end up receiving a 401.  Putting a working KDC server makes everything work.  The options &quot;forwardable=true&quot; (for delegation) and &quot;renewable=true&quot; are also inside the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I use HttpClient 4.5.2 (on a client), this is what I see happen in Wireshark (making a RESTful call):&lt;br/&gt;
1) A TGS-REQ is made, requesting FORWARDABLE, RENEWABLE-OK, I get a ticket back.&lt;br/&gt;
2) Then, right afterwards, a second request is made, with flags FORWARDBLE, FORWARDED, REWABLE-OK, I get a new ticket back.&lt;br/&gt;
3) I connect to the server which itself connects to a backend server, everything works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I use HttpClient 4.5.3, same conditions, this is what I see happen:&lt;br/&gt;
1) A TGS-REQ is made, requesting FORWADBLE, RENEWABLE-OK, I get a ticket back.&lt;br/&gt;
...no second request is made&lt;br/&gt;
2) Then it connects to the server which returns an error.  The server log shows that it gets a Principal, but when getDelegCreds (GSSCredential) is called, NULL is returned and therefore it can&apos;t make the call to the backend server (no delegation creds were forwarded).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&apos;t find some good hard documentation on GSSContext that definitely explains whether or not you&apos;re supposed to make the requestCredDeleg, so I went and looked at source code I could find (openjdk) for sun.security.jgss.GSSContextImpl (that is the GSSManager instanciates).  The variable &quot;reqCredDelegState&quot; is set to &quot;false&quot; by default.  It looks like nothing sets this variable to anything other than false, unless you call &quot;requestCredDeleg&quot; before &quot;initSecContext&quot; is called (which assigns something to &quot;mechCtxt&quot;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;public void requestCredDeleg(boolean state) throws GSSException &lt;/p&gt;
{
    if (mechCtxt == null)
        reqCredDelegState = state;
    }

&lt;p&gt;As the documentation says, however, you may ask for delegation, but depending on external factors, you may not get it. You then can confirm with getCredDelegState whether or not you got it or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You suggested extending SpnegoScheme.  I don&apos;t think it&apos;ll work for us if the SpnegoSchemeFactory and then the HttpClientBuilder each call one another in a chain and specifically create a SpnegoScheme instance. I&apos;m opened to alternate solutions however, if you believe this is a problem.  A System property or static flag could be used, or a way of making the SPNegoSchemeFactory instanciate a customizable &quot;GGSSchemeBase&quot; object.  What are your thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16191227" author="olegk" created="Wed, 4 Oct 2017 13:13:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=UlrichColby&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;UlrichColby&quot;&gt;UlrichColby&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
There is not much I can do here other that suggesting making the behavior configurable. One can either provide a Boolean (nullable) parameter to have &lt;tt&gt;requestCredDeleg&lt;/tt&gt; explicitly set to true or false, or left undefined or provide a more complex config class similar to &lt;tt&gt;RequestConfig&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to raise a PR with those changes to speed things up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16193165" author="ulrichcolby" created="Thu, 5 Oct 2017 16:43:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Oleg,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand and I agree.  Since most Kerberos related options in Java are configurable through System environment variables, then if you&apos;re okay with it, I was going to code/submit a PR that checks whether a System.getenv variable is set or not, i.e.: &quot;org.apache.httpclient.auth.spnego.requestcreddeleg&quot; &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;true,false&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; or left undefined.  Let me know if that&apos;s acceptable with you.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16193243" author="garydgregory" created="Thu, 5 Oct 2017 17:28:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Please consider making this code path configurable from the HttpClient builder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using system properties and environment variables is not a good thing in managed environments &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/sad.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16193374" author="olegk" created="Thu, 5 Oct 2017 18:20:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;HttpClient is very consistent in not using system properties for its configuration for reasons given by Gary. I personally do not have a strong preference here but would generally consider consistency within the same library important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16195153" author="ulrichcolby" created="Fri, 6 Oct 2017 19:47:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I understand your poibnt of vue.  If you&apos;ll allow though, let me try to illustrate just once more why I was leaning a bit more towards a system property solution.  If you disagree, then I&apos;ll modify the current solution to use a nullable Boolean as you suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see the &quot;SpnegoScheme&quot; class to be closer to the Kerberos world than it&apos;s higher-level HttpClient class.  In Java, when dealing with Kerberos, most options are passed by external files and system properties (i.e.: java.security.krb5.conf / java.security.auth.login.config / javax.security.auth.useSubjectCredsOnly... etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those type of system properties, as far as I know are seldom set at the O/S level as system or user environment variables.  They&apos;re either passed directly to the JVM with the -D option or directly in code with setProperty.  These options are expected to be set before or during the initialization of a program and then left alone for the lifespan of the JVM instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, you have the choice of doing it outside or programmatically in code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I can do to keep everyone happy, is a hybrid solution; Have a statically settable Boolean in case someone wants to explicitly set it.  Then, only if the Boolean isn&apos;t set, the System property would then be checked (only once, and set the Boolean if it exists).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;re not convinced, just tell me &quot;nay&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ulrich&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16195305" author="garydgregory" created="Fri, 6 Oct 2017 22:01:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi All.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this kind of sys prop twiddling is just hacking with global variables by another name. Using a static variable is no better. When I discussed this issue at work with the developer who did  our Kerberos module (using Kerby and custom bits), he did advise me explicitly &quot;please, no system properties&quot;. You can translate that to &quot;no global variables: no system properties, no environment variables, no static variables.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just think of living in a world of multi-tenancy...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16195620" author="olegk" created="Sat, 7 Oct 2017 09:12:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I could live with an enum parameter ON, OFF, DEFAULT, SYSPROP or some such. I do agree with Gary that system properties are essentially global variables and as such ought to be used with extreme care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16198625" author="ulrichcolby" created="Tue, 10 Oct 2017 12:56:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Oleg That sounds like the best option, I&apos;ll do that but forgo the SYSPROP option.  Are the 4.5.x branch &amp;amp; 5.0 alpha2-RC1 tag ok? Or should I be doing this on 4.6.x / 5.0..?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@Gary Thanks for your comments.  My opinion differs, but to satisfy both our and your requirement, I&apos;m planning to use an Enum only as a default value, configurable after the fact when an instance of GGSSchemeBase is created.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16204139" author="ulrichcolby" created="Fri, 13 Oct 2017 20:29:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Oleg / All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a PR for 4.5.x branch with what we discussed: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/UlrichColby/httpcomponents-client/pull/3&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/UlrichColby/httpcomponents-client/pull/3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Let me know if it&apos;s acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ulrich&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16205081" author="olegk" created="Sun, 15 Oct 2017 09:30:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=UlrichColby&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;UlrichColby&quot;&gt;UlrichColby&lt;/a&gt; Things look OK to me, but I generally dislike mutable stuff that can be made immutable. One thing I would like to do is to reduce the footprint of API changes if we want to add this feature to 4.5.x. Please see my review comments for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16214851" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 23 Oct 2017 09:17:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit cc58de13c5361d5ff98a839adc7b46eceb2f2bef in httpcomponents-client&apos;s branch refs/heads/4.6.x from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=olegk&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;olegk&quot;&gt;olegk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=httpcomponents-client.git;h=cc58de1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=httpcomponents-client.git;h=cc58de1&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HTTPCLIENT-1873&quot; title=&quot;Kerberos delegation no longer working after HTTPCLIENT-1736 patch in version 4.5.3&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HTTPCLIENT-1873&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HTTPCLIENT-1873&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Config option for Kerberos delegation&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16214874" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 23 Oct 2017 09:38:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit a4030759487b4663ed24f4bf8c27eb010efda75b in httpcomponents-client&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=olegk&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;olegk&quot;&gt;olegk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=httpcomponents-client.git;h=a403075&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=httpcomponents-client.git;h=a403075&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HTTPCLIENT-1873&quot; title=&quot;Kerberos delegation no longer working after HTTPCLIENT-1736 patch in version 4.5.3&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HTTPCLIENT-1873&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HTTPCLIENT-1873&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Config option for Kerberos delegation&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16214876" author="olegk" created="Mon, 23 Oct 2017 09:39:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Implemented in 4.6.x and 5.x. Please review and close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oleg&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16217712" author="ulrichcolby" created="Tue, 24 Oct 2017 21:13:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Excellent! Everything looks good from the config module to the client factory.  Thank you very much Oleg &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            8 years, 3 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i3kpsn:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>