<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 20:53:00 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[FLINK-21030] Broken job restart for job with disjoint graph</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21030</link>
                <project id="12315522" key="FLINK">Flink</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Building on top of bugs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21028&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21028&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21029&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21029&lt;/a&gt; : &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to stop a Flink application on YARN via savepoint which didn&apos;t succeed due to a possible bug/racecondition in shutdown (Bug 21028). Due to some reason, Flink attempted to restart the pipeline after the failure in shutdown (21029). The bug here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned: My jobgraph is disjoint and the pipelines are fully isolated. Lets say the original error occured in a single task of pipeline1. Flink then restarted the entire pipeline1, but pipeline2 was shutdown successfully and switched the state to FINISHED.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job thus was in kind of an invalid state after the attempt to stopping: One of two pipelines was running, the other was FINISHED. I guess this is kind of a bug in the restarting behavior that only all connected components of a graph are restarted, but the others aren&apos;t...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13353254">FLINK-21030</key>
            <summary>Broken job restart for job with disjoint graph</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="mapohl">Matthias Pohl</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="TheoD">Theo Diefenthal</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>pull-request-available</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 10:55:24 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 13:50:01 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 13:49:52 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.11.2</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.11.4</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>1.12.2</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>1.13.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Runtime / Coordination</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>12</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17267923" author="till.rohrmann" created="Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:29:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reporting this issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=TheoD&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;TheoD&quot;&gt;TheoD&lt;/a&gt;. I agree that the behaviour you observed is a bug. I think that we should do a global failover where we restart the whole job if the stop-with-savepoint operation fails. This will ensure that all tasks will be reset to the latest checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cc &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=zhuzh&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;zhuzh&quot;&gt;zhuzh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17268409" author="zhuzh" created="Wed, 20 Jan 2021 07:21:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Agreed to trigger a global failover to bring FINISHED tasks back to RUNNING if stop-with-savepoint fails. &lt;br/&gt;
Maybe right after the stopped checkpoint scheduler is restarted in &lt;tt&gt;SchedulerBase#stopWithSavepoint()&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17272108" author="mapohl" created="Tue, 26 Jan 2021 13:47:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Just to clarify: The expected behavior is then that the command still fails but the job will resume from the most recent checkpoint after this. I would proceed with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=zhuzh&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;zhuzh&quot;&gt;zhuzh&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s proposal which should be straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also looking into where we could test this behavior. Firstly, I identified &lt;tt&gt;JobMasterStopWithSavepointIT&lt;/tt&gt; as it seems to collect all the stop-with-savepoint related usecases. Unfortunately, this test class was unmaintained for a while due to wrong naming and is failing right now (this is covered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21031&quot; title=&quot;JobMasterStopWithSavepointIT test is not run due to wrong name&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-21031&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-21031&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). Alternatively, I&apos;d propose adding the test in &lt;tt&gt;SavepointITCase&lt;/tt&gt; to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21030&quot; title=&quot;Broken job restart for job with disjoint graph&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-21030&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-21030&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; not being depending on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21031&quot; title=&quot;JobMasterStopWithSavepointIT test is not run due to wrong name&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-21031&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-21031&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Do you have any objections against that?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17272186" author="till.rohrmann" created="Tue, 26 Jan 2021 15:52:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;No objections from my side.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17276539" author="mapohl" created="Mon, 1 Feb 2021 17:55:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I paired with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=chesnay&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;chesnay&quot;&gt;chesnay&lt;/a&gt; to look into the issue. We came up with a testcase covering the issue. We tried to emulate the problem by causing an Exception when cancelling the Source task (here, I&apos;m not 100% sure whether this is exactly the same usecase &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=TheoD&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;TheoD&quot;&gt;TheoD&lt;/a&gt; was describing in the issues description). But we were able to reproduce the described behavior. It turns out that the solution is a bit more complex than we thought (please correct me if I&apos;m wrong here): The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/60fb0f5c6e4e23759541a531e034f27f496e93b7/flink-runtime/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/runtime/scheduler/SchedulerBase.java#L1080&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;current implementation of SchedulerBase.stopWithSavepoint&lt;/a&gt; triggers the creation of a new savepoint and returns the completed checkpoint in case of success. The stopping of the execution happens implicitly through the &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; which calls &lt;tt&gt;AbstractInvokable#notifyheckpointCompleteAsync&lt;/tt&gt; on each executing source task. The &lt;tt&gt;stopWithSavepoint&lt;/tt&gt; method has no information about whether the actual stopping succeeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our case, the stopping failed while &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/60fb0f5c6e4e23759541a531e034f27f496e93b7/flink-runtime/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/runtime/scheduler/SchedulerBase.java#L1109&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;SchedulerBase.stopWithSavepoint&lt;/a&gt; waits for the &lt;tt&gt;ExecutionGraph&lt;/tt&gt; to terminate. The Source task got restarted. No termination of the &lt;tt&gt;ExecutionGraph&lt;/tt&gt; happens: The &lt;tt&gt;stopWithSavepoint&lt;/tt&gt; times out, instead.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17276846" author="zhuzh" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 04:09:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the investigation! &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=mapohl&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;mapohl&quot;&gt;mapohl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Does this mean that the future returned by &lt;tt&gt;checkpointCoordinator.triggerSynchronousSavepoint(...)&lt;/tt&gt; will no be completed exceptionally even if the savepoint fails or timed out? Because otherwise the triggering of failure handling in &lt;tt&gt;SchedulerBase#stopWithSavepoint(...)&lt;/tt&gt; will not require the terminationFuture of ExecutionGraph to be completed. If so, the restarting of stopped CheckpointScheduler does not work either and I think &lt;tt&gt;checkpointCoordinator.triggerSynchronousSavepoint(...)&lt;/tt&gt; needs to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17276909" author="mapohl" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 07:43:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, the notification of tasks happens right at the end of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/c7ed2e818a4ead70c6081117f771c54a1bbc0fc5/flink-runtime/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/runtime/checkpoint/CheckpointCoordinator.java#L1280&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;CheckpointCoordinator.completePendingCheckpoints:1280&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;tt&gt;sendAcknowledgeMessages&lt;/tt&gt; without any failure handling. Hence, the errors while canceling the tasks will be not considered when completing the Future returned by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/60fb0f5c6e4e23759541a531e034f27f496e93b7/flink-runtime/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/runtime/scheduler/SchedulerBase.java#L1080&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;CheckpointCoordinator. triggerSynchronousSavepoint &lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My proposal is to change the interface of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/2c4e0ab921ccfaf003073ee50faeae4d4e4f4c93/flink-runtime/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/runtime/jobmanager/slots/TaskManagerGateway.java#L96&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;TaskManagerGateway.notifyCheckpointComplete&lt;/a&gt; to return the &lt;tt&gt;CompletableFuture&lt;/tt&gt; already returned by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/2c4e0ab921ccfaf003073ee50faeae4d4e4f4c93/flink-runtime/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/runtime/taskexecutor/TaskExecutorGateway.java#L152&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;TaskExecutorGateway.confirmCheckpoint&lt;/a&gt;. This can, then, be forwarded to the &lt;tt&gt;completePendingCheckpoint&lt;/tt&gt; method and, then, be composed into the overall &lt;tt&gt;CompletableFuture&lt;/tt&gt; returned by &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointCoordinator.triggerSynchronousSavepoint&lt;/tt&gt;. Do you see any problems with this approach?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17276920" author="zhuzh" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 07:58:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sounds good to me.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yunta&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yunta&quot;&gt;yunta&lt;/a&gt; would you also take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=mapohl&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;mapohl&quot;&gt;mapohl&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s proposal to see if we missed anything?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17276965" author="yunta" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 09:10:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think returning the complete future to checkpoint coordinator to check whether the synchronous savepoint is finally completed is okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing I confuse is that shall we need such high requirement over normal checkpoints. From my understanding, current normal checkpoints could tolerate several executions fail to confirm the complete checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17277024" author="mapohl" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 10:37:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You&apos;re right: My proposal would affect the checkpoint creation as well which, as far as I can tell, shouldn&apos;t be like that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17277054" author="till.rohrmann" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 11:27:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I am not entirely sure whether adjusting the checkpoint protocol wouldn&apos;t let the scope explode a bit. I think this is quite a delicate thing for which we definitely would need to involve the people working on the &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt;. Maybe there is an easier solution to the problem. I&apos;ll try to investigate it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17277248" author="till.rohrmann" created="Tue, 2 Feb 2021 16:17:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think the problem can and should be solved in the scope of the &lt;tt&gt;SchedulerBase&lt;/tt&gt;/&lt;tt&gt;DefaultScheduler&lt;/tt&gt;. The underlying problem is that by calling &lt;tt&gt;SchedulerBase.stopWithSavepoint&lt;/tt&gt; the scheduler should go into a &quot;stop-with-savepoint&quot; state where it should react differently to the available signals. In fact, the stop with savepoint is a two stage operation which needs different behaviour depending on the stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Taking a savepoint&lt;br/&gt;
2. Stopping the job gracefully (waiting that the notify checkpoint complete messages are sent and the &lt;tt&gt;Tasks&lt;/tt&gt; shut themselves down)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a failure occurs in the first stage, then we should fail the stop-with-savepoint operation and recover the job normally. If a failure occurs in the second stage, then it is possible that parts of the &lt;tt&gt;ExecutionGraph&lt;/tt&gt; have already shut down. Hence, any task failure needs to trigger a global failover where we restart the whole job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the second stage is not treated properly which results into the reported problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest solution I can think of is to predicate the stop-with-savepoint operation on the state of the &lt;tt&gt;Executions&lt;/tt&gt;. Only if all &lt;tt&gt;Executions&lt;/tt&gt; reach a &lt;tt&gt;FINISHED&lt;/tt&gt; state, then the job can reach a &lt;tt&gt;FINISHED&lt;/tt&gt; state. Hence, if one observes an &lt;tt&gt;Execution&lt;/tt&gt; which reaches another terminal state, then one knows that the savepoint operation has failed. Depending on whether one is in stage 1. or 2. one needs to do nothing or trigger a global job failover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, one could make the state of stop-with-savepoint more explicit by letting the &lt;tt&gt;SchedulerBase&lt;/tt&gt; store a &lt;tt&gt;StopWithSavepointOperation&lt;/tt&gt;. This operation would then influence what &lt;tt&gt;DefaultScheduler.handleTaskFailure&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;DefaultScheduler.handleGlobalFailure&lt;/tt&gt; do. If, for example, we are in the 2. stage, then a single task failure should trigger a global failover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cc &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=zhuzh&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;zhuzh&quot;&gt;zhuzh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17277736" author="mapohl" created="Wed, 3 Feb 2021 06:51:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the analysis, that makes sense. I went ahead with this approach.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17277769" author="zhuzh" created="Wed, 3 Feb 2021 07:41:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I guess I had misunderstood the protocol of &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointCoordnator#triggerSynchronousSavepoint(...)&lt;/tt&gt;. Its returned future just indicates whether the savepoint is successfully taken, ignoring the result of &lt;tt&gt;notifyCheckpointComplete&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
So I agree that the scheduler should take care of the case that a savepoint is taken but job does not finish in a stop-with-savepoint process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=trohrmann&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;trohrmann&quot;&gt;trohrmann&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s solution looks good to me. Yet I think besides triggering a global failover, we also need to restart the &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointScheduler&lt;/tt&gt;. There is such handling in the end of &lt;tt&gt;SchedulerBase#stopWithSavepoint&lt;/tt&gt; but I think it does not work in the case that &lt;tt&gt;notifyCheckpointComplete&lt;/tt&gt; fails when a savepoint is successfully taken.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17277880" author="till.rohrmann" created="Wed, 3 Feb 2021 10:20:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, fully agreed. Restarting the &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; should happen in both stages if a failure occurs.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17278088" author="mapohl" created="Wed, 3 Feb 2021 15:45:44 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. Taking a savepoint&lt;br/&gt;
 2. Stopping the job gracefully (waiting that the notify checkpoint complete messages are sent and the Tasks shut themselves down)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&apos;ve been implementing two test cases to cover the use-case. Each of them covers a failure in one of the stages &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=trohrmann&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;trohrmann&quot;&gt;trohrmann&lt;/a&gt; described above. While doing this, I ran into some timeout issue when the failure happened during phase 1 (savepoint creation). The failed savepoint does not leave the pending state even though the snapshot creation failed. It looks like there&apos;s an&#160;&lt;tt&gt;AsyncCheckpointRunnable&lt;/tt&gt; (or something similar) missing that informs the &lt;tt&gt;CheckpointCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; about the failed savepoint as part of the exception handling in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/XComp/flink/blob/f421c6f72b91b7897ff2246bdf4f408e3609f6f0/flink-streaming-java/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/streaming/runtime/tasks/SubtaskCheckpointCoordinatorImpl.java#L305&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;SubtaskCheckpointCoordinatorImpl.checkpointState&lt;/a&gt;. In the test, the checkpoint gets cleaned up during cluster shutdown. &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=AHeise&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;AHeise&quot;&gt;AHeise&lt;/a&gt; Shall I create a Jira issue for that or do I miss something here?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17291654" author="till.rohrmann" created="Fri, 26 Feb 2021 13:49:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed via&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.13.0: f384b32877979d1118c0478bacae622ac7e0b330&lt;br/&gt;
1.12.2: e9af362f0caa16e75e66aa1403c62666e77f98f0&lt;br/&gt;
1.11.4: c9124884bbf8f086c00b82e76770bc31f90c60e4&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13298599">FLINK-17170</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is related to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13353253">FLINK-21029</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13353251">FLINK-21028</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            4 years, 37 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z0mrao:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>