<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 20:55:16 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[FLINK-21817] New Kafka Source might break subtask and split assignment upon rescale</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21817</link>
                <project id="12315522" key="FLINK">Flink</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;On restoring, splits are add back directly to &lt;tt&gt;SourceReader&lt;/tt&gt; in &lt;tt&gt;SourceOperator&lt;/tt&gt;. In no rescaled restoring, bindings between splits and subtasks are preserved due to no repartition in &lt;tt&gt;RoundRobinOperatorStateRepartitioner&lt;/tt&gt;. But in rescaled restoring, these operator states will be redistributed cross existing subtasks. This might break possible assignment from &lt;tt&gt;SourceEnumerator&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSource&lt;/tt&gt; as an example, the partition to subtask assignment is decided by &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSourceEnumerator.getSplitOwner&lt;/tt&gt;. The mappings will break after rescaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pushed &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kezhuw/flink/commit/9dc13cd9d7355d468a6ac8aae1b14b3a267581b6#diff-ad6e86c3757199ac3247687a71f9c34ee67b9ac743ae88a9f660950f27bec6eeR238&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;a test case&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSource&lt;/tt&gt; for evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it requires api addition to solve in generic and configurable way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it a valid issue ? I am not that sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cc&#160; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jqin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jqin&quot;&gt;jqin&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sewen&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sewen&quot;&gt;sewen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13365454">FLINK-21817</key>
            <summary>New Kafka Source might break subtask and split assignment upon rescale</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="renqs">Qingsheng Ren</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="kezhuw">Kezhu Wang</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>pull-request-available</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 09:16:26 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 11:13:44 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Thu, 8 Apr 2021 22:46:27 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.12.2</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.13.0</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>1.12.3</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Connectors / Common</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>6</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17305961" author="renqs" created="Mon, 22 Mar 2021 07:54:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the ticket &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=kezhuw&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;kezhuw&quot;&gt;kezhuw&lt;/a&gt;! I took a look of new source&apos;s code, and this bug does exist when the job rescales.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some possible solutions:&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.&#160;SourceOperator&#160;reports its restored splits back to &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; at registration, and &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; updates its &lt;tt&gt;SplitsAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt; in the context.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.&#160;SourceOperator&#160;reports its restored splits back to &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; at registration, and if these splits don&apos;t match with the&#160;&lt;tt&gt;SplitsAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; will revoke them and re-assign correct splits to the reader. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. Instead of using &lt;tt&gt;RoundRobinOperatorStateRepartitioner&lt;/tt&gt;, we can design a new partitioner, which will distribute splits according to the assignment tracked by &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I prefer the second one, because as the leader of &lt;tt&gt;SourceReader&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; holds the ground truth. For the first option, round-robin style partitioning might break the decision made by &lt;tt&gt;SourceEnumerator&lt;/tt&gt;. Also I think the second one is easier to implement compared to the third solution.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to make the second solution work, we also needs a split revocation mechanism to revoke mis-assigned splits after rescaling. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17306603" author="stephanewen" created="Mon, 22 Mar 2021 21:44:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I agree that this is a bug in the Kafka Enumerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we need to make sure users understand that the Enumerator should not in any case make any assumption about what is going on at the readers after a failure or restore. That is an anti-pattern in my experience, doing bookkeeping twice and trying to keep it in sync. It will very often break at some points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A similar bug was &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21452&quot; title=&quot;FLIP-27 sources cannot reliably downscale&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-21452&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-21452&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and the solution was to drop the bookkeeping on the enumerator side, and rely on reader registrations to learn about the current state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following a similar argument, I would suggest to go with variant (1) here.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17306629" author="stephanewen" created="Mon, 22 Mar 2021 22:41:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;For clarification, I think that the FLIP-27 sources as a whole are not affected by this.&lt;br/&gt;
There is the &lt;tt&gt;SplitAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt; which is mainly necessary to return splits on task failures. After a checkpoint completed (or after recovery with a completed checkpoint), the subtask specific information should no longer be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my take is that this is purely an issue of the new Kafka Source, that&apos;s why I updated the title.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17306669" author="becket_qin" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:28:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think solution 1 and 2 &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=renqs&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;renqs&quot;&gt;renqs&lt;/a&gt;&#160;mentioned do not conflict with each other. They are more like two steps. In another word, it is the enumerator&apos;s call whether it wants to adjust the splits assignment after the readers reported the assignment upon reader registration. Revoking a split assignment seems a useful primitive for other cases as well, e.g. workload balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to fix the inconsistent state, we only need to do (1).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17306805" author="kezhuw" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2021 06:39:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I guess we four are probably talking about two inconsistencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Inconsistency between &lt;tt&gt;SplitAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt; and operator instances.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Inconsistency between split enumerator and operator instances about possible contract that split assignment enforced by concrete split enumerators. For &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSource&lt;/tt&gt;, the contract is &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSourceEnumerator.getSplitOwner&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I did not aware of #1, but there are related anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IIUC, &lt;tt&gt;SplitAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt; is responsible for region recovering from last successful checkpoint. If this is the case, I think it makes no sense to snapshot and restore it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #2, I am not sure whether it is a valid feature request. I assume yes for now. I think &lt;tt&gt;void addReader(int subtaskId, List&amp;lt;SplitT&amp;gt; splits)&lt;/tt&gt; will help &lt;tt&gt;SourceOperator&lt;/tt&gt; to piggyback restored splits on open(eg. no &lt;tt&gt;SourceReader.addSplits&lt;/tt&gt; on operator startup). To make it configurable, a boolean flag in &lt;tt&gt;Source&lt;/tt&gt; could guide &lt;tt&gt;SourceOperator&lt;/tt&gt; how to do on restoring. Comparing to legacy source, this will not only make &lt;tt&gt;SplitEnumerator&lt;/tt&gt; a split assigner but &lt;b&gt;the&lt;/b&gt; assigner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we need to make sure users understand that the Enumerator should not in any case make any assumption about what is going on at the readers after a failure or restore. That is an anti-pattern in my experience, doing bookkeeping twice and trying to keep it in sync. It will very often break at some points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree this. &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSourceEnumState.currentAssignment&lt;/tt&gt; is misleading also and will inconsistent with operator instances after rescaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For solutions offered by&#160; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=renqs&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;renqs&quot;&gt;renqs&lt;/a&gt;, I guess we all opt out solution#3. For solution#1, I did not see values to snapshot and restore &lt;tt&gt;SplitAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt;. For solution#2, how to revoke in case of inconsistency#2 is valid ?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17306912" author="renqs" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2021 09:09:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the inspiring discussion!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About &lt;tt&gt;SplitAssignmentTracker&lt;/tt&gt;, I agree with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sewen&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sewen&quot;&gt;sewen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=kezhuw&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;kezhuw&quot;&gt;kezhuw&lt;/a&gt;. I think it&#8217;s not necessary to keep it in the state of &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt; since it will finally lose track of the per-subtask assignment after a global failover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About split revoking, I&#8217;m +1 with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt;. Whether or not to use it for correcting split assignment, this is still useful under scenarios like load balancing, and provides more flexibility for assignment decision made by split enumerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to opinions above, at least we have these TODOs on the current FLIP-27 source no matter which solution we finally choose:&lt;br/&gt;
 1. A mechanism for readers reporting current assignment back to coordinator. This can be added to &lt;tt&gt;ReaderRegistrationEvent&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
 2. An interface for passing these assignments to SplitEnumerator, like &lt;tt&gt;addReader(int subtaskId, List&amp;lt;SplitT&amp;gt; splits)&lt;/tt&gt; mentioned by &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=kezhuw&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;kezhuw&quot;&gt;kezhuw&lt;/a&gt;. Since &lt;tt&gt;SplitEnumerator&lt;/tt&gt; is a public interface, this change requires a FLIP.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17306985" author="stephanewen" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2021 11:33:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for this discussion and the analysis of the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say that to fix this problem, let&apos;s not offer a general solution on the basic source enumerator (the &lt;tt&gt;SourceCoordinator&lt;/tt&gt;) interface to track which readers have which split. I would suggest that if we want to track this in the Kafka Source, then let&apos;s implement it only in the Kafka Source with a custom event that is sent as a first thing after registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we may even skip this for now, and not track splits in the Kafka Source for this release. There is no functionality now that needs this tracking, and it is a source of errors, so I would suggest to add the split tracking later when we actually need it and have better test coverage with a common test suite that includes tests that change the parallelism. Then we are confident to catch issues better.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So my suggested actions would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Remove the SplitAssignmentTracker from the snapshots, because it isn&apos;t needed and might actually cause problems.&lt;br/&gt;
(2) Remove the split-to-reader tracking in the Kafka Source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;==&amp;gt; These two are 1.13 blockers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(3) Ensure our source test suite is in place&lt;br/&gt;
(4) Add split-to-reader-tracking to Kafka Source when we need this functionality&lt;br/&gt;
(5) Move this logic to the common source interface once it is stable in the Kafka Source&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I think split rebalancing isn&apos;t something we should start doing now, because there is no way to guarantee order of events in a partition when rebalancing: The events read by the newly assigned reader can overtake events from the old reader. We need something like epochs to establish clear before/after relationships for the in-flight events, which we implicitly get through checkpoints, that&apos;s why rescaling is safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The discussion about how to preserve order semantics per key with in-flight data is something we did for unaligned checkpoints. It is really complex to come up with a simple but effective semantical model, and unaligned checkpoints currently work only on &lt;tt&gt;keyBy()&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;rebalance()&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;random()&lt;/tt&gt; data exchanges (not &lt;tt&gt;forward()&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;rescale()&lt;/tt&gt;) because only for those three cases is it possible to provide meaningful semantics with the current parallel streams model that Flink has.&lt;br/&gt;
Just quickly doing something with source split rebalancing now will open up all sorts of problems and bugs if we don&apos;t answer the question about order guarantees before. So let&apos;s do one thing at a time. First get the basics of the new sources running very well. Then approach the next set of issues.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17307079" author="kezhuw" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2021 13:50:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 for gradual procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#160;But we may even skip this for now, and not track splits in the Kafka Source for this release. There is no functionality now that needs this tracking&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually could not give it a name for configuring, though old Kafka consumer do respect a same assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For (2), did you means &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSourceEnumerator.readerIdToSplitAssignments&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;KafkaSourceEnumState.currentAssignment&lt;/tt&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sewen&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sewen&quot;&gt;sewen&lt;/a&gt; ? This tracking currently does not hurt correctness, but still worth to drop. It also demands special care as it is stored in state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm, I guess (1) also does not hurt correctness for now. Both (1), (2) are just unnecessary atm&#160;&lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/sad.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;. Anyway, worth to fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=renqs&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;renqs&quot;&gt;renqs&lt;/a&gt; I guess with help of default method and &lt;tt&gt;SplitEnumerator.addSplitsBack&lt;/tt&gt;(fallback to this if default is not overrode), it could be a no breaking change.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17309481" author="dawidwys" created="Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:10:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry, I&apos;ve not checked the discussion. Just wanted to check if someone is working on a fix for it as it is marked as a blocker for the release. Could we assign the ticket to that person if there is one?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17309485" author="renqs" created="Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:16:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I can work on those two blockers mentioned by &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sewen&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sewen&quot;&gt;sewen&lt;/a&gt; above. &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dwysakowicz&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dwysakowicz&quot;&gt;dwysakowicz&lt;/a&gt; Could you please assign this ticket to me? Thanks~&#160;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17309494" author="dawidwys" created="Fri, 26 Mar 2021 15:27:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sure, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=renqs&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;renqs&quot;&gt;renqs&lt;/a&gt; Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17313346" author="stephanewen" created="Thu, 1 Apr 2021 17:48:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed in 1.13.0 via &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;65b43c45c69c20a51f2926d29be46c779fe65af&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;2be15338c00e75361566fe3010091ea61f0af645&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="17316294" author="dawidwys" created="Wed, 7 Apr 2021 12:40:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Double checking... Is the task still open, because it needs to backported to 1.12? Or is there another reason?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17317253" author="stephanewen" created="Thu, 8 Apr 2021 15:03:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Exactly, it is because of the 1.12 backport.&lt;br/&gt;
Let me try to merge this to the 1.12 branch today, and if it doesn&apos;t finish, I&apos;ll close this and open a separate issue for the backport.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17317533" author="stephanewen" created="Thu, 8 Apr 2021 22:41:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed in 1.12 via&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;035932e20e853b3dbc80a2a4826248ae2854711e&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;59f54d7725c3b277327bf317d99e9dcb17194437&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            4 years, 31 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z0ots8:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>