<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 21:08:37 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[FLINK-24038] DispatcherResourceManagerComponent fails to deregister application if no leading ResourceManager</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-24038</link>
                <project id="12315522" key="FLINK">Flink</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-21667&quot; title=&quot;Standby RM might remove resources from Kubernetes&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-21667&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-21667&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; we introduced a change that can cause the &lt;tt&gt;DispatcherResourceManagerComponent&lt;/tt&gt; to fail when trying to stop the application. The problem is that the &lt;tt&gt;DispatcherResourceManagerComponent&lt;/tt&gt; needs a leading &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; to successfully execute the stop/deregister application call. If this is not the case, then it will fail fatally. In the case of multiple standby JobManager processes it can happen that the leading &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; runs somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do see two possible solutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Run the leader election process for the whole JobManager process&lt;br/&gt;
2. Move the registration/deregistration of the application out of the &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; so that it can be executed w/o a leader&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13397977">FLINK-24038</key>
            <summary>DispatcherResourceManagerComponent fails to deregister application if no leading ResourceManager</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="2" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/critical.svg">Critical</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="trohrmann">Till Rohrmann</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="trohrmann">Till Rohrmann</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>pull-request-available</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 17:49:44 +0000</created>
                <updated>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 13:06:18 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:56:15 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.14.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.15.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Runtime / Coordination</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>12</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17406272" author="till.rohrmann" created="Sat, 28 Aug 2021 17:50:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;cc &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=xtsong&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;xtsong&quot;&gt;xtsong&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17406350" author="xintongsong" created="Sun, 29 Aug 2021 02:30:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think option 2) should not work. To deregister an application, it can involve interactions with the underlying external resource manager. This is usually specific to the underlying system, and is better performed by the ResourceManagerDriver. Most importantly, deregistration of an application usually means all the process will be terminated, thus a non-leader JobManager process could kill a leader process if it is allowed to deregister, which is undesired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 1) might work. I would need to look into it a bit more to be sure about that. Event this works, my gut feeling the efforts needed and the potential impacts on stabilities may not be trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, we may consider simply not throwing the error there&apos;s not a leading resource manager. To be specific, if there is a leading resource manager, errors occurred during the deregistration should still be considered fatal. But if there&apos;s not a leading resource manager, we simply don&apos;t do the deregistration. For standalone clusters, there should be no difference anyway, since the StandaloneResourceManager does not do anything for deregistration. For active resource managers, I think it&apos;s a good contract that only the leading resource manager interacts with the external resource manager (except for pure reading operations). The side effect would be, if Flink tries to deregister when there&apos;s no leader RM, the deregister cannot success and K8s/Yarn will bring up another JobManager process anyway, which is the same as how it is currently and IMHO not a big problem.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17406756" author="till.rohrmann" created="Mon, 30 Aug 2021 14:35:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I am not so sure about your verdict about option 2). At the moment it is correct that communication logic to interact with an external resource manager is encapsulated in the &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManagerDriver&lt;/tt&gt;. However, this does not have to mean that the logic to register and deregister an application should also be the responsibility of the &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt;. I think this actually shows in the old code where we call into the &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; to deregister the application independent of its leadership. Moreover, the decision whether to shut down the cluster or not is currently made by the &lt;tt&gt;Dispatcher&lt;/tt&gt;. Hence, this component should be able to do this independent whether there is a &lt;tt&gt;RM&lt;/tt&gt; running or not (also think about the hypothetical case where we split the &lt;tt&gt;Dispatcher&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; components into several processes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concerning your proposal of not doing the deregistration if there is no leading &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt;: How will this work if we use a K8s job? If I am not mistaken, then the return value of the process decides whether the job is restarted or not by K8s. So if we shut down normally but cannot deregister the application, then we will continue and stop with a zero exit code. So in this scenario, K8s will terminate the job but we won&apos;t clean up other K8s resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Yarn, this proposal can work I believe, even though it is not super nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you taking care of this problem &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=xtsong&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;xtsong&quot;&gt;xtsong&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17407048" author="xintongsong" created="Tue, 31 Aug 2021 03:30:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think you&apos;re correct, about option 2) and about the K8s job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me re-list the options I see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Allow &lt;tt&gt;Dispatcher&lt;/tt&gt; to deregister the application independently. This is probably the least invasive solution. The only down side I see is that it introduces the complexity of dealing with different external resource managers to the dispatcher, which is probably not very complex with a proper unified abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Run the leader election process for the whole &lt;tt&gt;DispatcherResourceManagerComponent&lt;/tt&gt;. This would guarantee we either have both a leading &lt;tt&gt;Dispatcher&lt;/tt&gt; and a leading &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt;, or neither or them. This is IMHO too invasive to be done in the release stabilization phase. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of splitting a JobManager process into multiple processes, I&apos;m not entirely sure whether it is indeed needed. And even this is needed in future, I wonder would it be good enough to have the &lt;tt&gt;Dispatcher&lt;/tt&gt; and the &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; in one process, while each &lt;tt&gt;JobMaster&lt;/tt&gt; in a separate process. I guess it depends on what essential demands we see in separating the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Make &lt;tt&gt;Dispatcher&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManager&lt;/tt&gt; talks to each other via RPC. This should work in scenarios where the leading RM is somewhere else, but not in scenarios where there&apos;s no leading RMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TBH, I&apos;m not entirely sure which one of 1) &amp;amp; 2) is better. Maybe slightly learning towards 2), which in general simplifies things rather than complicates them, if we leave aside the topic of splitting the process. WDTY?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d be happy to look into this, but cannot promise to take care of it for 1.14.0. It really depends on to which direction we decide to go. For option 1), I can have a try. For option 2), I would suggest to leave with the problem for now and fix it for the next major release.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17407049" author="xintongsong" created="Tue, 31 Aug 2021 03:31:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;cc &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=wangyang0918&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;wangyang0918&quot;&gt;wangyang0918&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17407130" author="fly_in_gis" created="Tue, 31 Aug 2021 07:05:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=trohrmann&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;trohrmann&quot;&gt;trohrmann&lt;/a&gt; Using a K8s job could help a bit when doing the deregistration failed. However, we still have the residual TaskManager pods and flink ConfigMaps. Maybe let the JobManager relaunched and recover the finished or failed jobs, then the dispatcher will deregister the application again. It is more reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Yarn, I am afraid it is in the same situation. Even though the JobManager(application master) exit with zero code, it will be launched again when deregistering failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the new options&#160;#1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=xtsong&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;xtsong&quot;&gt;xtsong&lt;/a&gt;&#160;listed, do you mean let the leader dispatcher do the&#160;deregistration? If it is, what will happen without leader.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17407145" author="xintongsong" created="Tue, 31 Aug 2021 07:24:33 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the new options #1 Xintong Song listed, do you mean let the leader dispatcher do the deregistration? If it is, what will happen without leader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I meant let the leading dispatcher to do the deregistration. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=trohrmann&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;trohrmann&quot;&gt;trohrmann&lt;/a&gt;, the decision whether to shut down the cluster or not is currently made by the Dispatcher. IIUC, that means there should not be a shutdown without a leading dispatcher, because there won&apos;t be any dispatcher to make that decision without obtaining leadership.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17407343" author="till.rohrmann" created="Tue, 31 Aug 2021 13:31:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It is a good question what the easiest solution is. I think the proper solution is option 1) because it does not only solve a symptom. Option 2) is desirable for other reasons as well (no spread leaders across different processes, less request load on HA system because there is only a single leader election) but it also solves the described problem here (even though it is more indirectly).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do see that option 1) will complicate things a bit because we have to create new &lt;tt&gt;YarnClient&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;NamespacedKubernetesClient&lt;/tt&gt; instances that are now nicely encapsulated in the &lt;tt&gt;ResourceManagerDriver&lt;/tt&gt;. I do think that we can manage some of this complexity by choosing proper abstractions. But still, it will make the system slightly more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we can start by looking into option 2) first in order to better understand the scope of this change.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17407743" author="xintongsong" created="Wed, 1 Sep 2021 01:44:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Alright, I&apos;ll take a look into option 2).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17414088" author="davidmoravek" created="Mon, 13 Sep 2021 10:06:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=xtsong&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;xtsong&quot;&gt;xtsong&lt;/a&gt; , is there any progress on the issue?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17414096" author="xintongsong" created="Mon, 13 Sep 2021 10:36:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dmvk&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dmvk&quot;&gt;dmvk&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;br/&gt;
No, I haven&apos;t started on this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17427020" author="till.rohrmann" created="Mon, 11 Oct 2021 09:09:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Quick check on the status &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=xtsong&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;xtsong&quot;&gt;xtsong&lt;/a&gt;? The reason is that we see a high load of requests coming from Flink K8s HA services and we hope that by reducing the number of leader elections per JobManager process could mitigate the situation a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17427035" author="xintongsong" created="Mon, 11 Oct 2021 09:31:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m a bit overloaded recently, and probably won&apos;t have time for this in at least a month from now.&lt;br/&gt;
I&apos;m un-assigning myself, in case someone else wants to work on this.&lt;br/&gt;
Will try to pick this up later if no one else work on it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17443285" author="flink-jira-bot" created="Sun, 14 Nov 2021 10:38:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I am the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/flink-jira-bot/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Flink Jira Bot&lt;/a&gt; and I help the community manage its development. I see this issue is assigned but has not received an update in 30 days, so it has been labeled &quot;stale-assigned&quot;.&lt;br/&gt;
If you are still working on the issue, please remove the label and add a comment updating the community on your progress.  If this issue is waiting on feedback, please consider this a reminder to the committer/reviewer. Flink is a very active project, and so we appreciate your patience.&lt;br/&gt;
If you are no longer working on the issue, please unassign yourself so someone else may work on it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17476095" author="till.rohrmann" created="Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:08:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve finalized the PR. It is ready for review now.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17476102" author="davidmoravek" created="Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:29:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s a great news, I can do a review pass next week.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17481006" author="mapohl" created="Mon, 24 Jan 2022 11:00:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I changed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-25432&quot; title=&quot;Introduce common interfaces for cleaning up local and global job data&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-25432&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-25432&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; link from &quot;blocks&quot; to &quot;relates to&quot; because we&apos;re considering the order of cleanup (i.e. &lt;tt&gt;JobMaster&lt;/tt&gt; needs to be closed before cleaning up the &lt;tt&gt;HighAvailabilityServices&lt;/tt&gt;) in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-25432&quot; title=&quot;Introduce common interfaces for cleaning up local and global job data&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-25432&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-25432&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This invariant can be removed as soon as we remove the old component-based leader election entirely. Currently, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-24038&quot; title=&quot;DispatcherResourceManagerComponent fails to deregister application if no leading ResourceManager&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-24038&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-24038&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; implements this feature in a way that it&apos;s configurable.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17482774" author="till.rohrmann" created="Wed, 26 Jan 2022 22:53:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed via&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5a2f220e31c&lt;br/&gt;
6a4eb9b815c&lt;br/&gt;
b609cb4462f&lt;br/&gt;
e8742f7f5ca&lt;br/&gt;
24fea2682ea&lt;br/&gt;
0afe3539d9e&lt;br/&gt;
bba7c417217&lt;br/&gt;
391ce7c6444&lt;br/&gt;
fef375e571e&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17483670" author="fly_in_gis" created="Fri, 28 Jan 2022 09:20:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;After introducing the multiple component leader election service, we now only have two ConfigMaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &quot;&amp;lt;clusterId&amp;gt;-cluster-config-map&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Leader election for all the components(e.g. restserver, dispatcher, resourcemanager, jobmanager)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;JobGraph store&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Running job registry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;2. &quot;&amp;lt;clusterId&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;jobId&amp;gt;-config-map&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Checkpoint store and counter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For jobmanager, the leader election and checkpoint store are using different ConfigMaps. I think it could happen the non-leader jobmanager overwrite the checkpoint store unexpectedly. Because we do not have the &quot;get-check_leadership-update&quot; transactional operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cc &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=trohrmann&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;trohrmann&quot;&gt;trohrmann&lt;/a&gt; Do you think this is a valid concern?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17483853" author="till.rohrmann" created="Fri, 28 Jan 2022 17:07:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You are correct &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=wangyang0918&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;wangyang0918&quot;&gt;wangyang0918&lt;/a&gt;, that we no longer have the leader check when writing to the &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;clusterId&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;jobId&amp;gt;-config-map&lt;/tt&gt; because there is no leader election happening for this map. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it gives now effectively the same guarantees that we also have with the ZooKeeper HA implementation. If there is an old leader the leader can still write things into the config map. If I am not mistaken, then the danger is that checkpoints from the old leader can complete. If this is a problem then one should not use the multiple component leader election ha services. Alternatively, one could think about only using a single config map. However, this would increase the concurrent writes to it. Given that we have the same semantics with the Zk HA services, then I am not sure whether this is a real problem.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17487854" author="fly_in_gis" created="Mon, 7 Feb 2022 03:33:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I will keep an eye on the multiple component leader election ha services when it is used in the production environment.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10032">
                    <name>Blocker</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="blocks">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13396933">FLINK-23946</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13416304">FLINK-25235</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310560">
                    <name>Problem/Incident</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="causes">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13433615">FLINK-26630</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13426918">FLINK-25981</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is caused by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13362984">FLINK-21667</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13420242">FLINK-25500</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13425117">FLINK-25847</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13441257">FLINK-27358</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13418609">FLINK-25393</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13424697">FLINK-25806</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is related to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13419214">FLINK-25432</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13558699">FLINK-33598</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            3 years, 40 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z0udig:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310192" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:textarea">
                        <customfieldname>Release Note</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>A new multiple component leader election service was implemented that only runs a single leader election per Flink process. If this should cause any problems, then you can set `high-availability.use-old-ha-services: true` in the `flink-conf.yaml` to use the old high availability services.</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>