<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 21:11:06 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[FLINK-26079] [Changelog] Disallow recovery from non-changelog checkpoints</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-26079</link>
                <project id="12315522" key="FLINK">Flink</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Extracted from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-25872&quot; title=&quot;Restoring from non-changelog checkpoint with changelog state-backend enabled in CLAIM mode discards state in use&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-25872&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-25872&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is with the CLAIM mode:&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; Because discarding an initial checkpoint will invalidate its &quot;private&quot; state which might be in use by future checkpoints.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; Normally, changelog backend wraps it and registers with tjhe SharedStateRegistry.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; But when recovering from non-changelog checkpoint, it is first added to the Checkpoint store, and wrapping in subsequent checkpoints doesn&apos;t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NO_CLAIM mode is not supported.&lt;br/&gt;
LEGACY could work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&apos;s difficult to differentiate between the modes on TM, where backend type is reliably known (see the discussion below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CANONICAL non-changelog savepoints must still be supported.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13427881">FLINK-26079</key>
            <summary>[Changelog] Disallow recovery from non-changelog checkpoints</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="roman">Roman Khachatryan</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="roman">Roman Khachatryan</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>pull-request-available</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 21:14:30 +0000</created>
                <updated>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 11:29:56 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:50:26 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>1.15.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Runtime / Configuration</component>
                    <component>Runtime / State Backends</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17490532" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Thu, 10 Feb 2022 21:56:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;To implement the validation, we need cluster config (read by TM) to load state backend; and application settings to read restore mode (and overriding backend if any).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading restore mode should be prone to JM failover; in particular, when failure happens before creating any new checkpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t see any reliable way to access full cluster config on JM (&lt;b&gt;am I wrong?&lt;/b&gt;). So the validation should be done on TM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see the following ways to pass Pass RestoreMode to each task:&lt;br/&gt;
1. in StreamConfig - set from JobGraph.savepointRestoreSettings in StreamingJobGraphGenerator&lt;br/&gt;
2. in TaskStateSnapshot - set in StateAssignmentOperation&lt;br/&gt;
3. in CheckpointProperties - set in CheckpointCoordinator&lt;br/&gt;
4. (other options?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 1st option is resilient to failures because job graph is generated once. The main disadvantage is multple places where it has to be checked; DataSourceTask for example uses TaskConfig instead of StreamConfig IIUC.&lt;br/&gt;
2nd and 3rd options need something similar to completedCheckpoint.props.unclaimed to survive crashes. &lt;br/&gt;
Additionally, 3rd has non-clear semantics (we&apos;re interested in the initial checkpoint, not the current one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WDYT &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=pnowojski&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;pnowojski&quot;&gt;pnowojski&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dwysakowicz&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dwysakowicz&quot;&gt;dwysakowicz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ym&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ym&quot;&gt;ym&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490716" author="dawidwys" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 07:32:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Why do you want to disallow the combination? What is the problem? Does it mean &lt;tt&gt;LEGACY&lt;/tt&gt; would be the only supported mode?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490719" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 07:44:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Why do you want to disallow the combination? What is the problem?&lt;br/&gt;
Because discarding an initial checkpoint will invalidate its &quot;private&quot; state which might be in use by future checkpoints.&lt;br/&gt;
Normally, changelog backend wraps it and registers with tjhe SharedStateRegistry.&lt;br/&gt;
But when recovering from non-changelog checkpoint, it is first added to the Checkpoint store, and wrapping in subsequent checkpoints doesn&apos;t help.&lt;br/&gt;
(I mistakenly omitted &quot;from non-changelog checkpoint&quot; from the ticket title, sorry).&#160;&lt;br/&gt;
&#160;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; Does it mean LEGACY would be the only supported mode?&lt;br/&gt;
&#160;&lt;br/&gt;
Yes.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490728" author="dawidwys" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 08:06:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Do I understand it correctly, that the use case that breaks is basically changing the state backend from a non-changelog to a changelog state backend? As food for thought. Is that something that we support/want to support? So far the only way to change the state backend was via a savepoint.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490729" author="pnowojski" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 08:08:07 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1st option is resilient to failures because job graph is generated once. The main disadvantage is multiple places where it has to be checked; DataSourceTask for example uses TaskConfig instead of StreamConfig IIUC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is that so? &lt;tt&gt;StreamTask#createStateBackend&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;StateBackendLoader#fromApplicationOrConfigOrDefault&lt;/tt&gt; could be that one place. &lt;tt&gt;DataSourceTask&lt;/tt&gt; is a legacy DataSet API class. We can safely limit ourselves just to &lt;tt&gt;StreamTask&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t like that we would have to pass the restore mode to implement such temporary check, but I don&apos;t know what&apos;s the alternative? Can we actually fix this properly before the release? As this is a bug, we could fix it after the feature freeze.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490751" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 08:47:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dwysakowicz&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dwysakowicz&quot;&gt;dwysakowicz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do I understand it correctly, that the use case that breaks is basically changing the state backend from a non-changelog to a changelog state backend?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes. Recovering from a non-changelog checkpoint (not savepoint) is desirable. The motivation is to reduce downtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=pnowojski&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;pnowojski&quot;&gt;pnowojski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;DataSourceTask is a legacy DataSet API class. We can safely limit ourselves just to StreamTask.&lt;br/&gt;
StreamTask#createStateBackend or StateBackendLoader#fromApplicationOrConfigOrDefault could be that one place.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&apos;re right regarding the DataSourceTask, I mistook it for FLIP-27 task.&lt;br/&gt;
However, state backend is also created by StreamOperatorContextBuilder (called by operators). Shouldn&apos;t the check be there as well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t like that we would have to pass the restore mode to implement such temporary check, but I don&apos;t know what&apos;s the alternative?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, me neither. I&apos;m not sure we should implement the validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see the following alternatives:&lt;br/&gt;
1. Fix the original issue&lt;br/&gt;
2. Only document the limitation without enforcing it&lt;br/&gt;
3. Disallow recovery from non-changelog checkpoints (only allow savepoints as Dawid mentioned)&lt;br/&gt;
&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for fixing the original issue (cc: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yunta&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yunta&quot;&gt;yunta&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;br/&gt;
1. Register all state with the SharedStateRegistry. This would require changing registerSharedStates() of at least KeyGroupsStateHandle and IncrementalRemoteKeyedStateHandle&lt;br/&gt;
2. Limit the above to only initial checkpoint and only recovery (CompletedCheckpoint.registerSharedStatesAfterRestored)&lt;br/&gt;
3. Wrap the materialized state with Changelog handles on JM, during recovery (not an option IMO because JM shouldn&apos;t be aware of that)&lt;br/&gt;
&#160;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490923" author="pnowojski" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 13:32:10 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see the following alternatives:&lt;br/&gt;
1. Fix the original issue&lt;br/&gt;
2. Only document the limitation without enforcing it&lt;br/&gt;
3. Disallow recovery from non-changelog checkpoints (only allow savepoints as Dawid mentioned)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presume 3. would be easier to implement compared to the `LEGACY` check we discussed earlier? And you mean allowing recovery only from changelog checkpoints or canonical savepoints (native savepoints wouldn&apos;t be supported)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If so I would be also fine with that (especially if we could implement such check in the changelog package) for the time being until we fix the original issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490951" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:33:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, I also think (3) is the easiest validation option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be implemented by checking handles types while &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/flink/blob/3aa267bf511287e39b0a9d781b9aaf38843e1e91/flink-state-backends/flink-statebackend-changelog/src/main/java/org/apache/flink/state/changelog/ChangelogStateBackend.java#L271&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;building&lt;/a&gt; the backend. Only&#160; ChangelogStateBackendHandle and SavepointKeyedStateHandle should be allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such a check, the following will be allowed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;changelog checkpoint + CLAIM/LEGACY&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;canonical savepoint (any restore mode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The following disallowed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;non-changelog checkpoint + CLAIM&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;non-changelog checkpoint + LEGACY&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;native savepoint&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;NO_CLAIM - by an existing check in StreamTask&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Unnecessarily disallowing (2) &quot;non-changelog checkpoint + LEGACY&quot;&#160;is the downside of this approach.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490957" author="pnowojski" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:39:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So let&apos;s do that. Given the MVP status of the changelog I think that&apos;s good enough. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17490962" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Fri, 11 Feb 2022 14:47:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Great, I&apos;ll create a PR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And probably we&apos;ll manage to resolve the original issue after the feature freeze, it then can be easily reverted.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17492058" author="ym" created="Mon, 14 Feb 2022 15:26:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; But when recovering from the non-changelog checkpoint, it is first added to the Checkpoint store, and wrapping in subsequent checkpoints doesn&apos;t help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;shouldn&apos;t claim mode with changelog state backend wrap it first and then be added to the checkpoint store?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Conceptually, when claiming: shouldn&apos;t we claim as a changelog checkpoint if we are using changelog state-backend after restoring?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;But I agree that&apos;s something we need to figure out after code freeze.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="17492094" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Mon, 14 Feb 2022 16:43:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; shouldn&apos;t claim mode with changelog state backend wrap it first and then be added to the checkpoint store?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per the discussion above, this doesn&apos;t seem a good option because JM should NOT be aware of how specific backends build their state handles.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; 3. Wrap the materialized state with Changelog handles on JM, during recovery (not an option IMO because JM shouldn&apos;t be aware of that)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Conceptually, when claiming: shouldn&apos;t we claim as a changelog checkpoint if we are using changelog state-backend after restoring?&lt;br/&gt;
What do you mean by &quot;claim as a changelog checkpoint&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; But I agree that&apos;s something we need to figure out after code freeze.&lt;br/&gt;
I personally meant that after the feature freeze we&apos;ll probably fix the root cause.&lt;br/&gt;
This issue of enforcing the limitation should be merged ASAP IMO, so that it can be tested as part of the release process. Although formally it can be merged after the feature freeze too.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17492404" author="ym" created="Tue, 15 Feb 2022 07:27:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; shouldn&apos;t claim mode with changelog state backend wrap it first and then be added to the checkpoint store?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; As per the discussion above, this doesn&apos;t seem a good option because JM should NOT be aware of how specific backends build their state handles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is a fair statement, but from an implementation point of view, let me state this in a different way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Conceptually, when claiming: shouldn&apos;t we claim as a changelog checkpoint if we are using changelog state-backend after restoring?&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; What do you mean by &quot;claim as a changelog checkpoint&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean is: when we restore a job from a normal checkpoint (created by non-changelog state backend) and use changelog state backend with CLAIM mode, It&apos;s natural that we make/transfer/register the first checkpoint to/as a changelog-style checkpoint.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; I personally meant that after the feature freeze we&apos;ll probably fix the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not disagree with that&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17492441" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Tue, 15 Feb 2022 08:30:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&#160; What I mean is: when we restore a job from a normal checkpoint (created by non-changelog state backend) and use changelog state backend with CLAIM mode, It&apos;s natural that we make/transfer the first checkpoint to a changelog-style checkpoint.&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it is natural for TM (state backend) - and this is what it actually does. But it is not natural for JM (checkpoint store), because it is not aware of the changelog (and should not be in my opinion).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementation-wise, are you proposing to add a dependency on ChangelogStateBackend to flink-runtime and run the necessary logic in JM inside or around CompletedCheckpointStore?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s maybe move this discussion to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FLINK-25872&quot; title=&quot;Restoring from non-changelog checkpoint with changelog state-backend enabled in CLAIM mode discards state in use&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;FLINK-25872&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;FLINK-25872&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which is about addressing the original issue, not the enforcing the limitation?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17492450" author="ym" created="Tue, 15 Feb 2022 08:48:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;OK, let&apos;s move the discussion to the original ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the disallow config itself, my last question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=roman&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;roman&quot;&gt;roman&lt;/a&gt;&#160; Would disallowing &quot;Non-changelog checkpoint + LEGACY&quot; break any existing ITCase + changelog randomization?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17492454" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Tue, 15 Feb 2022 08:54:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, &quot;changelog.enabled&quot; is not changed in tests during the recovery (except the newly added ChangelogCompatibilityITCase).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17493312" author="roman_khachatryan" created="Wed, 16 Feb 2022 15:50:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Merged into master as 369088f0f94ae7732f8a65b6676f2187c871328a&lt;br/&gt;
..6fc4bad2c6443ef33ac86a286f815ecc9afba31c.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10032">
                    <name>Blocker</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="blocks">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13357973">FLINK-21352</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310560">
                    <name>Problem/Incident</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is caused by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13425462">FLINK-25872</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            3 years, 38 weeks, 6 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z0zh3c:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>