<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 15:56:26 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[FELIX-4785] Incompatible SCR API</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/FELIX-4785</link>
                <project id="12310100" key="FELIX">Felix</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Current trunk contains version 2.0.0 of the org.apache.felix.scr API package. While this is a logical step, this makes the new implementation unusable as a drop-in replacement into existing installations which might use the 1.x version of that API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we should go a more moderate way, leave the 1.x version in but deprecate it and also provide the replacement API (if any). Then in one of the further versions along the road, we can remove the API. This gives our users a chance to migrate slowly&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12772045">FELIX-4785</key>
            <summary>Incompatible SCR API</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="cziegeler">Carsten Ziegeler</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="cziegeler">Carsten Ziegeler</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 3 Feb 2015 15:15:31 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 05:09:36 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 15:05:59 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>scr-2.0.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>scr-2.0.0</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14303414" author="bosschaert" created="Tue, 3 Feb 2015 15:17:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I also noticed that the bundle version is currently still at 1.8.3-SNAPSHOT. This should probably make a bigger jump given the changes...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14303484" author="cziegeler" created="Tue, 3 Feb 2015 16:01:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;My suggestion would be to readd that API, register the old service but let it just return empty collections&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14306924" author="cziegeler" created="Thu, 5 Feb 2015 09:43:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve added the old API together with an implementation back in rev 1657502&lt;br/&gt;
and deprecated the API&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as soon as the ScrService is registered, one test case fails - so there seems to be a timing problem with the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing line 152 in the Activator to&lt;br/&gt;
        m_runtime_reg = m_context.registerService(new String[] &lt;/p&gt;
{ScrService.class.getName(), ServiceComponentRuntime.class.getName()}
&lt;p&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a test fails &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14306934" author="cziegeler" created="Thu, 5 Feb 2015 09:58:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Failing tests: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failed tests:   test_concurrent_reference_bindings(org.apache.felix.scr.integration.Felix3680Test): unexpected warning or error logged: &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;org.apache.felix.scr.integration.components.felix3680.Main(1)&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; bind method &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;bindSCR&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; not found; Component will fail&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14307051" author="pderop" created="Thu, 5 Feb 2015 10:57:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hello Carsten; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the failing test (org.apache.felix.scr.integration.Felix3680Test), it looks like the&lt;br/&gt;
org.apache.felix.scr.integration.components.felix3680.Main class has now a &quot;bindSCR&quot; method that is now taking as parameter a &lt;br/&gt;
org.osgi.service.component.runtime.ServiceComponentRuntime object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, at the end of the ./src/test/resources/integration_test_FELIX_3680.xml file, the descriptor for the &quot;sCR&quot; Reference still refers to the old API:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
       ...&lt;br/&gt;
        &amp;lt;scr:component xmlns:scr=&apos;http://www.osgi.org/xmlns/scr/v1.1.0&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                name=&apos;org.apache.felix.scr.integration.components.felix3680.Main&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                activate=&apos;start&apos; deactivate=&apos;stop&apos; enabled=&quot;false&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                &amp;lt;implementation&lt;br/&gt;
                        class=&apos;org.apache.felix.scr.integration.components.felix3680.Main&apos; /&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                &amp;lt;reference name=&apos;a&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                        interface=&apos;org.apache.felix.scr.integration.components.felix3680.A&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                        cardinality=&apos;0..n&apos; bind=&apos;bindA&apos; unbind=&apos;unbindA&apos; policy=&apos;dynamic&apos; /&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                &amp;lt;reference name=&apos;logService&apos; interface=&apos;org.osgi.service.log.LogService&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                        bind=&apos;bindLogService&apos; /&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                &amp;lt;reference name=&apos;sCR&apos; interface=&apos;org.apache.felix.scr.ScrService&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                        bind=&apos;bindSCR&apos; /&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
        &amp;lt;/scr:component&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;can you try to update the ./src/test/resources/integration_test_FELIX_3680.xml and change the &quot;sCR&quot; reference like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
                ...&lt;br/&gt;
                &amp;lt;reference name=&apos;sCR&apos; interface=&apos;org.osgi.service.component.runtime.ServiceComponentRuntime&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
                        bind=&apos;bindSCR&apos; /&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="14307088" author="bosschaert" created="Thu, 5 Feb 2015 11:43:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=pderop&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;pderop&quot;&gt;pderop&lt;/a&gt; that fixes it! I&apos;ve committed the fix plus the extra service being registered in &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1657539&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?view=revision&amp;amp;revision=1657539&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14307201" author="cziegeler" created="Thu, 5 Feb 2015 13:30:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Awesome, I looked at the XML for hours and didn&apos;t see it ....Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14307776" author="djencks" created="Thu, 5 Feb 2015 19:01:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;IIUC you have added an implementation of the old service to the new service implementation, and are actually returning some information for the old interfaces.  I object in the strongest possible terms to this.  The meaning of the new interfaces cannot be stuffed back into the old ones, the old ones are just a wrong model of scr.  Freeing the implementation from the mistakes of the old model means that any attempt to return information in the old format will differ from what is returned in released felix ds versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be OK with including the old interfaces but returning absolutely no information in the SCRInfo service.  IMO There&apos;s no reason to saddle any implementation classes with returning deprecated information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have appreciated discussion on this when I originally proposed the version change rather than months later.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14308818" author="cziegeler" created="Fri, 6 Feb 2015 08:05:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I wasn&apos;t aware of the implications when the change happened, but I&apos;m now and It&apos;s not too late to discuss things . &lt;br/&gt;
I see your point, however the ScrService is widely used out in the field, it&apos;s even mentioned in OSGi books - so if we remove it and update the API to 2.0 this makes it impossible to simply update to the new DS implementation; it requires to change code - and the same is of course true if the service returns no information. And we gave our users no warning or time to act accordingly as we simply remove it from one version to the next.&lt;br/&gt;
I seriously think we have to find a compromise here - what about leaving it as it is; the api is back, it&apos;s functional, it&apos;s deprecated, it uses the wrong model - but it gives users a notice as it&apos;s deprecated - we could even add big bold log message each time the api is used. And once we released the new DS implementation, we remove the API so it&apos;s gone in the next version. WDYT?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14310549" author="djencks" created="Sat, 7 Feb 2015 04:49:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;cf my original attempt to discuss this april 16-may 14 2014:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://felix.markmail.org/message/ysjwfztinovvo7k5?q=from:david_jencks%40yahoo%2Ecom+list:org%2Eapache%2Efelix%2Edev&amp;amp;page=3&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://felix.markmail.org/message/ysjwfztinovvo7k5?q=from:david_jencks%40yahoo%2Ecom+list:org%2Eapache%2Efelix%2Edev&amp;amp;page=3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://felix.markmail.org/message/h7seohu2polq6aza?q=from:david_jencks%40yahoo%2Ecom+list:org%2Eapache%2Efelix%2Edev&amp;amp;page=2&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://felix.markmail.org/message/h7seohu2polq6aza?q=from:david_jencks%40yahoo%2Ecom+list:org%2Eapache%2Efelix%2Edev&amp;amp;page=2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://felix.markmail.org/message/6iux52gysnjg7fnv?q=from:david_jencks%40yahoo%2Ecom+list:org%2Eapache%2Efelix%2Edev&amp;amp;page=2&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://felix.markmail.org/message/6iux52gysnjg7fnv?q=from:david_jencks%40yahoo%2Ecom+list:org%2Eapache%2Efelix%2Edev&amp;amp;page=2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a hard time equating this with giving users no warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will have to study your proposal in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IIRC the actual implementation objects were exposed through the old API.  If we keep it I would really prefer to copy the info into more DTO like objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operations in the old API are just wrong and need to be disabled.  They act on the wrong logical layer of objects.  They cannot be made to work in a sensible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old API was flawed in that it conflated the two levels of DTO,   Basing the old info on the current objects will return different information than it used to and in particular for components that have no ComponentConfigurationDTO will return nothing at all.  It seemed impractical and pointless to me to expose the same info through the old interfaces as used to be exposed, but if you want to try to make it work I will not try to remove it, although I think a fragment bundle might be a more appropriate location.  I will seriously consider forking the project for my own use rather than go back to the incorrect data model being forced into the actual runtime classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only tool I&apos;m aware of that used the old data model was the web console, which (although I haven&apos;t actually tried it) ought to show the correct information now through the SCRInfo service which now uses the new data model.  Are there actually any other tools using the old data model?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14312855" author="cziegeler" created="Mon, 9 Feb 2015 20:47:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Many of our users simply rely on releases, so we have a 1.8.2 with the API in it and it&apos;s not deprecated. And we have the next release (probably 2.0.0) where the package is still there but changed incompatible (to version 2.0). And in this sense, users have no choice of simply upgrading the DS implementation as API is simply gone without any (deprecation) warning.&lt;br/&gt;
I totally agree that the old API has a wrong model, but we provided it and it&apos;s being used out there.&lt;br/&gt;
Now, in addition, it seems 1.8.2 has some bugs that are fixed in 2.0.0 - (it seems there are cases where a change to a factory config is not causing a reactivation of the component); so again updating to get just that fix is not possible.&lt;br/&gt;
The other option I see is we provide a compat package, that implements the old API based on the DTOs. So we clearly separated it and people upgrading install two bundles.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14313420" author="djencks" created="Tue, 10 Feb 2015 02:51:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Now, in addition, it seems 1.8.2 has some bugs that are fixed in 2.0.0 - (it seems there are cases where a change to a factory config is not causing a reactivation of the component); so again updating to get just that fix is not possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spec behavior is clearly wrong and caused by failure to notice that a section needed to be updated for 1.1, but apparently we could only have the correct behavior in 1.3 specced components.  No one has objected in practice to the correct but non-spec behavior that the last couple of releases have had.  If someone does we could release a 1.8.4 with just that fix.  Actually from your note it almost sounds like you would be ok with releasing 1.8.4 based on our last release with this wrong spec-required behavior present and the old api deprecated, and of course without any 1.3 features, and then as soon as the spec is finalized releasing current trunk as 2.0.0.  Since spec approval is still some months off, we could do this easily and it would give users several months of warning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you or someone wants to provide an additional bundle or fragment implementing the old api in terms of DTOs I won&apos;t object as long as the current behavior of the main bundle classes doesn&apos;t change.  The two Items I am totally against breaking to provide alleged compatible old behavior are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. The operations in the old api operate on the ComponentConfigurationDTO layer whereas the operations in the spec api operate on the ComponentDescriptionDTO layer.  Providing operations that operate on the ComponentConfigurationDTO layer is not acceptable, it cannot be made consistent with the spec API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. The component objects in the old api basically correspond to ComponentConfigurationDTOs.  However, since there is no ComponentConfigurationDTO, a bogus ComponentConfigurationDTO-like-object is provided whenever there is no actual ComponentConfigurationDTO, to represent the ComponentDescriptionDTO.  This is why a reimplementation of the old api needs to use objects independent of the runtime classes (e.g. SingleComponentManager which more or less corresponds to a ComponentDescriptionDTO).  We can&apos;t add a bogus ComponentManager in to represent the missing object modeling the ComponentDescriptionDTO.  However, I&apos;d be ok with an entirely new set of objects backing the old api, where the &quot;always present&quot; component is constructed based on either the ComponentDescriptionDTO (if there are no ComponentConfigurationDTOs) or the &quot;first&quot; ComponentConfigurationDTO.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14315905" author="cziegeler" created="Wed, 11 Feb 2015 09:47:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=djencks&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;djencks&quot;&gt;djencks&lt;/a&gt; After some rethinking of the issue, I agree that doing a compat bundle that acts on the DTOs is the nicer option. It gets the impl free of the cruft and people using that simply install the second bundle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, org.apache.felix.scr contains also the ScrInfo interface which isn&apos;t really used - as the package version is updated to 2.0 (due to the removal of the other stuff), this will break clients using this anyway. On the other hand, I&apos;m not sure if this one is used much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My suggestion is we complete remove the org.apache.felix.scr package from the DS implementation and put everything into the compat bundle including org.apache.felix.scr.ScrInfo and an implementation for that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14322713" author="cziegeler" created="Mon, 16 Feb 2015 12:36:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve now splitted this into a whole new bundle (scr-compat). This one registers the old ScrService and the ScrInfo.&lt;br/&gt;
The scr bundle itself is now free from the org.apache.felix.scr package (which currently causes the Aries bundle to fail therefore I disabled it for now).&lt;br/&gt;
As mentioned previously I think it makes sense to move the ScrInfo interface as well, if we still think this is usefull, we can add a similar interface in a new package in the DS bundle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the implementation I see a couple of problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How should we implement Component#getComponentInstance ? Currently it simply returns null&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The ScrInfo service is now always registered regardless of a system property which was previously used. I think as this is a compat bundle that&apos;s fine.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The ScrInfo#config method can&apos;t get the configuration and therefore it does not print it out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="14323134" author="djencks" created="Mon, 16 Feb 2015 18:47:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m using ScrInfo service so I&apos;ll need to reimplement it.  What package name would you suggest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8211; I&apos;m happy with Component#getComponentInstance returning null.  I don&apos;t think we should ever have exposed this, and we can&apos;t stop too soon IMO&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;#8211; glad you figured out how to implement &quot;isServiceFactory() &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;#8211; I won&apos;t be using this ScrInfo service so don&apos;t care about it.  I think registering it is fine.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;#8211; OK about ScrInfo#config.... maybe hooking it up to the new ScrInfo I&apos;m going to write would also work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m really not sure about your implementation of &lt;br/&gt;
        public void enable()&lt;/p&gt;
        {
            this.runtime.enableComponent(this.description);
        }

&lt;p&gt;        public void disable()&lt;/p&gt;
        {
            this.runtime.disableComponent(this.description);
        }

&lt;p&gt;The original implementation operated, basically, on a Configuration not a Description.  I&apos;m not going to be using this but changing the scope of the operation seems like an incompatible change to me.  I might rather have these no-ops.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14323748" author="cziegeler" created="Tue, 17 Feb 2015 06:58:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks David, so what about these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I think o.a.f.scr.info might be a good package for ScrInfo.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Component#getComponentInstance returning null: ok, I guess that&apos;s the best option we have&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ScrInfo#config: right, if we have a new service in a new package, we can easily hook it up. Maybe we can also simply delegate all methods to the new service?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I see your point with enableComponent/disableComponent : let&apos;s make it a noop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="14323767" author="cziegeler" created="Tue, 17 Feb 2015 07:12:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve changed the compat implementation as explained above.&lt;br/&gt;
I also added a o.a.f.scr.info package with the ScrInfo and implemented it in the same way the old one was implemented, so it&apos;s optional with a configurable property. I wouldn&apos;t mind dropping the property and always registering it; that way we could easily/always use it in the compat impl&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14323781" author="cziegeler" created="Tue, 17 Feb 2015 07:35:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve now changed the compat implementation to use the new ScrInfo service and simply delegates to it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            10 years, 40 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i254lr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>