<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 18:03:32 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[HIVE-3678] Add metastore upgrade scripts for column stats schema changes</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3678</link>
                <project id="12310843" key="HIVE">Hive</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Add upgrade script for column statistics schema changes for Postgres/MySQL/Oracle/Derby&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12615045">HIVE-3678</key>
            <summary>Add metastore upgrade scripts for column stats schema changes</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="shreepadma">Shreepadma Venugopalan</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="shreepadma">Shreepadma Venugopalan</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 6 Nov 2012 23:14:12 +0000</created>
                <updated>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 19:53:58 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 02:43:02 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>0.10.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Metastore</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>6</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13493392" author="gangtimliu" created="Thu, 8 Nov 2012 19:03:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=shreepadma&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;shreepadma&quot;&gt;shreepadma&lt;/a&gt; thank you for working on it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have plan when you submit a patch? I know it takes efforts to code and test in 4 different types of databases. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you please release mysql version first? Then file a jira to follow up Postgres/Oracle/Derby. Just a suggestion for fast release but up to you to decide. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thanks a lot again Tim&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13493587" author="shreepadma" created="Thu, 8 Nov 2012 22:59:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Tim: I&apos;m currently working on providing the upgrade scripts for different databases. Since there is a plan to release Hive 0.10 soon, we have to provide upgrade scripts for all of them. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13493589" author="gangtimliu" created="Thu, 8 Nov 2012 23:02:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;sure. no problem. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13499930" author="shreepadma" created="Sun, 18 Nov 2012 22:20:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Review board link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://reviews.apache.org/r/8119/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://reviews.apache.org/r/8119/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500500" author="cwsteinbach" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 18:51:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The upgrade scripts look good to me. As for &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3712&quot; title=&quot;Use varbinary instead of longvarbinary to store min and max column values in column stats schema&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-3712&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-3712&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which is included in this patch, I have started to wonder if it would be better for the metastore DB to store the column stats values (e.g. min/max value, num trues/falses, min/max/avg length, etc) as a JSON text blob. This approach would make the code more portable by eliminating dependencies on specific DBs and will also make it easier to add new fields in the future. The big downside of this approach is that we won&apos;t be able to push down column stats filters on these fields, but I&apos;m not convinced that this is a practical use case in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500526" author="shreepadma" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 19:26:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;With the changes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3712&quot; title=&quot;Use varbinary instead of longvarbinary to store min and max column values in column stats schema&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-3712&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-3712&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the column schema has &lt;b&gt;no&lt;/b&gt; dependency on any specific db. The column schema, with the changes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3712&quot; title=&quot;Use varbinary instead of longvarbinary to store min and max column values in column stats schema&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-3712&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-3712&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, uses simple data types, which are supported across DBs. The primary motivation for making the change to the schema in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3712&quot; title=&quot;Use varbinary instead of longvarbinary to store min and max column values in column stats schema&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-3712&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-3712&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was to avoid storing column statistics fields as a BLOB. The problem with using a BLOB is a) BLOBs are designed to store large volumes of data in the order of GBs and are hence stored outside the row. A consequence of this design is BLOBs don&apos;t perform well for storing small amounts of data. While some DBs such as Oracle inline small BLOBs, all DBs don&apos;t. While BLOBs are the only practical choice for storing data whose size is not known in advance, it is an overkill for storing around 100 bytes of data, and b) there is no uniform support across DB vendors and versions. Hence I don&apos;t really see the value in storing this as a JSON BLOB.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500570" author="cwsteinbach" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 19:47:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the confusion. When I wrote &quot;blob&quot; I was trying to convey only that the field will be opaque to the DB (since it&apos;s a JSON struct), not that it will actually be stored in a BLOB column. If we store the JSON struct in a VARCHAR we have at least 4000 bytes to work with.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500599" author="ashutoshc" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 20:10:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I agree with Carl, making it easier to evolve such that its independent of exact type will be a win. We already have one such use-case with BigDecimal support being added over on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-2693&quot; title=&quot;Add DECIMAL data type&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-2693&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-2693&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, following looks unintentional change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt; -- Constraints &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; table PARTITION_KEYS
-ALTER TABLE PARTITION_KEYS ADD CONSTRAINT PARTITION_KEYS_FK1 FOREIGN KEY (TBL_ID) REFERENCES TBLS (TBL_ID) INITIALLY DEFERRED ;
+ALTER TABLE PARTITION_KEYS ADD CONSTRAINT PARTITION_KEYS_FK1 FOREIGN KEY (TBTB_ID) REFERENCES TBLS (TBL_ID) INITIALLY DEFERRED ;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500673" author="shreepadma" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 22:03:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The problem with storing column statistics as a JSON blob in a varchar is some databases such as Oracle limit the size of varchar to 4000 bytes. While this may seem sufficient, JSON is verbose and the size of the JSON &quot;blob&quot; can exceed 4000 bytes, especially if we choose to evolve the statistics later. There is also additional serialization and deserialization cost while writing and reading statistics. Given that the column statistics schema consists of simple data types and is portable across DB vendors and versions, I&apos;d prefer to keep things the way they are.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500714" author="cwsteinbach" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 23:02:34 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem with storing column statistics as a JSON blob in a varchar is some databases such as Oracle limit the size of varchar to 4000 bytes. While this may seem sufficient, JSON is verbose and the size of the JSON &quot;blob&quot; can exceed 4000 bytes, especially if we choose to evolve the statistics later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the stats fields that exist right now, what&apos;s the longest JSON blob that we expect to create? Does it come anywhere close to 4000 bytes in length?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is also additional serialization and deserialization cost while writing and reading statistics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would be an issue if we were worried about filtering stats records based on stats values, but I don&apos;t think that&apos;s a practical use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given that the column statistics schema consists of simple data types and is portable across DB vendors and versions...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal with this change is to make the schema even more portable by modifying it to depend on fewer datatypes.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13500750" author="shreepadma" created="Tue, 20 Nov 2012 00:24:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Most users use multi byte variable width character set for storing varchar, so the number of characters available to store the JSON &quot;blob&quot; is less than 4000 characters and assuming an encoding of 3-4 bytes/character it is ~1000 characters. While 1000 characters may be sufficient today, it would not be as we add more fields to the JSON &quot;blob&quot; as a result of adding new types of statistics. When we exceed the 1000 character limit on the JSON blob, it is not clear how we would store the new types of statistics that we gather. While storing the statistics in a JSON &quot;blob&quot; may seem to help avoid schema upgrades in the short term (this is not entirely clear to me because I don&apos;t know what the max size of the initial JSON blob could be in the worst case, but I&apos;m assuming this for the sake of the argument), it would complicate upgrade when we hit the 1000 character limit. At that point, we will have no easy, simple way to evolve the schema.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13501392" author="ashutoshc" created="Tue, 20 Nov 2012 19:26:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Shreepadma, &lt;br/&gt;
Any thoughts on how we are going to store low and high values for BigDecimal column? Seems like there are four possibilites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We can add two more column in M*ColumnStatistics table of type BigDecimal: BigDecimalLowValue and BigDecimalHighValue. But is BigDecimal type supported consistently across different DBs?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We can have these two columns of type Double, but then we loose precision.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We can store as plain strings in column of type varchar.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We can store in json format in column of type varchar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;What do you think will be the best way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine there are other numeric types too for which neither of long or double will be a good choice. This question will come up again if we choose to add support for these later.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13502440" author="shreepadma" created="Wed, 21 Nov 2012 23:46:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Ashutosh: My answers are inline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can add two more column in M*ColumnStatistics table of type BigDecimal: BigDecimalLowValue and BigDecimalHighValue. But is BigDecimal type supported consistently across different DBs?&lt;br/&gt;
Agreed, BigDecimal is not consistently supported across DBs. Hence we can&apos;t add a BigDecimal column consistently across DB vendors and versions easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can have these two columns of type Double, but then we loose precision.&lt;br/&gt;
Yes, we can store BigDecimal and Long as Double but we will lose precision. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can store as plain strings in column of type varchar.&lt;br/&gt;
The maximum number of digits after the decimal point in a BigDecimal number is unlimited for all practical purpose. If we stored it in a varchar, it could result in truncation of some digits following the decimal point in some cases, but this seems to be the only practical solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can store in json format in column of type varchar.&lt;br/&gt;
The maximum number of digits in a BigDecimal number after the decimal point is unlimited for all practical purposes (Java allows nearly 2 billion digits after the decimal point). At this time, we collect MIN, MAX column values for numeric columns. If we stored BigDecimal value, we may exceed the varchar size limit and as a result truncate the JSON &quot;blob&quot;. This would result in a malformed JSON object. Additionally we will also lose some of the column statistics.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13503420" author="ashutoshc" created="Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:01:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Shreepadma, Seems like you are suggesting to store BigDecimal statistics as plain strings in CLOBs. I think its a fair choice. As I am thinking more about choice between one json blob for all stats Vs different column for diff stat, I am inclining towards different columns. Apart from performance argument for (de)serialization, extra code that we have to write to do (de)serialization will present more opportunities to introduce bugs, its always good to avoid writing code unless its useful in substantial ways. &lt;br/&gt;
In nutshell, I am +1 on the patch as it is. Unless, Carl has some other suggestions, lets go with it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13503425" author="shreepadma" created="Sat, 24 Nov 2012 20:53:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Ashutosh: Thanks for your comments. Do you think it makes sense to store numeric long/double/bigdecimal values in a varchar column? I don&apos;t see consistent BLOB/CLOB support across DB vendors and versions. If you agree, I&apos;ll make the change to store these numeric values in a varchar column and post a new patch. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13503438" author="ashutoshc" created="Sat, 24 Nov 2012 23:27:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Lets stick with long and double for numeric types (as it is at the moment), we shouldn&apos;t untype the data unless there is a strong reason for it. For BigDecimal, lets go with varchar column.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13503531" author="shreepadma" created="Sun, 25 Nov 2012 18:57:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Ashutosh: If store long/double types as a varchar instead of storing it as a numeric type, we can avoid evolving the schema when we add a BigDecimal type. That&apos;s the only benefit I see for storing long/double as a varchar. However, I agree with you that we should avoid untyping data when possible. Let me know your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13503535" author="ashutoshc" created="Sun, 25 Nov 2012 19:18:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Lets store numeric types with long/double. Can you add varchar column for BigDecimal in the patch. Lets finish the work while we are at it and get it in.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13504337" author="shreepadma" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 03:13:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Ashutosh: I&apos;ve uploaded a new patch which adds 2 varchar columns for storing BigDecimal low and high values. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13504338" author="shreepadma" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 03:15:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Updated patch is available on both JIRA and RB. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13504416" author="ashutoshc" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 07:14:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 patch looks good, though fails to apply cleanly. Can you update the patch on latest trunk?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13504852" author="shreepadma" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 19:16:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Uploaded patch rebased off tip of trunk. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13504869" author="ashutoshc" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 19:39:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Shreepadma for updating patch. Running tests now.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13505180" author="ashutoshc" created="Wed, 28 Nov 2012 02:43:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed to trunk and 0.10 Thanks, Shreepadma!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13505430" author="hudson" created="Wed, 28 Nov 2012 13:02:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Integrated in Hive-trunk-h0.21 #1822 (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://builds.apache.org/job/Hive-trunk-h0.21/1822/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://builds.apache.org/job/Hive-trunk-h0.21/1822/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3678&quot; title=&quot;Add metastore upgrade scripts for column stats schema changes&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-3678&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-3678&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : Add metastore upgrade scripts for column stats schema changes (Shreepadma via Ashutosh Chauhan) (Revision 1414509)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     Result = ABORTED&lt;br/&gt;
hashutosh : &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewcvs.cgi/?root=Apache-SVN&amp;amp;view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1414509&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewcvs.cgi/?root=Apache-SVN&amp;amp;view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1414509&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Files : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/derby/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.derby.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/derby/hive-schema-0.10.0.derby.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/derby/upgrade-0.9.0-to-0.10.0.derby.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/mysql/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.mysql.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/mysql/hive-schema-0.10.0.mysql.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/mysql/upgrade-0.9.0-to-0.10.0.mysql.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/oracle/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.oracle.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/oracle/hive-schema-0.10.0.oracle.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/postgres/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.postgres.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/postgres/hive-schema-0.10.0.postgres.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/postgres/upgrade-0.9.0-to-0.10.0.postgres.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/java/org/apache/hadoop/hive/metastore/ObjectStore.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/model/org/apache/hadoop/hive/metastore/model/MPartitionColumnStatistics.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/model/org/apache/hadoop/hive/metastore/model/MTableColumnStatistics.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/model/package.jdo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13548200" author="hudson" created="Wed, 9 Jan 2013 10:24:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Integrated in Hive-trunk-hadoop2 #54 (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://builds.apache.org/job/Hive-trunk-hadoop2/54/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://builds.apache.org/job/Hive-trunk-hadoop2/54/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-3678&quot; title=&quot;Add metastore upgrade scripts for column stats schema changes&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-3678&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-3678&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; : Add metastore upgrade scripts for column stats schema changes (Shreepadma via Ashutosh Chauhan) (Revision 1414509)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     Result = ABORTED&lt;br/&gt;
hashutosh : &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewcvs.cgi/?root=Apache-SVN&amp;amp;view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1414509&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewcvs.cgi/?root=Apache-SVN&amp;amp;view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1414509&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Files : &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/derby/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.derby.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/derby/hive-schema-0.10.0.derby.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/derby/upgrade-0.9.0-to-0.10.0.derby.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/mysql/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.mysql.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/mysql/hive-schema-0.10.0.mysql.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/mysql/upgrade-0.9.0-to-0.10.0.mysql.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/oracle/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.oracle.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/oracle/hive-schema-0.10.0.oracle.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/postgres/012-&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-1362&quot; title=&quot;Optimizer statistics on columns in tables and partitions&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-1362&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-1362&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.postgres.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/postgres/hive-schema-0.10.0.postgres.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/scripts/upgrade/postgres/upgrade-0.9.0-to-0.10.0.postgres.sql&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/java/org/apache/hadoop/hive/metastore/ObjectStore.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/model/org/apache/hadoop/hive/metastore/model/MPartitionColumnStatistics.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/model/org/apache/hadoop/hive/metastore/model/MTableColumnStatistics.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;/hive/trunk/metastore/src/model/package.jdo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13550253" author="ashutoshc" created="Thu, 10 Jan 2013 19:53:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This issue is fixed and released as part of 0.10.0 release. If you find an issue which seems to be related to this one, please create a new jira and link this one with new jira.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310060">
                    <name>Container</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="contains">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12616291">HIVE-3712</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310040">
                    <name>Required</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is required by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12465176">HIVE-1362</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12554090" name="HIVE-3678.1.patch.txt" size="37318" author="shreepadma" created="Sun, 18 Nov 2012 22:03:44 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12554254" name="HIVE-3678.2.patch.txt" size="36875" author="shreepadma" created="Mon, 19 Nov 2012 23:07:31 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12554955" name="HIVE-3678.3.patch.txt" size="38829" author="shreepadma" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 03:14:16 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12555050" name="HIVE-3678.4.patch.txt" size="38829" author="shreepadma" created="Tue, 27 Nov 2012 19:16:06 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>4.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>255599</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            12 years, 45 weeks, 5 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i0fspr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>90250</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>