<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 17:50:44 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[HIVE-144] Ql java source copied to build/gen-java</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-144</link>
                <project id="12310843" key="HIVE">Hive</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-98&quot; title=&quot;Dependency management with hadoop core using either maven or ivy&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-98&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-98&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the build process copies the contents of the ql/src/java directory to build/gen-java where the code generated from Hive.g is located. This makes it a bit more difficult to work on the project in Eclipse, since one has to add the build/gen-java folder to the project and not ql/src/java. This means we&apos;ll edit the ql java files in the wrong location. Adding both of these directories will of course result in duplicate entries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12410280">HIVE-144</key>
            <summary>Ql java source copied to build/gen-java</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/trivial.svg">Trivial</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="johanoskarsson">Johan Oskarsson</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="johanoskarsson">Johan Oskarsson</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 9 Dec 2008 15:05:09 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 00:08:36 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 03:02:13 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>0.3.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Build Infrastructure</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>2</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12654818" author="johanoskarsson" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 15:09:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;A few alternatives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If we&apos;d want to make the handling of generated code a bit more consistent we could put the code from Hive.g into svn under ql/src/gen-java much like the thrift generated code in other modules.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Copy ql/src/java into build/ql/java or a similar directory that is not build/gen-java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Personally I&apos;d vote for the first option.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12654821" author="athusoo" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 15:16:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;hmm...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the reason that these files are copied there is to support pre processing as that is needed due to differences in the hadoop APIs. Consequently, the files in ql/src/java are preprocessed and then copied to build/gen-java where everything is built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agreed though, that if this breaks eclipse then we need to figure out a way to make pre-processing work with eclipse. What are the standard practices to deal with pre processing in eclipse?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12654869" author="johanoskarsson" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 17:52:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Personally I would avoid preprocessing altogether, it sounds like a messy path to go down. For example unit testing becomes a pain and new code might have to be developed in two versions. And for example the unit testing template code is impossible to edit with an IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems the reason behind using the preprocessor is to support multiple Hadoop versions? Would it not be simpler and easier for both developers and the end user if for example Hive 0.19 only worked with Hadoop 0.19? That way there wouldn&apos;t be a need for preprocessed code. This is how HBase does it.&lt;br/&gt;
Are there any major drawbacks of that solution?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12654878" author="athusoo" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 18:29:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The overhead for that approach is too high. We had gone that route originally and were maintaining three different code drops for 0.17 (which we use in production at facebook), 0.18 which was a port requested by some external folks and 0.19 which was the hadoop version at the time hive was open sourced, and making these bug fixes and checking it into 3 different places was 3x the amount of work for the developers. Add to that, these branches would invariably diverge in the short term because the sequence of the checkins would not be the same, it became a big pain to port ones changes from one branch to the other because of the numerous merge conflict. So the solution for us, specially during this active phase of development was to have a single branch and compile it and run it with the different versions of hadoop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Hbase this probably works because they are perhaps a tad more mature at this point or at least have figured out the dependencies with hadoop to a large extent. It seems that they were also having a separate versioning scheme (different from hadoop) intially - I can hazard a guess that perhaps it was for the same reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, given the minor tweaks that were needed in the code to port it to 0.18 and 0.19, we saw this as the better of two evils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the unit testing template code - we have really taken the pains to ensure that the actual run time code is in QTestUtil.java and the velocity templates are just used to generate the front end junit test cases for different queries.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12654891" author="johanoskarsson" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 18:49:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I&apos;m misunderstanding, but what I meant was a release schedule similar to what HBase uses. Meaning that once a Hadoop version is out they try to have a new HBase version that runs on it within a month, they don&apos;t make sure it works with any previous version of Hadoop. &lt;br/&gt;
Once the branch of a new version has been created no new features goes in there, just serious bugfixes. This is also how Hadoop does it. So there would be very few patches of bugfixes to backport to a previous version of Hive. HBase also only supports the last two versions with new bugfixes, limiting how far back to port fixes.&lt;br/&gt;
This naturally forces people to upgrade to a recent version of Hadoop to get the latest Hive version but I don&apos;t think that&apos;s much of a drawback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps doing it differently in the early days of the project is ok, but it also sets a precedent that people are likely to follow further down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the HBase wiki on the version numbering: &quot;Going forward, new releases of HBase will have the same version number as the Hadoop release so there will be less confusion over which release of HBase works with which version of Hadoop.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12654983" author="jsensarma" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 22:03:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I would really like to see Hive be available for multiple versions of Hadoop.  As a company we are using Hadoop-17 - and i know of many other companies that don&apos;t keep up with latest releases of Hadoop (typically - once they have things working well on a particular version of hadoop - they tend to be conservative with hadoop upgrades).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the difference is that Hive is relatively immature and fast moving software right now where people are willing/wanting to try out the latest version (even while they continue using older version of Hadoop). So having latest features from Hive be available on older releases will really help in adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12654986" author="athusoo" created="Tue, 9 Dec 2008 22:21:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, we had followed the same exact approach that Hbase before switching to the current one and considering that there are a lot of fixes that we are making and we want to ensure that those fixes work with all the 3 versions of hadoop, having 3 branches to check those fixes into is very painful. The reality right now is that there are a lot of bug fixes and fixing them in all the 3 versions at the same time is too much of an overhead. Once we start cutting release branches, we would also follow the same methodology (which is quite standard) in that only blocker bugs get checked into the old branches, but right now, we have a number of those bugs which we want to get in before we embark on creating the first release. We do need an exercise to categorize those bugs - which I think we should do this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we can do to alleviate some of the problems is to restrict the preprocessing to a specific list of files (right now there is only 1 file that needs this). That would alleviate some of the problems with eclipse till we come up with a better solution for eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655179" author="johanoskarsson" created="Wed, 10 Dec 2008 11:43:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I can see you&apos;ve made your minds up, fair enough. Going back to the original issue, I&apos;ve got a patch that should help some with the Eclipse issue.&lt;br/&gt;
It simply generates the Hive.g Java code into a different directory, ql/src/gen-java so that Eclipse users can include that separately from the preprocessed source code.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655180" author="johanoskarsson" created="Wed, 10 Dec 2008 11:45:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I wasn&apos;t sure if you wanted to avoid including the generated code from Hive.g in the repository. It will of course mean patches that change the query language will have more changes in them but on the other hand it&apos;s more consistent with including the generated Thrift code as is already done.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655481" author="athusoo" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 03:06:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;We actually went through a lot of discussion and then decided not to include the generated sources into the svn tree and we actually wanted to do the same for the thrift generated stuff in the long run. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can the antlr stuff be moved to a different directory within build and we can achieve both the benefits there (no generated code and also easier for eclipse users). Something on the lines as zheng suggested in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-159&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-159&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655515" author="athusoo" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 05:18:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also wanted to add that the reason we could not get the thrift generated files out from svn was that the thrift compiler is C++ code and so we were not sure how portable it would be on different *nix platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655534" author="zshao" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 06:27:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Earlier before Hive is open-sourced we actually do check in HiveParse.java and HiveLexer.java, however they change greatly whenever Hive.g changes so the commits become very noisy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@Johan Can you take a look at the idea on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-159&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-159&lt;/a&gt; ? Let me know if that makes sense to you, and then we can merge the 2 issues.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655559" author="zshao" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 07:56:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Johan, just found my idea is just your option 2.&lt;br/&gt;
I&apos;d vote for option 2.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655609" author="johanoskarsson" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 11:33:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Updated patch for option 2. It just copies the preprocessed data into a folder that is different from the one containing the Hive.g generated code.&lt;br/&gt;
With the arguments above taken into consideration I agree that it&apos;s the best option.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12655741" author="athusoo" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 19:05:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;looks good to me.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12656234" author="zshao" created="Sat, 13 Dec 2008 03:01:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed revision 726160.&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks Johan!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12656235" author="zshao" created="Sat, 13 Dec 2008 03:02:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HIVE-144&quot; title=&quot;Ql java source copied to build/gen-java&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HIVE-144&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HIVE-144&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Hive/ql java source copied to build/ql/java to make it work &lt;br/&gt;
with eclipse. (Johan Oskarsson via zshao)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10032">
                    <name>Blocker</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="blocks">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12410472">HIVE-166</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310000">
                    <name>Duplicate</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="duplicates">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12410427">HIVE-159</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12395827" name="HIVE-144.patch" size="715" author="johanoskarsson" created="Thu, 11 Dec 2008 11:33:36 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12395727" name="HIVE-144.patch" size="975091" author="johanoskarsson" created="Wed, 10 Dec 2008 11:43:19 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>73753</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310191" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multicheckboxes">
                        <customfieldname>Hadoop Flags</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="10343"><![CDATA[Reviewed]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            16 years, 50 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i0l853:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>121969</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>