<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 22:04:26 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[TIKA-4082] Extraction from Microsoft Sharepoint protected PDFs doesn&apos;t expose exception like other parsers.</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-4082</link>
                <project id="12310631" key="TIKA">Tika</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;I have attached a PDF file (see &quot;MSFT Transcript FY23-Q3.pdf&quot;) that we are currently attempting to extract content from using Tika 2.4.1 (via Tika server), but since the file has had password protection added to it via Microsoft Sharepoint service, instead of getting the actual file content, we get content that says this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This PDF file is protected&lt;/em&gt;&#160;&lt;br/&gt;
&#160;&#160;__&#160;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&apos;ll need a different reader in order to view this content:&lt;/em&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download a compatible PDF reader.&lt;/em&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&#160;__&#160;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This PDF Document has been protected.&lt;/em&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The reader you are using does not support opening files protected by Microsoft Office&lt;/em&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_&lt;a href=&quot;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=231373_&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=231373_&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which is fine since the original content can obviously not be accessed without the password. It also throws an exception that we can see in&#160;&quot;X-TIKA:EXCEPTION:embedded_warning&quot; that is attached in the file &quot;password protected pdf exception.txt&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were surprised that we see any content at all as we have a similar document (see attached &quot;PasswordProtectedWorkbook.xlsx&quot;) that we test with that is password protected in a similar way, albeit a XLSX instead of a PDF, that doesn&apos;t return any content and throws an exception in &quot;X-TIKA:EXCEPTION:container_exception&quot; (attached in &quot;password protected xlsx.txt&quot;), which we currently treat as a failure mode. whereas we don&apos;t currently treat &quot;X-TIKA:EXCEPTION:embedded_warning&quot; as a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize these are different parsers, but since it is a very similar scenario, should they not be treated in the same way, at least voiding all content and emitting a proper failing exception instead of just what appears to be considered a warning? We are hesitant to make all instances of &quot;X-TIKA:EXCEPTION:embedded_warning&quot; as failures as we are unsure what other kinds of errors can be surfaced in that way. But it is clear to us that password protected files should be considered as failed to process. Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13540099">TIKA-4082</key>
            <summary>Extraction from Microsoft Sharepoint protected PDFs doesn&apos;t expose exception like other parsers.</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="4" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Minor</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="-1">Unassigned</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="chalton">Carey Halton</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:30:30 +0000</created>
                <updated>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 19:25:41 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:40:15 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>2.4.1</version>
                                    <fixVersion>2.9.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>parser</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>6</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17732765" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 21:11:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Encrypted file formats should all have the same behavior.  However, this file is, um, a bit vendor specific.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&apos;t looked closely, but it looks like the container file that you attached is a PDF with an embedded PDF.  The content that you see from the container file is what anyone not using an Adobe or Microsoft product&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;0&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; would see (Preview, Foxit, pdftotext, etc.).  That is literally the text that is stored in the container PDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The embedded PDF is the one that is actually encrypted via MicrosoftIRMServices, and Microsoft has added this embedded file description: &quot;This embedded file is encrypted using MicrosoftIRMServices filter&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can add special handling for this...especially because the vendor is rather big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;0&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; Caveat: &lt;a href=&quot;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/compliance/sp-compatible-pdf-readers-for-irm?view=o365-worldwide&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/compliance/sp-compatible-pdf-readers-for-irm?view=o365-worldwide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17732773" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:23:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Looks like we can be fairly general and throw an EncryptedDocumentException if the container file is a &quot;Collection&quot; and one of the embedded files has an Associated File Relationship (AFRelationship) of EncryptedPayload?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I don&apos;t like about this solution is that there theoretically could be other interesting content that someone might want from a document including other un-encrypted embedded files. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow devs (esp. &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tilman&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tilman&quot;&gt;tilman&lt;/a&gt;), any thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17732777" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:24:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=chalton&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;chalton&quot;&gt;chalton&lt;/a&gt; given that there might be other useful info in the file, are you ok if we throw the encrypted document exception after processing the parts that aren&apos;t encrypted?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17732827" author="tilman" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 03:06:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This is a PDF 2.0 file. AFRelationship and EncryptedPayload are new in File specification dictionaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFRelationship: &quot;name value that represents the relationship between the component of this PDF document that refers to this file specification and the associated file denoted by this file specification dictionary&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EncryptedPayload: &quot;shall be used if this file specification is an encrypted payload document that should be displayed to the user if the PDF processor has the cryptographic filter needed to decrypt the document.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No extra thoughts except disgust that a microsoft dialog appears when clicking on this file from windows&lt;br/&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;image-wrap&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/13059080/13059080_screenshot-1.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px solid black&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17732846" author="pwyatt" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 04:55:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Note that Microsoft IRM for PDF came in a few versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the earliest version I am aware of was known as IRM v1 from back in 2012 and covered by a publication called &quot;Microsoft IRM protection for PDF Specification, Supplement to ISO 32000 v0.9.6&quot;. A lot of the information for this has disappeared from the web but the PDFs haven&apos;t. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20120512233302/http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=29844&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20120512233302/http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=29844&lt;/a&gt; and then the v0.9.6 document which, AFAIK, was the last/latest. I found a copy on this hosting site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dokumen.tips/documents/microsoft-irm-protection-for-pdf-specification-supplement-to-iso-32000.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://dokumen.tips/documents/microsoft-irm-protection-for-pdf-specification-supplement-to-iso-32000.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;later (circa 2018) they moved to a IRM v2 as described here &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/security-compliance-and-identity/new-support-for-pdf-encryption-with-microsoft-information/ba-p/262757&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/security-compliance-and-identity/new-support-for-pdf-encryption-with-microsoft-information/ba-p/262757&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Microsoft then brought their &quot;unencrypted wrapper&quot; proposal used by their IRM solutions to ISO which was adopted and finally standardized in PDF 2.0 in 2017. Note that this did not define their encryption tech, just the method in which anybody&apos;s proprietary encrypted PDFs (e.g. DRM) could be wrapped (enveloped) in an unencrypted PDF to give users a far nicer experience rather than a vague &quot;encryption not supported&quot; message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17732848" author="pwyatt" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 05:03:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Note sure what Tika can really do about such things&#8230; same as if you encountered any of the many DRM or eBook solutions that are layered on top of PDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming PDFBox plays nice &#128512;, you &lt;ins&gt;can&lt;/ins&gt; still read the full structure of the PDF and get a lot of info, since encryption only impacts PDF strings and streams &#8211; not dictionaries, names, Booleans, arrays, indirect references, numbers, keywords, etc. Obviously text content is locked away in content streams which will be encrypted. This is a trick I use with Arlington when using pdfium. The issue for embedded files is that the filename inside the PDF is a string object and that will be encrypted &#8211; but you can still know and report that one or more File Specification dictionaries exist and maybe the annotation, Associated File, or other PDF feature that they are referenced from, even without the password. But the filename will be obscured by the encryption.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733103" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 14:35:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=pwyatt&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;pwyatt&quot;&gt;pwyatt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tilman&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tilman&quot;&gt;tilman&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m now thinking we could add a throwOnEncryptedPayload parameter to the PDFParser. The default would be &quot;false&quot; as is current behavior, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=chalton&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;chalton&quot;&gt;chalton&lt;/a&gt; and others could set it to true to get an EncryptedDocumentException immediately?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ll look for examples of the older method that &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=pwyatt&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;pwyatt&quot;&gt;pwyatt&lt;/a&gt; mentioned so that we can work with those as well. &lt;del&gt;It looks like &lt;em&gt;basically&lt;/em&gt; the same idea: wrapper PDF with an encrypted payload, but different keys.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, not at all, it looks like the encrypted file is simply appended to the initial PDF, and there&apos;s a &lt;tt&gt;WrapperOffset&lt;/tt&gt; that specifies the offset to the start of the encrypted file. &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/tongue.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/sad.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733104" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 14:41:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Separately, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tilman&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tilman&quot;&gt;tilman&lt;/a&gt;, would it make sense for us at the Tika level to catch PDFBox&apos;s IOException &quot;No security handler for filter&quot;... and rethrow as an EncryptedDocumentException?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733109" author="chalton" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 14:56:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;For us, if any part of a file is encrypted or password protected, I believe we want to throw an error as such. So I&apos;m ok with the exception being the default, or needing to pass a flag to make the exception happen as default if needed.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733117" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:17:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Makes sense. Sounds like we have a plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separately, I&apos;m not sure how you&apos;re using Tika, but in your current use of Tika, would you see, for example, EncryptedDocumentExceptions from encrypted XLSX files embedded in an MSG or PDF?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733135" author="chalton" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 15:35:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Not sure, would need to test it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733210" author="githubbot" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:36:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;tballison opened a new pull request, #1196:&lt;br/&gt;
URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/pull/1196&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/tika/pull/1196&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   &amp;lt;!--&lt;br/&gt;
     Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one&lt;br/&gt;
     or more contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file&lt;br/&gt;
     distributed with this work for additional information&lt;br/&gt;
     regarding copyright ownership.  The ASF licenses this file&lt;br/&gt;
     to you under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the&lt;br/&gt;
     &quot;License&quot;); you may not use this file except in compliance&lt;br/&gt;
     with the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;       &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing,&lt;br/&gt;
     software distributed under the License is distributed on an&lt;br/&gt;
     &quot;AS IS&quot; BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY&lt;br/&gt;
     KIND, either express or implied.  See the License for the&lt;br/&gt;
     specific language governing permissions and limitations&lt;br/&gt;
     under the License.&lt;br/&gt;
   --&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   Thanks for your contribution to &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Apache Tika&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://tika.apache.org/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://tika.apache.org/&lt;/a&gt;)! Your help is appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   Before opening the pull request, please verify that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;there is an open issue on the &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Tika issue tracker&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/projects/TIKA&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/projects/TIKA&lt;/a&gt;) which describes the problem or the improvement. We cannot accept pull requests without an issue because the change wouldn&apos;t be listed in the release notes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the issue ID (`TIKA-XXXX`)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;is referenced in the title of the pull request&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;and placed in front of your commit messages surrounded by square brackets (`&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;TIKA-XXXX&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; Issue or pull request title`)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;commits are squashed into a single one (or few commits for larger changes)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Tika is successfully built and unit tests pass by running `mvn clean test`&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;there should be no conflicts when merging the pull request branch into the &lt;b&gt;recent&lt;/b&gt; `main` branch. If there are conflicts, please try to rebase the pull request branch on top of a freshly pulled `main` branch&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;if you add new module that downstream users will depend upon add it to relevant group in `tika-bom/pom.xml`.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;   We will be able to faster integrate your pull request if these conditions are met. If you have any questions how to fix your problem or about using Tika in general, please sign up for the &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Tika mailing list&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;a href=&quot;http://tika.apache.org/mail-lists.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://tika.apache.org/mail-lists.html&lt;/a&gt;). Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;


</comment>
                            <comment id="17733212" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:49:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=chalton&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;chalton&quot;&gt;chalton&lt;/a&gt; are you ok if we add the file you attached to our unit tests?&#160; Any chance you could create a smaller file?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733232" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 20:42:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;A bit late, but I finally broke out the new spec, and 7.6.7 suggests that we should check for a Collection dictionary with view of &lt;tt&gt;H&lt;/tt&gt; (hidden) as well in addition to our current approach of looking at the AFRelationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I look back at &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-3666&quot; title=&quot;Detect and indicate file encrypted with Rights Management Service RMS/IRM&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-3666&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-3666&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, MS is doing to encrypting PDF what they did to encrypting ooxml.&#160; Wrap the encrypted document in an un-encrypted package.&#160; So, this is in the spec, and it is somewhat logically consistent with MS formats.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733510" author="chalton" created="Fri, 16 Jun 2023 13:35:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This file was shared with us by a partner team, and I did have permission to share it publicly, so I think its fine to include in your unit tests. However I&apos;m not sure on the exact steps to recreate it with a smaller file since it wasn&apos;t encrypted by us.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733528" author="githubbot" created="Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:35:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;tballison merged PR #1196:&lt;br/&gt;
URL: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/pull/1196&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/tika/pull/1196&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="17733532" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Fri, 16 Jun 2023 14:40:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I updated the wiki for the PDFParser: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=109454066&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/pages/viewpage.action?pageId=109454066&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17733606" author="hudson" created="Fri, 16 Jun 2023 17:03:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;SUCCESS: Integrated in Jenkins build Tika &#187; tika-main-jdk11 #1121 (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://ci-builds.apache.org/job/Tika/job/tika-main-jdk11/1121/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://ci-builds.apache.org/job/Tika/job/tika-main-jdk11/1121/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-4082&quot; title=&quot;Extraction from Microsoft Sharepoint protected PDFs doesn&amp;#39;t expose exception like other parsers.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-4082&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-4082&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (#1196) (github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/commit/ba77113802157ad81c93a231fae562fcadd1140f&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/tika/commit/ba77113802157ad81c93a231fae562fcadd1140f&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) tika-parsers/tika-parsers-standard/tika-parsers-standard-modules/tika-parser-pdf-module/src/test/java/org/apache/tika/parser/pdf/PDFParserTest.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) CHANGES.txt&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) tika-parsers/tika-parsers-standard/tika-parsers-standard-modules/tika-parser-pdf-module/src/main/java/org/apache/tika/parser/pdf/PDFParser.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) tika-parsers/tika-parsers-standard/tika-parsers-standard-modules/tika-parser-pdf-module/src/main/java/org/apache/tika/parser/pdf/PDFParserConfig.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(add) tika-parsers/tika-parsers-standard/tika-parsers-standard-modules/tika-parser-pdf-module/src/test/resources/test-documents/testMicrosoftIRMServices.pdf&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) tika-parsers/tika-parsers-standard/tika-parsers-standard-modules/tika-parser-pdf-module/src/main/java/org/apache/tika/parser/pdf/AbstractPDF2XHTML.java&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-4082&quot; title=&quot;Extraction from Microsoft Sharepoint protected PDFs doesn&amp;#39;t expose exception like other parsers.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-4082&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-4082&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; add annotation (tallison: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/commit/1e9f360efacb406e70a20781414a43181e3326ed&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/tika/commit/1e9f360efacb406e70a20781414a43181e3326ed&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) tika-parsers/tika-parsers-standard/tika-parsers-standard-modules/tika-parser-pdf-module/src/main/java/org/apache/tika/parser/pdf/PDFParser.java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="17733746" author="tilman" created="Sat, 17 Jun 2023 11:11:53 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Separately, Tilman Hausherr, would it make sense for us at the Tika level to catch PDFBox&apos;s IOException &quot;No security handler for filter&quot;... and rethrow as an EncryptedDocumentException?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. If you don&apos;t have a security handler, then it&apos;s the same for the user as if you don&apos;t have the password.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17735708" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Wed, 21 Jun 2023 12:58:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tilman&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tilman&quot;&gt;tilman&lt;/a&gt;!&#160; Implemented in &lt;tt&gt;main&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13425853">TIKA-3666</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="13059068" name="MSFT Transcript FY23-Q3.pdf" size="290327" author="chalton" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:04:19 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="13059065" name="PasswordProtectedWorkbook.xlsx" size="14336" author="chalton" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:18:51 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="13059074" name="Screenshot from 2023-06-14 18-13-21.png" size="67817" author="tallison" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 22:13:59 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="13059067" name="password protected pdf exception.txt" size="5550" author="chalton" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:18:21 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="13059066" name="password protected xlsx exception.txt" size="3661" author="chalton" created="Wed, 14 Jun 2023 19:18:21 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="13059080" name="screenshot-1.png" size="24689" author="tilman" created="Thu, 15 Jun 2023 03:06:35 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>6.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            2 years, 20 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z1ik5s:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>