<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 22:01:04 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[TIKA-2359] Extreme slow parsing on the attachment attached</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-2359</link>
                <project id="12310631" key="TIKA">Tika</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;i have 93s for parsing this document using 1.14 in server or in cli mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java:&lt;br/&gt;
java version &quot;1.8.0_121&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
Java(TM) SE Runtime Environment (build 1.8.0_121-b13)&lt;br/&gt;
Java HotSpot(TM) 64-Bit Server VM (build 25.121-b13, mixed mode)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;debian-jessie, 8GB ram in a docker container, current xeon 3GHz, so decent (2 cores limited)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13071172">TIKA-2359</key>
            <summary>Extreme slow parsing on the attachment attached</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="8">Not A Problem</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="-1">Unassigned</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="eugenmayer">Eugen Mayer</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 11 May 2017 13:49:17 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 14:13:00 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 14:11:57 +0000</resolved>
                                                                    <component>parser</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>7</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16006655" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 15:45:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Are you using tesseract?  I&apos;m getting 2.5 seconds via Tika app with no tesseract.  I&apos;ll give tika-server a try.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006661" author="eugenmayer" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 15:48:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;thats my call&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;java -jar tika.jar Sample-doc-file-2000kb.doc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to tesseract - i would say, no actively, not intended - by no means i am using &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apache.org/tika/TikaOCR&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/tika/TikaOCR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006665" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 15:51:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Doh, right, tika-app.  Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To confirm, if you type &quot;tesseract&quot; on your commandline, er, in docker, you&apos;d get an error message, not the list of options for tesseract, right?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006667" author="eugenmayer" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 15:54:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;interestingly, no, i get an option list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tesseract&lt;br/&gt;
Usage:&lt;br/&gt;
  tesseract imagename|stdin outputbase|stdout &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;options...&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;configfile...&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but interestingly, that is not due to tika, probably for libreoffice. Does that create an issue?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006680" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 15:59:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;y, Tika will call tesseract on every image file in your document, and you have quite a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the bottom of &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apache.org/tika/TikaOCR&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/tika/TikaOCR&lt;/a&gt; for how to turn off tesseract.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006689" author="eugenmayer" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 16:08:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;oh holy..seriously? By default OCR by simply having a lib installed which is installed by libreoffice? This is incredibly odd, seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the googlers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cat /etc/tika.xml&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;properties&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;parsers&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &amp;lt;parser class=&quot;org.apache.tika.parser.DefaultParser&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
      &amp;lt;parser-exclude class=&quot;org.apache.tika.parser.ocr.TesseractOCRParser&quot;/&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
    &amp;lt;/parser&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;/parsers&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/properties&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;export TIKA_CONFIG=/etc/tika.xm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the just run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;java -jar tika.jar test.pdf&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006692" author="eugenmayer" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 16:11:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Anyways, case closed, thank you for the quick response&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006697" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 16:17:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;IIRC, might also want to check ExifTool and Strings...which I think we also call if they exist...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow devs, am I right about ExifTool and Strings...and any others?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16006750" author="eugenmayer" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 16:44:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;any informations how the binaries are called and how to disable those?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.apache.org/tika/EXIFToolParser&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://wiki.apache.org/tika/EXIFToolParser&lt;/a&gt; accordning to this, exiftool needs to be activated&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cannot find anthing about &quot;String&quot; though&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16007276" author="lfcnassif" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 22:02:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In the past I was against enabling tesseract by default automatically if it is simply installed on the system (maybe it is there for other use cases), because of the very slow ocr process, but I was minority...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16007416" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 00:25:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry, took me a while to dig into this.  I hadn&apos;t seen our documentation on EXIFTool, and I know that I&apos;ve seen EXIFTool quite a bit in &apos;top&apos; when I run our regression testing...you&apos;re right...that&apos;s what the documentation says, and it&apos;s true for mp4.  The MP4Parser is sorted before the external parser so the MP4Parser gets called on an mp4 rather than EXIFTool.  However, for some other file formats, e.g. x-msvideo, that are covered by our ExternalParser/EXIFTool but do not have their own standalone parsers, EXIFTool is called.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong about our StringsParser.  That does have to be turned on...AFAICT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To disable external parsers, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1867&quot; title=&quot;Tika external parsers cannot be turned off without patching the tika-app-XX.jar&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-1867&quot;&gt;TIKA-1867&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16007718" author="eugenmayer" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 07:02:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Guys as far as i understood you just explained that  you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Are not using the easy deterministic, fast extraction libs if the are installed by default ( as a design decision ) - like exiftool, string and others&lt;br/&gt;
2. But you are using the most expensive, not deterministic on, OCR, by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what this means for legacy users, think about the decision process here - i would say this needs to be fixed. Not for me - i got this, but believe me, i am using TIKA for 4 years now and thats the first time i stumbled upon this - i am living with this waste of time for 4 years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This just fools your user base and makes you even look bad performance wise - i was comparing tike to other doc/pdf to text libs which performed better and was about to switch - because i had not idea i compare apple with oranges ( OCR vs plaintext ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a number, the example document take 93s with the defaults (so with OCR) and  0.9s without. We are talking about roughly 100x slower.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16008048" author="lfcnassif" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 12:31:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The problem is back compat. Some users now expect ocr enabled by default. Maybe add a warning in 1.15 that ocr is on and it Will be disabled by default in next release? And announce loudly in 1.16?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008057" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 12:42:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The other argument in favor of turning off tesseract by default is that it assumes English...so for those processing non-English documents who happen to have tesseract installed, Tika will be crazily slower, and the OCR will be awful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this right, or can users set the default language via a tesseract config file?  Is the language model specification available only via commandline?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008094" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 13:04:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;For broader community feedback, I put this to vote on twitter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ApacheTika/status/863016074664697856&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/ApacheTika/status/863016074664697856&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not compelled to follow the outcome of the vote, but I&apos;m curious.  I&apos;m +1 to change default behavior, esp. now that I know that users can have tesseract installed by other apps and not even be aware they have it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008102" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 13:10:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;And in response to this apparent (er, real) dichotomy, to paraphrase Eric Raymond, Tika is open source, a bazaar, not a cathedral.  Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=eugenmayer&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;eugenmayer&quot;&gt;eugenmayer&lt;/a&gt; for shouting in the bazaar so that we can address this. &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008121" author="eugenmayer" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 13:28:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tallison%40mitre.org&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tallison@mitre.org&quot;&gt;tallison@mitre.org&lt;/a&gt; well i am very good at shouting - but thats it! &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No seriously, if i would not value tika for what it is, i would not even have created an issue. I think helping getting the perspective other people have on your project sometimes removes a &quot;blindness&quot; you get from the inner. We know that from our products very well, also glad if somebody from the outside, e.g. a customer, shakes us up or just asking questions nobody actually calculated with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand that disabling it by default is a breaking change - but no functionality is removed - you have not just to enable it. Providing sane defaults is key for every project - and managing those over time is a very important task to keep the project alive, since this lets you get traction for new users which probably are not as convinced as i am an after 4 years, that tika is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside that, you should really claim something else for tike. The speed-benefit in server-mode is so immense, you should make this a default or at least promote that - but thats a different topic. that was just something we learned recently and it was significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just go on &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008188" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 14:11:39 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beside that, you should really claim something else for tike. The speed-benefit in server-mode is so immense, you should make this a default or at least promote that - but thats a different topic. that was just something we learned recently and it was significant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you share details of your findings, perhaps, on our users list (user@tika.apache.org)?  I&apos;d be interested to learn what you found!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008559" author="lfcnassif" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 19:01:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Still +1 to disable ocr by default.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008628" author="chrismattmann" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 19:55:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This is a tough one. In general I&apos;d be fine to add a parameter in the tesseract config that&apos;s a boolean org.apache.tika.parser.ocr.tesseract.enable (default &quot;false&quot;). That said, to do so, would inhibit those since &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-93&quot; title=&quot;OCR support&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-93&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-93&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that expect if they install Tesseract, Tika picks it up, and uses it. So, it would be an extremely non-back compat change b/c now we would require users to install some config file, update their java sysprops, or tika config parameters, which isn&apos;t nice at all. Part of the convenience of Tika &quot;picking up&quot; tesseract is that it is zero config, zero maintenance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Any change to this needs careful thought, documentation updates on the wiki, in CHANGES.txt, and convenience scripts, etc, that make it extremely painless for the one time upgrade, and going forward to use OCR with Tika. I am in the boat of users that depends/relies on this by default if tesseract is available/installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the opposite - would it be so hard to simply add a property to turn it on/off, and have it on by default (and then allow it to  be disabled with e.g., java -Dorg.apache.tika.parser.ocr.tesseract=false? To me that&apos;s easier, handles the back compat better, and is less intrusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 2c.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008774" author="lfcnassif" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 21:56:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Chris, thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this issue demonstrates a lot of users can have ocr on their systems not for Tika and they will get a 100X performance slowdown without knowledge about that. So the original hypothesis thrown in Tika-93 that tesseract is uncommon and if it is there it is for Tika is wrong. New users (and some old!) may not know they have to set a Java system property to get 100X speed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For users that need ocr it also should be simple to set a Java Runtime property. Of course this is a breaking change that must be documented all around, on wiki, release notes, site announcement, even logged. For users missing all those warnings, I think it is more likely they will note the breaking change and search for the option to get ocr back than a new user of Tika searching for an option to get performance speed up or to disable some ocr that they do not know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I propose for 1.15 add some logging saying &quot;ocr is on and can cause severe slowdowns and it Will be disabled by default in 1.16&quot;. So users will have more time to know about that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008782" author="chrismattmann" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 22:01:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=lfcnassif&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;lfcnassif&quot;&gt;lfcnassif&lt;/a&gt; great points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your point here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it is more likely they will note the breaking change and search for the option to get ocr back than a new user of Tika searching for an option to get performance speed up or to disable some ocr that they do not know about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not so sure about. In fact, the data tells me the opposite. We haven&apos;t had hundreds of JIRAs filed by users who find Tika to be slow. In fact, quite the opposite, and OCR has been on (if Tesseract is installed - so it&apos;s not &quot;by default&quot;, but if you have Tesseract installed, either knowingly or unknowingly) for quite a few releases now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m happy to have a waiting period to consider this. I also say I think it&apos;s just as easy either way - that is to set a system property to either enable, or disable OCR. For me, since it&apos;s been &quot;enabled&quot; if Tesseract is installed (big &quot;if&quot;) and that&apos;s been the expectation, I would say that we ought to stay with that, and then help the handful of users that have suggested performance is an issue in tickets like this by making that minority set the option as a command line parameter. I would be a big +1 as you say either way to have logging say &quot;OCR is on, did you really want that?&quot; or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008843" author="lfcnassif" created="Fri, 12 May 2017 22:39:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thank you Chris! Reviewing Tika-93, the original intent of my patch was to make the user have to configure a TesseractOcrConfig into parseContext to enable ocr. I think it happened to be enabled by default when some user, instead of configuring ocr properly, inserted a new Tesseractocrconfig if it was null in parseContext in the patch. But now it is the default since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think all is ok with the &quot;ocr is On/Off...&quot; log warning, it could have helped Eugen and others.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16008953" author="lfcnassif" created="Sat, 13 May 2017 00:14:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also, in the long run, disabling by default non pure java parsers, like is done for native libs, rest services, non java machine learning parsers (those are awesome!) and external parsers may be desired. Is there any other non pure java parser enabled by default, except tesseract parser?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16015571" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 18 May 2017 10:53:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I just added this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;                
LOG.info(&quot;Tesseract OCR is installed and will be automatically applied to image files.\n&quot;+
                        &quot;This may dramatically slow down content extraction (TIKA-2359).\n&quot;+
                        &quot;As of Tika 1.15 (and prior versions), Tesseract is automatically called.\n&quot;+
                        &quot;In future versions of Tika, users may need to turn the TesseractOCRParser on via TikaConfig.&quot;
                );
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if we want to change this message.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16015601" author="lfcnassif" created="Thu, 18 May 2017 11:19:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tallison%40mitre.org&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tallison@mitre.org&quot;&gt;tallison@mitre.org&lt;/a&gt;! I am ok with the message for 1.15.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16015636" author="hudson" created="Thu, 18 May 2017 11:51:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;SUCCESS: Integrated in Jenkins build Tika-trunk #1270 (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://builds.apache.org/job/Tika-trunk/1270/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://builds.apache.org/job/Tika-trunk/1270/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-2359&quot; title=&quot;Extreme slow parsing on the attachment attached&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-2359&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-2359&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Alert user that tesseract is available and will be used. (tallison: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/tika/commit/ebc87aec539eef752072e95315daee65f7f42ebb&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/tika/commit/ebc87aec539eef752072e95315daee65f7f42ebb&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;(edit) tika-parsers/src/main/java/org/apache/tika/parser/ocr/TesseractOCRParser.java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16015808" author="chrismattmann" created="Thu, 18 May 2017 14:14:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;totally agree! this is good for 1.15! thanks Tim and Luis!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16076480" author="tallison@mitre.org" created="Thu, 6 Jul 2017 13:15:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;We should make the warning a static-level-once-only warn, and the warning should be triggered on parse, not initialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to use the Initializable class for the warning, but this won&apos;t work in the case where someone excludes the tesseract parser.  We build an instance and then exclude it from the DefaultParser.  So, we have to lazily check if the warning has been given at parse time.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17524341" author="abias" created="Tue, 19 Apr 2022 14:13:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;=== English version follows ===&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sehr geehrter Absender,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ich bin nicht mehr an der Universit&#228;t Ulm t&#228;tig.&lt;br/&gt;
Ihre E-Mail wird nicht gelesen und nicht weitergeleitet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falls Sie mich bez&#252;glich der Services des Kommunikations- und Informationszentrums,&lt;br/&gt;
insbesondere bez&#252;glich Moodle, kontaktieren wollten, wenden Sie sich bitte stattdessen an&lt;br/&gt;
den Helpdesk des kiz unter helpdesk@uni-ulm.de.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Falls Sie mich im Rahmen der Moodle Community oder zu einem anderem Thema zu digitalen&lt;br/&gt;
Lerntechnologien kontaktieren wollten, k&#246;nnen Sie mich ab sofort unter&lt;br/&gt;
alexander.bias@lernlink.de erreichen.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;=========================================&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Dear sender,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not working anymore for Ulm university.&lt;br/&gt;
Your email will not be neither read nor forwarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you contacted me regarding the IT Services of the Communication and Information Centre&lt;br/&gt;
(kiz), especially regarding Moodle, please contact the kiz helpdesk at helpdesk@uni-ulm.de&lt;br/&gt;
instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you contacted me in the context of the Moodle community or another topic of digital&lt;br/&gt;
learning technologies, you can contact me at alexander.bias@lernlink.de from now on.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12867574" name="Sample-doc-file-2000kb.doc" size="2048000" author="eugenmayer" created="Thu, 11 May 2017 13:49:42 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>1.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            3 years, 29 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i3eu4f:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>