<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 16:44:12 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[KAFKA-2406] ISR propagation should be throttled to avoid overwhelming controller.</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/KAFKA-2406</link>
                <project id="12311720" key="KAFKA">Kafka</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a follow up patch for &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/KAFKA-1367&quot; title=&quot;Broker topic metadata not kept in sync with ZooKeeper&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;KAFKA-1367&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;KAFKA-1367&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
We need to throttle the ISR propagation rate to avoid flooding in controller to broker traffic. This might significantly increase time of controlled shutdown or cluster startup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12851589">KAFKA-2406</key>
            <summary>ISR propagation should be throttled to avoid overwhelming controller.</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="becket_qin">Jiangjie Qin</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="becket_qin">Jiangjie Qin</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 5 Aug 2015 05:36:02 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:02:51 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 21:55:32 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>0.9.0.0</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>6</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14654923" author="githubbot" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 07:11:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;GitHub user becketqin opened a pull request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/KAFKA-2406&quot; title=&quot;ISR propagation should be throttled to avoid overwhelming controller.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;KAFKA-2406&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;KAFKA-2406&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;WIP&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;: Throttle ISR propagation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    This is a follow up patch for &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/KAFKA-2406&quot; title=&quot;ISR propagation should be throttled to avoid overwhelming controller.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;KAFKA-2406&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;KAFKA-2406&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Further test to verify if this change alone is enough to solve the problem or not. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can merge this pull request into a Git repository by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    $ git pull &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/becketqin/kafka&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/becketqin/kafka&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/KAFKA-2406&quot; title=&quot;ISR propagation should be throttled to avoid overwhelming controller.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;KAFKA-2406&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;KAFKA-2406&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively you can review and apply these changes as the patch at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114.patch&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114.patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To close this pull request, make a commit to your master/trunk branch&lt;br/&gt;
with (at least) the following in the commit message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    This closes #114&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commit 27224779c21781e87353a28d060322bfc2c70be2&lt;br/&gt;
Author: Jiangjie Qin &amp;lt;becket.qin@gmail.com&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Date:   2015-08-05T07:09:06Z&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/KAFKA-2406&quot; title=&quot;ISR propagation should be throttled to avoid overwhelming controller.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;KAFKA-2406&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;KAFKA-2406&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Throttle ISR propagation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658417" author="junrao" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 15:50:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt;, thanks for the patch. Have you tested the patch in a cluster with lots of partitions? How is the controlled shutdown time with your patch?&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="14658531" author="becket_qin" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 17:13:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, I&apos;m doing the test right now. This patch only takes care of the second part of ISR propagation, which is controller to broker propagation. I hope this would solve our current problem. However, I am still not sure if creating a zookeeper path for each ISR change is a good way for the broker to report ISR change. Creating tens of thousands of ZKpath during cluster startup might cause issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658685" author="junrao" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 18:56:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt;, another way to reduce the overhead is to batch on the broker side. Every time a broker changes an ISR, it just saves the partition in an in-memory map. Periodically, the replica manager can collect all partitions in the map and write a single node in the ISR change path. This should reduce the number of UpdateMetadataRequests the controller sends to the brokers. It also reduces the number of ZK nodes to be deleted and the number of times the ISR change watchers are triggered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, could you provide a bit more details on the performance issue? Does that issue happen when shutting down the first broker in the cluster or when there is another broker just being restarted? It will also be good know where the bottleneck is: whether just in the number of UpdateMetadataRequests or in processing the watchers as well.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658781" author="becket_qin" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 20:01:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, I&apos;m still doing the test, here is what I see:&lt;br/&gt;
1. When controller was on old version, the controlled shutdown during rolling bounce seems to be normal.&lt;br/&gt;
2. After controller is running on new version, the controlled shutdown of brokers become very slow.&lt;br/&gt;
3. There are many zk paths still left in /isr_change_notification after the cluster bounce.&lt;br/&gt;
4. The first broker shuts down a little bit slower than before, but after that the subsequent shutdown takes super long - which is expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;1&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; I was thinking maybe throttling UpdateMetadataRequest would be the minimum solution for now, but I have the same concern as you do on the number of zk writes and watcher fires.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;3&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; probably is an indication of zk watcher cannot catch up with the change reported by brokers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having broker side to batch the changes makes sense. I am thinking about doing the following:&lt;br/&gt;
1. Broker only update ISR change in a batch periodically by writing partitions data to /isr_change_notification/brokerId_IsrChangeEpoch path. so zkWrite is bounded to #broker/update_interval.&lt;br/&gt;
2. Instead of using zk watcher, controller simply periodically query zookeeper and propagate ISR changes.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658909" author="singhashish" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 20:55:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt; it sounds like we are delaying ISR change propagation to fix this issue. Quick intimation of ISR change is a good thing, I believe. However, what &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt; ran into is certainly an issue that needs to be fixed. I think the issue will surface only when there are lot of changes happening in system, like during rolling bounce. Such scenarios are usually started by admins. If we just specify a way to turn off or delay ISR notifications only during such operations, we will still react fast to ISR changes and won;t hit this issue during rolling bounce like scenarios. Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658922" author="junrao" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 21:01:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt;, are you suggesting not using sequential ZK node, but just having an isrChangePath per broker and keeping updating it? Not sure how this coordinates with the controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, not sure having the controller periodically read from the IsrChange path is better. After the cluster is stable, there shouldn&apos;t be any ISR change and the periodic ZK read is just pure overhead. If we batch enough, there shouldn&apos;t be that many ZK watchers fired. Another optimization that we could do is that on controller failover, the controller can actually delete all existing sequential ZK nodes in isr_change before initialization. The initialization will read the latest leader and ISR for all partitions from ZK anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658929" author="becket_qin" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 21:04:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ashishujjain&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ashishujjain&quot;&gt;ashishujjain&lt;/a&gt;, the large number of ISR change might not only occur during Admin operations, for example, any long GC might cause this issue. Also when a broker goes down if zk session timeout is longer than the replica.lag.time.max.ms will also cause problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of think it is OK to delay the ISR change propagation. From user point of view, the ISR from two brokers still can be different even with the current approach considering we have a propagation delay.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658944" author="singhashish" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 21:10:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Makes sense. Can I suggest that we still keep the batching window duration configurable?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14658968" author="becket_qin" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 21:22:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, I was thinking to have a sequential path for each broker before, but it probably does not make sense. So a global sequential zk path should be good enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I agree that a periodically checking thread might be a bad idea. The main concern I have is that what if there are many brokers and they report isr change almost at same time, will the watcher be fired for that many times? Will that cause problem on controller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleting the zk path on controller migration makes sense and I&apos;m actually manually doing it now. The only issue I see here is that when I was trying to delete the zk path with &amp;gt; 110000 children paths, it takes quite a while. Not sure if that will cause issue. But if we throttle the zk path creation, it should reduce the paths to be deleted also.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14659007" author="junrao" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 21:40:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=singhashish&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;singhashish&quot;&gt;singhashish&lt;/a&gt;, yes, ideally we want to propagate isr asap. However, this is not critical for the current known use cases. The first use case is for admin tools like describing a topic. The second potential use case is for read affinity in the consumer, which is just an optimization. For both cases, delaying the propagation of isr is ok. Also, isr typically only changes during rolling bounces. If you turn off and delay the propagation then, most of the isr changes will be delayed anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can probably have a configurable batching window on the broker side.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14659039" author="junrao" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 21:55:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt;, the ZK watcher is a one-time watcher. So, when a watcher is triggered, you have to do another read to register the watcher. There could be multiple changes in between, but only one more watcher will be triggered. However, the brokers may not be writing to ZK at exactly the same time. So, the more brokers you have, likely the more times the watcher will be fired. I think if we make the batch window configurable, one can adjust this value based on the cluster size if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writes are more expensive than reads in ZK. By batching, we can significantly reduce the number of ZK writes for isr changes. The controller still needs to read the changed isr from ZK for all affected partitions though. Hopefully there&apos;s not the main bottleneck.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14659147" author="becket_qin" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 23:03:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ashishujjain&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ashishujjain&quot;&gt;ashishujjain&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, sure, we can make the batching window size configurable. The related question is that, If we are adding a configuration, do you think we need a KIP? I think this is a pretty small change, but since we think of config change as API change, so just want to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14659217" author="junrao" created="Wed, 5 Aug 2015 23:50:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=becket_qin&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;becket_qin&quot;&gt;becket_qin&lt;/a&gt;, we can probably do a quick KIP on the config change so that people are aware of it. We probably want to test if this approach works first.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14659269" author="becket_qin" created="Thu, 6 Aug 2015 00:43:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, sure. I&apos;m testing the new patch and will update the findings later. Also another problem in current code is that it is creating znode in /isr_change_notification, but we are deleting path from /config. So the znode never got deleted.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14662018" author="becket_qin" created="Fri, 7 Aug 2015 15:58:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt; I submitted a new patch and it works according to my test. Could you help take a look? Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14662059" author="becket_qin" created="Fri, 7 Aug 2015 16:35:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Just created KIP-29 for adding the config.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/KAFKA/KIP-29+-+Add+an+IsrPropagateIntervalMs+configuration+to+KafkaConfig&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/KAFKA/KIP-29+-+Add+an+IsrPropagateIntervalMs+configuration+to+KafkaConfig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14662766" author="becket_qin" created="Sat, 8 Aug 2015 02:54:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ashishujjain&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ashishujjain&quot;&gt;ashishujjain&lt;/a&gt; We are discussing whether to expose the batch window as a configuration or not in the discussion mail thread. It seems people are a little bit hesitant on adding this configuration because of lack of valid use case. Do you have some use cases that can share on the discussion thread?&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14679296" author="junrao" created="Sun, 9 Aug 2015 19:23:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Left some review comments in the PR.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14679395" author="becket_qin" created="Sun, 9 Aug 2015 23:11:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;, thanks for the review. Just updated the PR to address your comments.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14682431" author="becket_qin" created="Tue, 11 Aug 2015 20:28:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ashishujjain&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ashishujjain&quot;&gt;ashishujjain&lt;/a&gt; We discussed about KIP-29 on today&apos;s KIP hangout. In this ticket we will hard code the ISR propagation interval to fix the trunk. I will create another ticket and link that to KIP-29 and submit follow up patch once we reach conclusion for KIP-29.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just submitted a new patch that has the ISR propagation interval hard coded to 5 seconds. Could you help review? Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jiangjie (Becket) Qin&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14695932" author="becket_qin" created="Thu, 13 Aug 2015 20:58:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt; ping for review.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14696012" author="githubbot" created="Thu, 13 Aug 2015 21:55:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Github user asfgit closed the pull request at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14696013" author="junrao" created="Thu, 13 Aug 2015 21:55:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Issue resolved by pull request 114&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/kafka/pull/114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14696196" author="becket_qin" created="Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:02:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=junrao&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;junrao&quot;&gt;junrao&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            10 years, 14 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i2icjr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>