<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 21:44:14 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[HADOOP-10213] Fix bugs parsing ACL spec in FsShell setfacl.</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HADOOP-10213</link>
                <project id="12310240" key="HADOOP">Hadoop Common</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;When calling setfacl -x to remove ACL entries, it does not make sense for the entries in the ACL spec to contain permissions.  The permissions should be unspecified, and the CLI should return an error if the user attempts to provide permissions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12687963">HADOOP-10213</key>
            <summary>Fix bugs parsing ACL spec in FsShell setfacl.</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="vinayakumarb">Vinayakumar B</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="cnauroth">Chris Nauroth</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 8 Jan 2014 23:06:27 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 04:14:02 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 18:03:05 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>HDFS ACLs (HDFS-4685)</version>
                                    <fixVersion>HDFS ACLs (HDFS-4685)</fixVersion>
                                    <component>tools</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>2</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13866027" author="cnauroth" created="Wed, 8 Jan 2014 23:09:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Here is an example on Linux showing rejection of an attempt to specify permissions in an ACL spec with setfacl -x:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; setfacl -x user:bruce:rw- file2
setfacl: Option -x: Invalid argument near character 12
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of the following are correct syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;setfacl -x user:bruce file2
setfacl -x user:bruce: file2
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=vinayrpet&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;vinayrpet&quot;&gt;vinayrpet&lt;/a&gt;, if you&apos;re interested in taking this, would you please assign the issue to yourself?  Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13866298" author="vinayrpet" created="Thu, 9 Jan 2014 04:14:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks chris. I will make necessary changes and post a patch soon.. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13866530" author="vinayrpet" created="Thu, 9 Jan 2014 10:44:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached the patch for validation for -x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also removed the permissions from equals() and hashCode() as AclEntry always may not carry permissions.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13866531" author="vinayrpet" created="Thu, 9 Jan 2014 10:44:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Please review&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13870184" author="cnauroth" created="Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:40:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi, Vinay.  This looks good, but I think we&apos;ll need to revert the &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry&lt;/tt&gt; portion of the change.  There are various unit tests that rely on &lt;tt&gt;assertEquals&lt;/tt&gt; or &lt;tt&gt;assertArrayEquals&lt;/tt&gt; to check that the correct ACL was applied to a file.  With this change, those &lt;tt&gt;assertEquals&lt;/tt&gt; calls would pass even if the permissions inside the ACL entries were incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even putting aside tests, this is a public user-facing class, and callers likely would find it surprising if &quot;user:bruce:rwx&quot; and &quot;user:bruce:---&quot; were considered equal.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13870188" author="cnauroth" created="Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:43:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;One more note on the above.  The implementation of &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry#equals&lt;/tt&gt; is using Guava&apos;s &lt;tt&gt;Objects#equal&lt;/tt&gt;.  That method returns true if both instances are null, so I think that addresses your concern stated earlier about correct behavior if the &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry&lt;/tt&gt; does not carry permissions.  &lt;tt&gt;Objects#hashCode&lt;/tt&gt; is null-safe too.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13870382" author="vinayrpet" created="Tue, 14 Jan 2014 04:44:36 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi, Vinay. This looks good, but I think we&apos;ll need to revert the AclEntry portion of the change. There are various unit tests that rely on assertEquals or assertArrayEquals to check that the correct ACL was applied to a file. With this change, those assertEquals calls would pass even if the permissions inside the ACL entries were incorrect. Even putting aside tests, this is a public user-facing class, and callers likely would find it surprising if &quot;user:bruce:rwx&quot; and &quot;user:bruce:---&quot; were considered equal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this reason only I have earlier included permissions also from command line for -x.&lt;br/&gt;
But in this case, say permissions are not passed from the commandline, but the ACLEntries contain ACL for same user/group with some permissions. In this case, permissions will differ and objects also will differ.&lt;br/&gt;
In general, there will be only one ACL entry per user/group in each type no matter what are the permissions. I agree that we cannot consider &quot;user:bruce:rwx&quot; and &quot;user:bruce:---&quot; as equal, but also both these entries cannot be present in list of ACL entries right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my preference is that we need to check for permissions separately whenever necessary, instead of including in equals() and hashCode(). &lt;br/&gt;
What you say?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13871437" author="cnauroth" created="Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:47:43 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In general, there will be only one ACL entry per user/group in each type no matter what are the permissions. I agree that we cannot consider &quot;user:bruce:rwx&quot; and &quot;user:bruce:---&quot; as equal, but also both these entries cannot be present in list of ACL entries right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is correct.  It doesn&apos;t make sense to have 2 different ACL entries with the same scope + type + name.  We already enforce this on the NameNode side in &lt;tt&gt;AclTransformation#buildAndValidateAcl&lt;/tt&gt;.  The validation logic rejects duplicate ACL entries, where two entries are considered duplicate if they have the same scope + type + name (even if the permissions are different).  If a user supplies duplicates like this, then we&apos;ll return an error.  This is regardless of whether the request comes in through the CLI, another interface, or programmatically through &lt;tt&gt;FileSystem&lt;/tt&gt; method calls.  The enforcement is centralized on the server side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So my preference is that we need to check for permissions separately whenever necessary, instead of including in equals() and hashCode().&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering that the NameNode is enforcing the required uniqueness on the server side, let&apos;s not remove permissions from consideration in &lt;tt&gt;equals&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;hashCode&lt;/tt&gt;.  There are 2 reasons for this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;As mentioned above, it&apos;s a public user-facing class, and most callers will have an intuition that &lt;tt&gt;equals&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;hashCode&lt;/tt&gt; consider all data members.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&apos;m also anticipating that we&apos;ll want to include perms when the NameNode starts de-duplicating ACLs via the Global ACL Set as described in the design doc (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HDFS-5620&quot; title=&quot;NameNode: implement Global ACL Set as a memory optimization.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HDFS-5620&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HDFS-5620&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).  The implementation of this is likely to be sensitive to &lt;tt&gt;equals&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;hashCode&lt;/tt&gt;, and we wouldn&apos;t want it to de-duplicate &quot;user:bruce:---&quot; based on seeing that &quot;user:bruce:rwx&quot; already exists in the live set.  If we remove perms from the &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry&lt;/tt&gt; implementation here, then the NameNode is likely going to have to translate everything to some kind of alternative internal class with an &lt;tt&gt;equals&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;hashCode&lt;/tt&gt; that includes perms.  This would require additional awkward data copying code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13871616" author="vinayrpet" created="Wed, 15 Jan 2014 04:00:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Ok. If the validation of the acl is already done for duplicate then no problem. Only thing I am concerned about is while implementation removal of acl entry proper ack entry should be found regardless of the permission. &lt;br/&gt;
I will post a patch soon by removing the modifications to AclEntry&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13871689" author="cnauroth" created="Wed, 15 Jan 2014 05:57:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Vinay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only thing I am concerned about is while implementation removal of acl entry proper ack entry should be found regardless of the permission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is important too.  This is also handled server-side in the NameNode.  The relevant code is in &lt;tt&gt;AclTransformation#filterAclEntriesByAclSpec&lt;/tt&gt;, which also uses a helper method &lt;tt&gt;AclTransformation#ValidatedAclSpec#containsKey&lt;/tt&gt;.  This method finds an entry in the ACL spec by a key consisting of scope + type + name (but not permission).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13873437" author="vinayrpet" created="Thu, 16 Jan 2014 14:34:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Reverted the changes in AclEntry equals() and hashCode().&lt;br/&gt;
Sorry for the noise. : )&lt;br/&gt;
Please review&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13873732" author="cnauroth" created="Thu, 16 Jan 2014 18:43:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;No worries.  The patch looks good.  Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have one more question for you.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sachinjose2007%40gmail.com&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sachinjose2007@gmail.com&quot;&gt;sachinjose2007@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; has provided a WebHDFS patch on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HDFS-5608&quot; title=&quot;WebHDFS: implement ACL APIs.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HDFS-5608&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HDFS-5608&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and it needs the same logic for parsing an ACL spec from a query parameter.  I&apos;m thinking that we could refactor your &lt;tt&gt;AclCommands#SetfaclCommand#parseAclSpec&lt;/tt&gt; method to a public static method on &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry&lt;/tt&gt;, so that WebHDFS can reuse the parsing logic instead of duplicating it.  It would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;  /**
   * Parses a string representation of an ACL spec into a list of AclEntry
   * objects.  Example: &lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;user::rwx,user:foo:rw-,group::r--,other::---&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
   *
   * @param aclSpec &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; ACL spec to parse
   * @&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; List&amp;lt;AclEntry&amp;gt; containing parsed ACL spec
   */
  &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; List&amp;lt;AclEntry&amp;gt; parseAclSpec(&lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; aclSpec) {
    ...
  }
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think that makes sense?  If so, would you want to do that refactoring as part of this patch?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13874465" author="vinayrpet" created="Fri, 17 Jan 2014 05:46:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached the refactored patch to separate parse logic to static method in AclEntry.&lt;br/&gt;
Please review&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13875176" author="cnauroth" created="Fri, 17 Jan 2014 19:40:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The refactoring change looks good.  Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve discovered a few other small problems while running a dev build of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HDFS-4685&quot; title=&quot;Implementation of ACLs in HDFS&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HDFS-4685&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HDFS-4685&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; branch plus some additional uncommitted patches.  Can we address the following as part of this patch?  I think the changes will be small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I noticed that setfacl wasn&apos;t actually doing anything.  This is because it was popping the path argument from the list, and this caused the base classes to think there was no path to process.  To fix this, please 1) remove the &lt;tt&gt;SetfaclCommand#path&lt;/tt&gt; member variable, 2) in &lt;tt&gt;SetfaclCommand#processOptions&lt;/tt&gt; remove the line that deleted from the &lt;tt&gt;args&lt;/tt&gt; list and assigned to &lt;tt&gt;path&lt;/tt&gt;, 3) in &lt;tt&gt;SetfaclCommand#processPath&lt;/tt&gt;, you can use &lt;tt&gt;item.path&lt;/tt&gt; instead of the old &lt;tt&gt;path&lt;/tt&gt; member variable.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I noticed that &lt;tt&gt;parseAclSpec&lt;/tt&gt; was failing for comma-separated lists of multiple ACL entries.  The reason for this is that within the for loop, it&apos;s calling &lt;tt&gt;aclSpec.split&lt;/tt&gt;, which splits the whole ACL spec.  Instead, it should be calling &lt;tt&gt;aclStr.split&lt;/tt&gt; to split just the single ACL entry.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Let&apos;s add a test to &lt;tt&gt;TestAclCommands&lt;/tt&gt; for passing a comma-separated list to cover the above change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13875598" author="vinayrpet" created="Sat, 18 Jan 2014 09:10:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Chris for checking. &lt;br/&gt;
Corrected all your comments and attached the patch. Please review&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13875692" author="cnauroth" created="Sat, 18 Jan 2014 17:18:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for making those changes.  I found one more thing.  &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry#parseAclSpec&lt;/tt&gt; is setting the name of the &lt;tt&gt;AclEntry&lt;/tt&gt; to an empty &lt;tt&gt;String&lt;/tt&gt; when the name is unspecified in the input string.  This can cause validation failures on the server side when we try to check that the caller didn&apos;t specify a name for entries that do not permit a name.  For example, the other entry can never have a name, so the NameNode will throw an exception back to the client if it tries to do something like setfacl -m other:vinay:rwx.  I&apos;m pasting below a small diff that fixes the problem.  Could you please incorporate this into your patch and add another test in &lt;tt&gt;TestAclCommands&lt;/tt&gt; to cover this?  Thanks again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;diff --git a/hadoop-common-project/hadoop-common/src/main/java/org/apache/hadoop/fs/permission/AclEntry.java b/hadoo
index 6143ef8..7de6115 100644
--- a/hadoop-common-project/hadoop-common/src/main/java/org/apache/hadoop/fs/permission/AclEntry.java
+++ b/hadoop-common-project/hadoop-common/src/main/java/org/apache/hadoop/fs/permission/AclEntry.java
@@ -249,7 +249,10 @@ &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;private&lt;/span&gt; AclEntry(AclEntryType type, &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; name, FsAction permission, AclEntrySc
             &lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;Invalid type of acl in &amp;lt;aclSpec&amp;gt; :&quot;&lt;/span&gt; + aclStr);
       }
 
-      builder.setName(split[index++]);
+      &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; name = split[index++];
+      &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (!name.isEmpty()) {
+        builder.setName(name);
+      }
 
       &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (expectedAclSpecLength == 3) {
         &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; permission = split[index++];
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13875694" author="cnauroth" created="Sat, 18 Jan 2014 17:19:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Updating summary to show expanded scope of the patch.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13876167" author="vinayrpet" created="Mon, 20 Jan 2014 05:45:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attaching the updated patch&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13876637" author="cnauroth" created="Mon, 20 Jan 2014 18:03:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 for the patch.  Thanks for fixing all of this, Vinay.  I&apos;ve committed it to the feature branch.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13877168" author="vinayrpet" created="Tue, 21 Jan 2014 04:14:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Chris for the detailed reviews and commit.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12682466">HADOOP-10187</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12686476">HADOOP-10184</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12623901" name="HADOOP-10213.patch" size="10938" author="vinayakumarb" created="Mon, 20 Jan 2014 05:45:40 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12623786" name="HADOOP-10213.patch" size="10407" author="vinayakumarb" created="Sat, 18 Jan 2014 09:10:33 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12623586" name="HADOOP-10213.patch" size="7926" author="vinayakumarb" created="Fri, 17 Jan 2014 05:46:48 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12623388" name="HADOOP-10213.patch" size="2958" author="vinayakumarb" created="Thu, 16 Jan 2014 14:34:08 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12622153" name="HADOOP-10213.patch" size="3785" author="vinayakumarb" created="Thu, 9 Jan 2014 10:44:00 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>5.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>366970</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310191" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multicheckboxes">
                        <customfieldname>Hadoop Flags</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="10343"><![CDATA[Reviewed]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            11 years, 44 weeks ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i1r97b:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>367280</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310320" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiversion">
                        <customfieldname>Target Version/s</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12325672">HDFS ACLs (HDFS-4685)</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>