<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 21:31:49 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[HADOOP-2366] Space in the value for dfs.data.dir can cause great problems</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HADOOP-2366</link>
                <project id="12310240" key="HADOOP">Hadoop Common</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;The following configuration causes problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;property&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;dfs.data.dir&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;value&amp;gt;/mnt/hstore2/hdfs, /home/foo/dfs&amp;lt;/value&amp;gt;  &lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;description&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  Determines where on the local filesystem an DFS data node  should store its bl&lt;br/&gt;
ocks.  If this is a comma-delimited  list of directories, then data will be stor&lt;br/&gt;
ed in all named  directories, typically on different devices.  Directories that &lt;br/&gt;
do not exist are ignored.  &lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;/description&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/property&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the space after the comma causes the second directory for storage to be &quot; /home/foo/dfs&quot; which is in a directory named &amp;lt;SPACE&amp;gt; which contains a sub-dir named &quot;home&quot; in the hadoop datanodes default directory.  This will typically cause the user&apos;s home partition to fill, but will be very hard for the user to understand since a directory with a whitespace name is hard to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My proposed solution would be to trimLeft all path names from this and similar property after splitting on comma.  This still allows spaces in file and directory names but avoids this problem. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12384096">HADOOP-2366</key>
            <summary>Space in the value for dfs.data.dir can cause great problems</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="pirroh">Michele Catasta</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="tdunning@veoh.com">Ted Dunning</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 6 Dec 2007 17:39:21 +0000</created>
                <updated>Thu, 2 May 2013 02:29:25 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Tue, 30 Jun 2009 21:46:33 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>0.21.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>conf</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>3</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12634707" author="szetszwo" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2008 00:18:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; a directory with a whitespace name is hard to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be right but systems like GNU/Linux support this.  For example,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;[latest]$ mkdir &quot; &quot;
[latest]$ mkdir &quot; &quot;/foo
[latest]$ cd \ /foo/
[foo]$ pwd
/home/tsz/hadoop/latest/ /foo
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12634728" author="craigm" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2008 01:33:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Why stop on trim left? &lt;br/&gt;
IMHO you should assume that the whitespace is part of the delimitation, not of the pathname.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not sure where the split happens to look at the code, but I suggest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; parts[] = value.split(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;\\s*,\\s*&quot;&lt;/span&gt;);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And/Or pathnames with space could be placed in quotes which are trimmed off, however, double quote is also an acceptable file/diretory name on GNU/Linux.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12634730" author="rangadi" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2008 01:43:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 for trimming on either side of the dir path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is ok not to have the flexibility to specify directories with spaces at the end. If a user really wants to use such directories, as symlink could be used. Note that we already have restriction that directory names can not have &apos;,&apos; in their name.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12634844" author="steve_l" created="Fri, 26 Sep 2008 12:56:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;And by using XML1.0, you have an explicit restriction on not having any characters &amp;lt; 32 in the name other than, possibly, CR, LF and TAB. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to consider in testing this is to try some high-UTF8 characters and see that everything works with non-ascii filenames, as that checks assumptions quite well.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12718246" author="pirroh" created="Wed, 10 Jun 2009 23:12:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;getStrings() trims leading and trailing whitespace by default now.&lt;br/&gt;
Patch includes also a simple unit test.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12718249" author="pirroh" created="Wed, 10 Jun 2009 23:21:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch updated, it was adding a warning on StringUtils.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719212" author="tlipcon" created="Sun, 14 Jun 2009 01:08:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch looks OK, but why not use str.split(&quot;\\s*,&lt;br class=&quot;atl-forced-newline&quot; /&gt;s*&quot;) as suggested by Craig above? Then you can simply use Arrays.asList and not have to iterate over the split array to create an ArrayList.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719276" author="pirroh" created="Sun, 14 Jun 2009 15:07:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch updated, now it&apos;s using &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;split(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;\\s*,\\s*&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@tlipcon: Thanks for the comment! Gotta be honest, I wasn&apos;t using the regex because I thought mine was the only way to let getStrings() behave as it was doing before regarding trailing empty tokens. &lt;br/&gt;
Actually, I took a look at the code which is using getStrings(), and throwing away the trailing empty token should not break anything (while helps the users who leave a final comma without any following path). Anyway, to make it behave as it was before, just add a -1 as the second argument of split(). Hope it&apos;s OK now &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719655" author="tlipcon" created="Mon, 15 Jun 2009 17:19:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think this patch changes the behavior of getStrings when the configured value is the empty string &quot;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;bsh % System.out.println(&quot;&quot;.split(&quot;\\s*,\\s*&quot;).length);
1
bsh % System.out.println(&quot;&quot;.split(&quot;\\s*,\\s*&quot;)[0]);    

bsh % import java.util.StringTokenizer;
bsh % StringTokenizer tk = new StringTokenizer(&quot;&quot;, &quot;,&quot;);
bsh % System.out.println(tk.hasMoreTokens());
false
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;maybe the condition just needs the additional !str.trim().equals(&quot;&quot;)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719832" author="hadoopqa" created="Mon, 15 Jun 2009 22:44:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;-1 overall.  Here are the results of testing the latest attachment &lt;br/&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12410578/HADOOP-2366.patch&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;http://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12410578/HADOOP-2366.patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  against trunk revision 784663.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 @author.  The patch does not contain any @author tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 tests included.  The patch appears to include 3 new or modified tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 javadoc.  The javadoc tool did not generate any warning messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 javac.  The applied patch does not increase the total number of javac compiler warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 findbugs.  The patch does not introduce any new Findbugs warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 Eclipse classpath. The patch retains Eclipse classpath integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    +1 release audit.  The applied patch does not increase the total number of release audit warnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    -1 core tests.  The patch failed core unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    -1 contrib tests.  The patch failed contrib unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test results: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/testReport/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/testReport/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Findbugs warnings: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/artifact/trunk/build/test/findbugs/newPatchFindbugsWarnings.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/artifact/trunk/build/test/findbugs/newPatchFindbugsWarnings.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Checkstyle results: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/artifact/trunk/build/test/checkstyle-errors.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/artifact/trunk/build/test/checkstyle-errors.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Console output: &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/console&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Patch-vesta.apache.org/499/console&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This message is automatically generated.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719866" author="tlipcon" created="Tue, 16 Jun 2009 00:10:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Lots of test failures on this one. Michele: can you look into these failures please? Thanks&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719909" author="pirroh" created="Tue, 16 Jun 2009 03:43:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch modified to make getStrings() behave as before with whitespace-only strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todd: thanks a lot for the feedback, I&apos;m running an &apos;ant test&apos; in a local server to see if tests are failing again. Feel free to move back the issue to &quot;In Progress&quot; status - I&apos;ll let you know as soon as the build ends. &lt;br/&gt;
Sorry for the naiveness, I didn&apos;t know that Hudson was triggered by the &quot;Patch Available&quot; status... skipped an important section in the wiki page, shame on me!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12719935" author="szetszwo" created="Tue, 16 Jun 2009 05:40:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Michele, StringUtils contain common utility codes, which are not only used in HDFS but also other parts of Hadoop.  Therefore, changing the behavior of methods like getStringCollection(..) is very likely to break other existing codes.  That&apos;s why there were so many tests failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this issue, I think we should only trim the values of dfs.data.dir, but not all conf values.  See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HADOOP-4212&quot; title=&quot;New lines and leading spaces are not trimmed of a value when configuration is read&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HADOOP-4212&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HADOOP-4212&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for working on this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12720243" author="tlipcon" created="Tue, 16 Jun 2009 17:08:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Tsz Wo: In reviewing this patch, I grepped for other usages of StringUtils.getStrings and getStringCollection. It appears to me that the only user other than Configuration is StreamJob for handling some command line flags (where the whitespace trimming also makes good sense). Inside Configuration, it&apos;s used for getClasses as well as various file-path related things. Looking at uses of conf.getStrings I also can&apos;t find any that look like they would cause an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If tests pass after fixing the behavior on an empty conf, do you have an issue with changing the semantics of these utility functions so long as the new behavior is clearly documented in the javadoc?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12720335" author="szetszwo" created="Tue, 16 Jun 2009 20:33:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; If tests pass after fixing the behavior on an empty conf, do you have an issue with changing the semantics of these utility functions so long as the new behavior is clearly documented in the javadoc?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuration is a public class and is not a part of fs or hdfs.  Trimming the string values may make sense in fs/hdfs paths but it may not for the other usages.  Personally, I wish the trimming was done in the beginning.  Unfortunately, it was not.  If we change it now, then it breaks existing semantics.  I think that users rarely use leading or tailing spaces in configuration values but we cannot break them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/HADOOP-2461&quot; title=&quot;Configuration should trim property names and accept decimal, hexadecimal, and octal numbers&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;HADOOP-2461&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;HADOOP-2461&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I think that the property names should be trimmed but not the values. Otherwise, it forbids the potential use of leading and trailing spaces. If there is a need, the codes using the conf values should do the trimming.  In this issue, only the values for dfs.data.dir should be trimmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a trimmed version of getStrings(..) is needed, I think it is better to provide new methods, say getTrimmedStrings(..) in Configuration and StringUtils but not changing the existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12720438" author="pirroh" created="Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:25:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I attached a separate patch which exposes a getTrimmedStrings() method and modifies only the behavior of the Datanode.&lt;br/&gt;
When the property value is empty, the behavior of getTrimmedStrings is by purpose different from getStrings(). I&apos;d rather pass an empty array which is handled correctly by Datanode.instance(), than a null which causes NPE. &lt;br/&gt;
Just let me know if you want me to fix this behavior and make it consistent with the other methods, mine was just a proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todd: I run a whole ant clean test cycle with the other patch, and it fails anyway. I gave a shallow look with greps on getStrings() when I was attaching the first version, and I had your same impression. Actually, after that fix you suggested, I was expecting the tests to run smoothly, but probably there&apos;s something missing still. I&apos;ll leave the patch attached, in case it could be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tsz Wo: thanks for the hints. run-test-core was successful, hope will be the same with the Hudson build.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12720444" author="rangadi" created="Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:46:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;New interface sounds better. NameNode also reads a list of directories. Could you check if this fix is required there as well?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12720962" author="pirroh" created="Wed, 17 Jun 2009 22:45:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As suggested by Raghu, patch now modifies also NameNode behavior.  &lt;br/&gt;
NN was using directly getStringCollection(), so I just added a new getTrimmedStringCollection().&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12721314" author="tlipcon" created="Thu, 18 Jun 2009 15:37:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Can someone with the correct privileges make Michele a contributor and reassign this issue?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12724496" author="pirroh" created="Fri, 26 Jun 2009 12:10:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Is there something I should do to trigger again the Hudson build with the new patch?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12724644" author="szetszwo" created="Fri, 26 Jun 2009 18:19:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;After the project split, this problem needs two separated patches, one for Common and the other one for HDFS.  I think we should change Configuration and StringUtils in this issue and create a new HDFS issue for the rest.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12725405" author="pirroh" created="Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:25:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Same logic as the previous patch, without the HDFS part.&lt;br/&gt;
I&apos;ll create a new issue in the HDFS project linked to this one.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12725420" author="szetszwo" created="Tue, 30 Jun 2009 01:26:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Michele, could you run &quot;ant test-patch&quot; and &quot;ant test&quot; over your patch, and then post the results?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12725591" author="pirroh" created="Tue, 30 Jun 2009 12:19:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Tsz Wo: build successful for &quot;ant test&quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt; 
-1 overall.  
+1 @author.  The patch does not contain any @author tags.
+1 tests included.  The patch appears to include 3 &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; or modified tests.
+1 javadoc.  The javadoc tool did not generate any warning messages.
 -1 javac.  The applied patch generated 64 javac compiler warnings (more than the trunk&apos;s current 124 warnings).
+1 findbugs.  The patch does not introduce any &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Findbugs warnings.
+1 release audit.  The applied patch does not increase the total number of release audit warnings.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;for &quot;ant test-patch&quot;. No idea about the warnings, probably I messed up something in forrest/findbugs?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12725822" author="szetszwo" created="Tue, 30 Jun 2009 21:46:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I have committed this.  Thanks, Michele!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12726013" author="hudson" created="Wed, 1 Jul 2009 11:10:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Integrated in Hadoop-Common-trunk #13 (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Common-trunk/13/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://hudson.zones.apache.org/hudson/job/Hadoop-Common-trunk/13/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
    . Support trimmed strings in Configuration.  Contributed by Michele Catasta&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310010">
                    <name>Incorporates</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is part of">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12398420">HADOOP-3582</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12404703">HADOOP-4212</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12455096">MAPREDUCE-1441</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10001">
                    <name>dependent</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is depended upon by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12429140">HDFS-455</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12412109" name="HADOOP-2366.patch" size="5740" author="pirroh" created="Tue, 30 Jun 2009 00:25:42 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>1.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>37324</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310191" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multicheckboxes">
                        <customfieldname>Hadoop Flags</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="10343"><![CDATA[Reviewed]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            16 years, 21 weeks, 6 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i02sxr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>14289</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>