<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 08:33:29 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[THRIFT-5314] Enum forward compatibility</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-5314</link>
                <project id="12310800" key="THRIFT">Thrift</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems that enums in the Rust implem are not forward compatible. As Thrift enums are mapped 1:1 to Rust enum, if a newer Thrift definition adds a case to an enum, an error will be returned when parsing the message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this intended? Is there a workaround?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(We met this problem in the Rust parquet implem: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/ARROW-10553&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/ARROW-10553&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13341010">THRIFT-5314</key>
            <summary>Enum forward compatibility</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="allengeorge">Allen George</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="rdettai">R&#233;mi Dettai</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 09:11:24 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 12:31:21 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 1 Mar 2021 19:48:28 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>0.13.0</version>
                    <version>0.14.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>0.15.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Rust - Compiler</component>
                    <component>Rust - Library</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>5</watches>
                                                    <progress percentage="100">
                                    <originalProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#89afd7"/>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="transparent"/>
                                            </originalProgress>
                                                    <currentProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#51a825"/>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#ec8e00"/>
                                            </currentProgress>
                            </progress>
                                    <aggregateprogress percentage="100">
                                    <originalProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#89afd7"/>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="transparent"/>
                                            </originalProgress>
                                                    <currentProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#51a825"/>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#ec8e00"/>
                                            </currentProgress>
                            </aggregateprogress>
                                            <timeestimate seconds="0">0h</timeestimate>
                            <timespent seconds="1800">0.5h</timespent>
                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17233868" author="jensg" created="Tue, 17 Nov 2020 19:17:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; Is this intended?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thrift APIs are allowing for soft-versioning, so aside from a few constraints basically anything can change in an IDL file. Especially adding more enum values is not really something unusual, so the Rust implementation should be enaboed to handle such a case of it curretly does not work.. &lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="17235158" author="allengeorge" created="Thu, 19 Nov 2020 03:53:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;What should the right behavior be? If the receiver gets a new enum value that exists in the sender...what should the receiving code generate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Note that I&apos;m agreeing there&apos;s a problem. I&apos;m not sure what the &apos;correct&apos; behavior looks like on the receiver&apos;s side. For example, does every generated enum have a hidden &quot;__unknown&quot; variant that encodes the unrecognized enum value?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17235525" author="rdettai" created="Thu, 19 Nov 2020 14:48:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I love Rusd enums so much! Sadly I am not sure that they are the way to go here... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve have been investigating how the problem was solved in other similar usecases. After some debates &lt;b&gt;flatbuffer&lt;/b&gt; decided to replace the generated Rust enum with a C style representation that its closer to its internal representation ( &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/flatbuffers/pull/6098&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/google/flatbuffers/pull/6098&lt;/a&gt; ):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;struct MyEnum(u16);
impl MyEnum {
  &lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;// Variants are expressed as associated constants.
&lt;/span&gt;  pub &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; Variant1: MyEnum = MyEnum(1);
  pub &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; Variant2: MyEnum = MyEnum(2);
}}}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can then match like this, which is still pretty neat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;
match my_enum {
  MyEnum::Variant1 =&amp;gt; ...,
  MyEnum::Variant2 =&amp;gt; ...,
  MyEnum(x) =&amp;gt; ...,
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As enums are pretty similar in thrift and flatbuffer (C-style), I think the same behavior should be mimicked.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17235560" author="allengeorge" created="Thu, 19 Nov 2020 16:01:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think that&apos;s necessary. You could have the same outcome by using something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;pub enum RustEnum {
  Add = 1,
  Subtract = 2,
  Multiply = 3,
  Divide = 4,
  __Unknown(i32),
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, all we need is the ability to parse an unknown enum value on the wire into a variant that can be processed by the receiving code. If &lt;tt&gt;__Unknown&lt;/tt&gt; is generated automatically the reading code can always populate it with the unrecognized value on the wire.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17235585" author="rdettai" created="Thu, 19 Nov 2020 16:53:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I must admit that I don&apos;t understand why Flatbuffer ended up with that design, I just assumed that if they converged to it after such a long and passionate debate, there must be a reason &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/biggrin.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a users perspective, I think I prefer your option.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242300" author="wiredwolf" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 12:14:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jensg&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jensg&quot;&gt;jensg&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=allengeorge&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;allengeorge&quot;&gt;allengeorge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Parquet file that started this thread (in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/ARROW-10553&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/ARROW-10553&lt;/a&gt;&#160;issue) came from a project I&apos;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You refer to Thrift&apos; &quot;soft versioning&quot; but I don&apos;t see how this relates to the laxed treatment of invalid enum values in the cpp vs rust implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;soft versioning, IIUC, relates to the fact that Thrift IDLs don&apos;t adhere to any strict versioning schema like semantic versioning for example, so no handshaking on version numbers is performed, and maintaining backward compatibility is more of a common sense and accepted behavior, than a formal contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thrift however is used to clearly define a wire protocol, as such one of the invariants I&apos;d expect Thrift to uphold is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A binary stream created with a Thrift encoder, from an object which complies with the IDL, also complies with the IDL definition&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;an object &lt;em&gt;successfully&lt;/em&gt;&#160;decoded by Thrift from a binary stream results in an object that complies with the IDL definition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;WRT to enums, allowing any value as an enum (even if it doesn&apos;t correspond to a defined value in the Thrift spec) violates this invariant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example in the Parquet file in the related issue demonstrates this, a value is provided for the ConvertedType enum outside of the enum space, it&apos;s an invalid value that has no semantics within Parquet. Accepting it (by e.g. the cpp implementation) will most likely break something down the line of whatever ETL + OLAP pipeline this Parquet goes through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing early (like the Rust implementation does) seems like the right thing to do to catch such invalid values in the stream, this is what I&apos;m expecting a wire protocol to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the author of an IDL wants to allow a more laxed semantics for a value (say ConvertedType in Parquet) they can use an i32 field, and defer any semantic interpretation of the value to the application layer that reads this value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using an enum is a clear statement that a value has well defined semantics and should be restricted to a pre-defined set of values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would appreciate your take on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242620" author="jensg" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 18:55:20 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You refer to Thrift&apos; &quot;soft versioning&quot; but I don&apos;t see how this relates to the laxed treatment of invalid enum values in the cpp vs rust implementation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you replace &quot;invalid&quot; by &quot;possibly defined in the future&quot; it makes a lot more sense, does it? &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I refer to soft versioning? Well, Thrift generally has very few limits about what you can do to evolve your API contract represented as IDL files. You may add new fields, service methods, method arguments, exceptions, data types and of course also define additional services - all of this &lt;b&gt;without breaking the contract&lt;/b&gt;. You can even deprecate fields etc. (with the only exception being &quot;required&quot; fields - they technically have a great potential to introduce breaking changes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this in mind, why of all things and in whose interest woukd it be to place a restriction on enums of the kind &quot;thou may not add more, or remove existing values from a given enum in the future&quot;? Hence, the implementation absolutely should be able to deal with unknown enum values, because some counterpart will send you such a value some day.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242628" author="jensg" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 19:02:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Note that whether or not the logic of a particular piece of code which uses Thrift is willing to accept an enum outside of the range known at compile time is an entirely&#160;different question. It may be that way in with one use case but may not with some other. That&apos;s nothing Thrift can or should decide.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242671" author="wiredwolf" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 19:41:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jensg&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jensg&quot;&gt;jensg&lt;/a&gt;&#160;thanks for your comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wholly deprecating an &apos;optional&apos; field makes perfect sense, as it was never guaranteed to be included in a stream and its&apos; presence can be inferred from the stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding an enum value&#160;&lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; updating the stubs on both sides of the call makes less sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How should an implementation decide whether an unrecognized enum value is a value from a newer version of the IDL vs. just a corrupt data stream?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the logic of&#160;&#160;&quot;possibly defined in the future&quot;, why then not just use an i32 field, since any i32 will be&#160;&#160;&quot;possibly defined in the future&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The (semantic) point of an enum is to specify a subset of well defined (semantically) values for a field, otherwise, why provide a set at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I get an IP datagram where the &apos;Protocol&apos; field in the header has some unrecognized value (in that case the &quot;enum&quot; would be the relevant Protocol values in the &quot;Assigned Numbers&quot; RFC) I don&apos;t expect my IP stack to silently accept it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242708" author="fishywang" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 20:43:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=WiredWolf&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;WiredWolf&quot;&gt;WiredWolf&lt;/a&gt; so enums can be considered as &quot;documented i32 constants&quot; in some way. on the wire they are the same as i32s, but they also come with values documented, so you don&apos;t have to use magic numbers in your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a server removed an enum value the client is still using, the server should either return an error indicate that the client passed in an unsupported enum value, or silently ignore it if the enum value is truly optional. This is the same as any optional fields being absent: a lot of practical usage of thrift/protobuf are that they define every field as optional so removing them in the future is not a breaking change, but some of those fields are actually required (at the time being) and if it&apos;s absent server will just return an error to the client.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242731" author="rdettai" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 21:19:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t really have a point of view on what the invariants of a wire protocol should or shouldn&apos;t be, but my intuition tells me that consistence between implementations is very important. If the C++ and Java implementations (that are used in production for yeeeeaaaaars) work in a given way, I think it makes sense to align newer implementations with them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should a vote be started on the way to go on this?  &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17242743" author="fishywang" created="Wed, 2 Dec 2020 21:29:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m in favor to make it consistent (making rust&apos;s enum forward compatible), FWIW. But I don&apos;t have the expertise on rust.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17288781" author="allengeorge" created="Tue, 23 Feb 2021 01:56:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve taken a crack at this here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/thrift/pull/2337&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/thrift/pull/2337&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking at the alternatives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the one I proposed: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-5314?focusedCommentId=17235560&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:comment-tabpanel#comment-17235560&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-5314?focusedCommentId=17235560&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:comment-tabpanel#comment-17235560&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;the flatbuffer implementation: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/flatbuffers/pull/6098/files&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/google/flatbuffers/pull/6098/files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I decided that comments from others were correct: the flatbuffer one was cleaner, avoided the use of a magic &lt;tt&gt;__Unknown&lt;/tt&gt; and still allowed us to use basic matching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core, we now implement enums using the newtype idiom:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;pub enum Foo {
  VariantOne = 1,
  VariantTwo = 2.
   ...
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;pub struct Foo(pub i32);
impl Foo {
  pub const VARIANT_ONE: Foo = 1;
  pub const VARIANT_TWO: Foo = 2;
  pub const ENUM_VALUES: &amp;amp;&apos;static [Self] = &amp;amp;[Self::VARIANT_1, Self::VARIANT_2];
  ...
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve also implemented &lt;tt&gt;std::convert::From&lt;/tt&gt; for some types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that to conform to the Rust style guide enum variants are now in uppercase as opposed to camelcase. Whenever possible I prefer to use Rust&apos;s default conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cc &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=rdettai&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;rdettai&quot;&gt;rdettai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17293139" author="allengeorge" created="Mon, 1 Mar 2021 19:48:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Done in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/thrift/pull/2337&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/thrift/pull/2337&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13045228">THRIFT-4101</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310051">
                    <name>Supercedes</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is superceded by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13370325">THRIFT-5392</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            4 years, 37 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z0knnc:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>