<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 07:59:37 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[THRIFT-638] BufferedTransport + C extensions block until recv timeout is reached on last fread call</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-638</link>
                <project id="12310800" key="THRIFT">Thrift</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to throw this out if any other folks experience this later on. At Digg we&apos;ve been using the BufferedTransport + C extension of Thrift in PHP. Every so often, we will see spikes in latency increases on RPC calls that we know have acceptable response times (&amp;lt;200ms). This seems to happen based on how much data is being sent back over the wire. This is more of a PHP problem, but can be corrected in Thrift&apos;s PHP library for folks who don&apos;t want to upgrade PHP. I am still waiting to see if it&apos;s corrected in later versions (we use 5.2.9).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bonsai.php.net/bug.php?id=42720&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://bonsai.php.net/bug.php?id=42720&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replacing the fread statements in TSocket.php with stream_socket_recvfrom correct this behavior so that calls do not wait until they hit the recv timeout.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12441880">THRIFT-638</key>
            <summary>BufferedTransport + C extensions block until recv timeout is reached on last fread call</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="nicktelford">Nicholas Telford</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="lenn0x">Chris Goffinet</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Sun, 29 Nov 2009 07:08:08 +0000</created>
                <updated>Wed, 7 Jan 2015 23:01:57 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 4 Mar 2011 01:26:39 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>0.2</version>
                                    <fixVersion>0.7</fixVersion>
                                    <component>PHP - Library</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>2</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12797755" author="lenn0x" created="Thu, 7 Jan 2010 19:27:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;stream_socket_recvfrom does not respect timeouts from stream_set_timeout. Investigating more.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12797764" author="dreiss" created="Thu, 7 Jan 2010 19:35:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Chris and some people at Facebook have independently discovered that this version does not respect timeouts, which is obviously not acceptable.  We&apos;re discussing possible solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12881834" author="arya" created="Wed, 23 Jun 2010 19:13:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;At Gaia, we discovered this happens only when the streams don&apos;t contain exact multiples of buffer size, thus there could be cases where the length passed to read() would be larger than the actual data remained to be read from the stream. fread() would block till timeout when the length passed is larger than the actual bytes_left in the stream. So, we are submitting this patch for review. I&apos;ve tested this to work with our interface. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12898008" author="dreiss" created="Thu, 12 Aug 2010 23:50:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hey Chris.  Does this version of the patch seem reasonable to you?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12898011" author="bryanduxbury" created="Thu, 12 Aug 2010 23:58:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Not going to make this release.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12898013" author="lenn0x" created="Fri, 13 Aug 2010 00:00:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Reasonable yes, I can test it this weekend. Hopefully it can make the next release.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12903607" author="ryanobjc" created="Fri, 27 Aug 2010 20:39:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;At SU we found that if the TBufferedStream block size != 8192 (hard coded in C) we see the timeout read thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glad to know we are not alone.  I haven&apos;t looked at it enough to figure it out yet.  Looks like Chris is on to something here?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12934852" author="jbellis" created="Tue, 23 Nov 2010 15:10:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This appears to only affect unframed transport, fwiw.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001003" author="nicktelford" created="Tue, 1 Mar 2011 18:23:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This problem is linked to the timeout issues discussed in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-347&quot; title=&quot;PHP TSocket Timeout Issues&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-347&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-347&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and in fact has been exacerbated by the &quot;fixes&quot; applied for those tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-347&quot; title=&quot;PHP TSocket Timeout Issues&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-347&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-347&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was addressed by detecting timeouts with the following expression:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; === $md[&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&apos;timed_out&apos;&lt;/span&gt;] &amp;amp;&amp;amp; &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt; === $md[&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&apos;blocked&apos;&lt;/span&gt;])
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue here is that $md&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;&amp;#39;blocked&amp;#39;&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; denotes whether a stream is a blocking (true) or non-blocking (false) stream; since all TSocket streams are blocking (they never change the default, nor should they) this &lt;b&gt;always&lt;/b&gt; evaluates to false: The result is, &lt;em&gt;TException is never thrown even for legitimate timeouts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn&apos;t cause the problem itself, but it handily hides it away by making read() block excessively when there&apos;s not enough data to fill the fread() buffer instead of erroneously throwing a TException as it did before. It&apos;s also the reason the stream_socket family of functions are reportedly ignoring timeouts. They don&apos;t, TSocket is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris correctly points out that this issue is resolved by replacing fread() calls with stream_socket_recv() calls, however, it&apos;s not a bug in PHP (the bug report linked is invalid). fread() is buffered by design - from the php.net docs: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reading stops as soon as one of the following conditions is met: length bytes have been read, EOF (end of file) is reached or a packet becomes available or the socket timeout occurs (for network streams)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My understanding of TSocket is that it&apos;s meant as a raw socket abstraction and that any desired buffering should be done in a wrapping TTransport (e.g. TBufferedTransport or TFramedTransport), if that&apos;s the case then we should use stream_socket_recv() for all socket reading &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; stream_socket_sendto() for all socket writing.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001005" author="nicktelford" created="Tue, 1 Mar 2011 18:26:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch with the following changes to PHP&apos;s TSocket:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All reads now done with the unbuffered stream_socket_recv()&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All writes now done with the unbuffered stream_socket_sendto()&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reverted patch to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-347&quot; title=&quot;PHP TSocket Timeout Issues&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-347&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-347&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that broken reporting of timeouts.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Changes TSocket::flush() to be a no-op as PHP is no longer buffering data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13001071" author="bryanduxbury" created="Tue, 1 Mar 2011 19:55:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It certainly sounds like you&apos;ve got a handle on the issue. I&apos;m willing to commit this patch, if no one else has objections.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001124" author="thobbs" created="Tue, 1 Mar 2011 21:32:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think the patch has a typo where $got is used instead of $res in write().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With only that change to the patch, I&apos;m seeing problems when using TFramedTransport with the C extension.  With Arya&apos;s patch applied from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-867&quot; title=&quot;PHP accelerator module&amp;#39;s output transport is incompatible with TFramedTransport&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-867&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-867&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I get indefinite hanging.  Without it, I get &apos;TSocket: Could not read 4 bytes&apos;.  I&apos;ll try to dig in a little further, but I think the patch is still problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(It&apos;s entirely possible that using $res where $got is used is what breaks this.)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001190" author="nicktelford" created="Tue, 1 Mar 2011 23:48:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You&apos;re right, my bad - there was some churn while I was writing the patch, forgot to change the variable names. s/$got/$res/g&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&apos;s still not stable we should continue to work on it until it is. I was unable to test it against the thrift PHP test-suite for various reasons, but I will try to get a complete set of tests working tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is of primary concern to me at the moment so I&apos;m going to spend some time re-producing the issues Tyler has identified and work on a solution that&apos;s stable for everyone. I&apos;ll re-roll the patch once I have something I think will be acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001371" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 11:04:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Take two of the patch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Fixes typo on a variable name (thanks Tyler!)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;readAll($len) now blocks until the requested bytes have all been read. I&apos;ve inferred this behaviour from the code that calls it, so if I&apos;m mistaken, let me know.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Improved comments on TSocket::read() and TSocket::readAll() to be more explicit about the blocking behaviour of each.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At first glance, it may seem as though readAll() will tie up CPU in an infinite loop if there&apos;s no data available to read on the socket (since stream_socket_recv() is &quot;unbuffered&quot;) - however, the underlying recv() syscall blocks until &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; data arrives on the socket, making this not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve tested this best I can against the PHP test suite, but the test suite seems to be a bit of a mystery, so if anyone has any pointers on using it I&apos;d love to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001374" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 11:14:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Another quick note: because readAll() loops until all the data has been read and socket timeouts are the idle time for a socket, the loop will execute for at most ($len * $recvTimeout) seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want a timeout for the entire data chunk (i.e. for execution of the entire readAll() call) we will need to add some manual timing to readAll(). This doesn&apos;t just apply to TSocket, but any TTransport that has the same while (...) &lt;/p&gt;
{ $this-&amp;gt;read(); }
&lt;p&gt; behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001408" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 13:06:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Some digging revealed that stream_socket_recv() and stream_socket_sendto() do not respect timeouts, as Chris mentioned earlier. From &lt;a href=&quot;http://php.net/stream_set_timeout:&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://php.net/stream_set_timeout:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This function doesn&apos;t work with advanced operations like stream_socket_recvfrom(), use stream_select() with timeout parameter instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attached patch is a fairly major refactoring of TSocket to use stream_select() for timeout detection. From what I can tell it works fine, although there may be issues with TFramedTransport. I have yet to figure out an effective way to test changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should also be a little more robust for writing large chunks of data as write() will now block until all the data has been sent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would seriously appreciate any testing people contribute.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001515" author="bryanduxbury" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 18:18:09 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have yet to figure out an effective way to test changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about you make a server implementation that intentionally waits longer than the clientside timeout?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001522" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 18:28:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;My major concern is that I can&apos;t find an effective way to run the existing test suite (for PHP at least). Specifically, in order to run the ThriftTest client tests, I need to run a ThriftTest server, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it&apos;s worth, I&apos;ve managed to test this patch with both TBufferedTransport and TFramedTransport (with the patch in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-867&quot; title=&quot;PHP accelerator module&amp;#39;s output transport is incompatible with TFramedTransport&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-867&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-867&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) with my own set of homebrew scripts. I&apos;m pretty confident about it, but I&apos;d feel better with a complete test suite. That&apos;s something I may work on tomorrow if I get the chance.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001527" author="bryanduxbury" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 18:32:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You can use the ThriftTest server from another language, like java.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001537" author="thobbs" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 18:44:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The the 003 version of the patch, I&apos;m seeing better behavior, but still occasional problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With or without the C extension, using TFramedTransport, I get &apos;TSocket: timed out reading 4 bytes&apos; about 25% of the time when running this test (requires Cassandra):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/thobbs/phpcassa/blob/master/test/test_large_ops.php&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/thobbs/phpcassa/blob/master/test/test_large_ops.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The patched version of this does run quite a bit faster, so that&apos;s a nice bonus.  Thanks for the hard work, Nicholas!  Hopefully we can get to the bottom of this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001547" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 19:00:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Tyler, I did test with the TFramedTransport, although it&apos;s possible I missed something. A few questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Is this with the patch(es) from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-867&quot; title=&quot;PHP accelerator module&amp;#39;s output transport is incompatible with TFramedTransport&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-867&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-867&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; applied?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;What timeout are you using? Is it possible that the Cassandra node is taking a long time to complete the operation or failing altogether?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Assuming your answers still indicate a problem, I&apos;ll work to reproduce this tomorrow. If you have any other information that will help me reproduce it, that&apos;d be great &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FWIW, the &quot;quite a bit faster&quot; is actually the expected behaviour of Thrift. The bug was causing incredibly poor performance.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001568" author="thobbs" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 19:31:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Without the patch from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-867&quot; title=&quot;PHP accelerator module&amp;#39;s output transport is incompatible with TFramedTransport&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-867&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-867&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I still see &apos;TSocket: Could not read 4 bytes&apos; immediately.  (Note that I also ran tests without the C extension at all and experienced the occasional &apos;Could not read 4 bytes&apos; behavior.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not using a timeout, but I tested again setting send and recv timeouts to 10000 (ten seconds), and behavior was the same.  Cassandra isn&apos;t logging any failure messages, and the test should be well below what Cassandra can handle easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not sure I could give you any more specifics to help reproduce other than setting up an environment for you.  Would an EC2 instance that&apos;s ready to go with phpcassa be useful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m glad PHP performance might finally be up to par!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13001978" author="nicktelford" created="Thu, 3 Mar 2011 12:45:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Tyler,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been working to reproduce the issues you&apos;re seeing using phpcassa and cassandra. I noticed that phpcassa sets the default timeouts (send and recv) to 1 millisecond. I imagine this was meant to be in seconds as 1 millisecond seems rather optimistic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my tests I set my timeouts to 10 seconds (the VM I&apos;m testing on was swapping badly so Cassandra needed some time to GC a lot) and could not reproduce those problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did notice that your tests take a very long time and a ton of CPU to run, strace reveals that gettimeofday() is being called nearly constantly (approximately every 200 microseconds). I don&apos;t think this is related so I haven&apos;t gone in to too much detail looking for the culprit there, but I&apos;m pretty certain it&apos;s not Thrift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it&apos;s not too much trouble an EC2 instance would help a great deal in tracking this down.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13002319" author="thobbs" created="Thu, 3 Mar 2011 23:30:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Nicholas,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&apos;re correct &amp;#8211; it was discovered yesterday that the master branch of phpcassa was setting a default timeout of 1 millisecond.  After correcting this, I&apos;m no longer able to reproduce the problem.  I think you&apos;ve solved the issue!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your hard work, and sorry about any extra time I made you spend looking through this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13002351" author="nicktelford" created="Fri, 4 Mar 2011 00:27:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Excellent! No worries Tyler, it forced me to test my changed more aggressively &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; it&apos;s additional testing spent on phpcassa. Neither of which can be a bad thing!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13002371" author="bryanduxbury" created="Fri, 4 Mar 2011 00:46:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So are we ready for a commit guys?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13002373" author="thobbs" created="Fri, 4 Mar 2011 00:49:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, I think so.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13002386" author="nicktelford" created="Fri, 4 Mar 2011 01:22:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Unless anyone has any objections, I&apos;d say so.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13002387" author="bryanduxbury" created="Fri, 4 Mar 2011 01:26:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I just committed this. Thanks for the patch, Nicholas!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10032">
                    <name>Blocker</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="blocks">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12465280">THRIFT-788</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310051">
                    <name>Supercedes</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="supercedes">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12415421">THRIFT-347</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12426356" name="0001-Replace-freads-with-stream_socket_recvfrom.patch" size="1254" author="lenn0x" created="Sun, 29 Nov 2009 07:13:24 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12447870" name="0002-tocket-read-meta-data-check.diff" size="734" author="arya" created="Wed, 23 Jun 2010 19:13:19 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12472414" name="thrift-tsocket-638-0002.patch" size="4217" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 11:04:02 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12472424" name="thrift-tsocket-638-0003.patch" size="8170" author="nicktelford" created="Wed, 2 Mar 2011 13:06:26 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12472341" name="thrift-tsocket-638.patch" size="3537" author="nicktelford" created="Tue, 1 Mar 2011 18:26:11 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>5.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>87724</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            14 years, 38 weeks, 5 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i16d7z:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>245274</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>