<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 17:25:33 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CODEC-199] Bug in HW rule in Soundex</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CODEC-199</link>
                <project id="12310464" key="CODEC">Commons Codec</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;The Soundex algorithm says that if two characters that map to the same code are separated by H or W, the second one is not encoded.&lt;br/&gt;
However, in the implementation (in Soundex.getMappingCode() line 191), a character that is preceded by two characters that are either H or W, is not encoded, regardless of what the last consonant was.&lt;br/&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soundex#American_Soundex&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soundex#American_Soundex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12783203">CODEC-199</key>
            <summary>Bug in HW rule in Soundex</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="-1">Unassigned</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="yossi">Yossi Tamari</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 11:55:40 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:59:05 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:59:05 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.10</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.11</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>2</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14370277" author="garydgregory" created="Thu, 19 Mar 2015 22:51:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patches with unit tests are welcome &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14374907" author="yossi" created="Sun, 22 Mar 2015 12:44:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch for the problematic method and adding a unit test attached.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14375108" author="garydgregory" created="Sun, 22 Mar 2015 18:54:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fix is in trunk. Thank you. Please verify and close.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14379700" author="yossi" created="Wed, 25 Mar 2015 11:10:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In the first patch I submitted I tried to localize the changes to reduce risk. Having thought about it since, I have a better patch which I think is more efficient (less map lookups), more correct (the HW rule is specific to the US English mapping, but it was implemented in the main code, I fixed this by defining a new mapping character of &apos;#&apos; that marks a silent letter, and mapping H and W to it), and I think results in simpler code.&lt;br/&gt;
Patch attached as better.patch.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14381326" author="garydgregory" created="Thu, 26 Mar 2015 04:11:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thank you Yossi. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patch applied and pushed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://repository.apache.org/content/repositories/snapshots/commons-codec/commons-codec/1.11-SNAPSHOT/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://repository.apache.org/content/repositories/snapshots/commons-codec/commons-codec/1.11-SNAPSHOT/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please verify and fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14381504" author="yossi" created="Thu, 26 Mar 2015 07:27:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15948955" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 12:20:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately the fix breaks binary compatibility.&lt;br/&gt;
It changes a public string constant.&lt;br/&gt;
That can cause problems because the Java compiler can inline constants, so code may fail to pick up a new value.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15948975" author="yossi" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 12:37:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sebb, correct me if I&apos;m wrong, but it seems to me that in such a case, the compiled code will continue to use the old value of the constant, instead of the new one, and so it will continue to see the old behavior for H and W, but the new code is backwards compatible and will not break.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949007" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 12:54:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also code may have its own mapping string and expect the code to deal with HW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it would be better to revert to the original patch, which fixes the HW behaviour in the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes the fix less generic, but AFAICT the Soundex algorithm is specific to English language names.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949032" author="yossi" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:15:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;If a code has its own mapping, it will work, as it will have the new logic, and the constant is not used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the the fact that the second patch is more generic is just nice, the improved performance is more important I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Soundex is specific to English language names, why do we need the ability to customize the mapping? I thought the whole point was to make it customizable to other languages.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949076" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 13:37:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I just tried running the tests from version 1.10 against the current code, but using the old version of the mapping by using the following override:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;    @Override
    &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;protected&lt;/span&gt; Soundex createStringEncoder() {
        &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Soundex(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;01230120022455012623010202&quot;&lt;/span&gt;);
    }
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This causes failures in 3 tests: testHWRuleEx1/2/3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So existing code that has an old copy of the mapping string will see a change in behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: the original test class works fine if the override uses:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Soundex(Soundex.US_ENGLISH_MAPPING_STRING); &lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;// using the &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;OR
        &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; Soundex(); &lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;// the original test code&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949208" author="yossi" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 14:42:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You are right: in such a case, the HW rule will be ignored, instead of being implemented wrong, as it was in 1.10.&lt;br/&gt;
This is true regardless of the binary-incompatibility issue, as you clearly shown in your test.&lt;br/&gt;
It seems to me to be a natural side-effect of fixing bugs.&lt;br/&gt;
If you think that this is a real problem, you can add a patch in the Soundex constructors - if H and W are mapped to 0, remap them to #.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949303" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 15:53:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The problem is that the patch does not just fix the incorrect behaviour - it also breaks existing good behaviour if the original mapping is used either deliberately (or accidentally due to caching).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changing the mapping provided by a user also has side effects - it stops a user from using mapping H and W as 0.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949349" author="yossi" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 16:28:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The fact that the HW rule is forced IS a bug, in my mind, and one of the things I was trying to fix. &lt;br/&gt;
Read &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soundex&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soundex&lt;/a&gt;. While the class pretends to implement Soundex, it really implemented American Soundex. I have no problem with that, but then we should change the class name. I was under the impression that the constant (and the parameterized constructors) were there in order to be able to say that this is a generic Soundex implementation, with a default behavior of American Soundex (which is fine, since this is what most people want). But this was not the case before my second patch - the HW rule is part of American Soundex only, but there was no way to disable it, or apply it to other letters.&lt;br/&gt;
The original default was wrong, and changing it is a feature. When somebody passes &quot;01230120022455012623010202&quot; intentionally, the HW rule should be disabled. If you want to protect from the accidental case, we can change the name of the constants, so the caching will not work. If you think this change is too big for 1.11 and should only happen in 2.0, that is a fair argument, though I personally don&apos;t think so at this moment (I am not sure what the rules for behavior change on minor release are here).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949821" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 21:02:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I agree that the class should probably have been called American Soundex.&lt;br/&gt;
But it cannot be renamed without breaking compatibility, which would require a new major version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s not clear what sort of variations the class was originally designed for, so I am not convinced that the original HW behaviour is a bug.&lt;br/&gt;
Nor is it clear whether there is a use case for different letters to have the same behaviour as HW.&lt;br/&gt;
So it seems wrong to change the underlying behaviour of the class just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the first patch fixes the incorrect behaviour without any side effects, I think that is the approach that should be taken for the 1.x versions of Codec.&lt;br/&gt;
The code may not be as efficient as the second patch but there are other ways to deal with that (e.g. use the algorithm noted on the Wikipedia page).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there is a case for more flexible behaviour, that could be implemented in 2.x, once the requirements are known.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15949896" author="yossi" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 21:35:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I would just like to point out the logical fallacy in worrying about the case where someone would want to change the default mapping, but claiming that nobody will want to change the list of &quot;silent&quot; letters.&lt;br/&gt;
Here is a real-life use case which requires disabling the HW rule: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.genealogy.com/articles/research/00000060.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://www.genealogy.com/articles/research/00000060.html&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15950057" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 23:21:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Not sure what your first para refers to.&lt;br/&gt;
I am unaware of having claimed that nobody would want to change the list of silent letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As to the second para, it is useful to know that there is a use case where the treatment of HW is the not the same.&lt;br/&gt;
However AFAICT the process treats all the vowels plus HW as silent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any letters next to each other that have the same number should be treated as one. This means that you should never have two of the same numbers next to each other in a Soundex code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i.e. vowels don&apos;t get used as invisible consonant separators; they are ignored like HW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that &apos;#&apos; were used to represent silent letters, then it would be easy enough to check if the mapping contains any &apos;#&apos; chars and skip the default HW behaviour if so.&lt;br/&gt;
This would allow the silent letters to be changed; in the case above one would just map A, E, I, O, U, Y, W, H to &apos;#&apos;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s not so obvious how to handle the case where H and W are treated as vowels - if there is a use case for that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15950079" author="yossi" created="Thu, 30 Mar 2017 23:50:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;By silent I meant HW, not vowels. &lt;br/&gt;
You said &quot;Nor is it clear whether there is a use case for different letters to have the same behaviour as HW.&quot;, I was making the point that the list HW may need to change, in this instance to empty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rule that you quote is not a variant, it is step 3 in the Wikipedia definition, and is implemented. Again, in this case not all vowels need to be mapped to #, but the opposite, no letter should be mapped to #.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, this is exactly a use case for where H and W are treated as vowels, and it is easily handled by mapping them to 0. (with my second patch. Without it, you can&apos;t handle this variant using this library.)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15950496" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Fri, 31 Mar 2017 07:59:59 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;this is exactly a use case for where H and W are treated as vowels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, it&apos;s not. &lt;br/&gt;
Vowels have the code &apos;0&apos; and are used to separate consonants with the same non-zero code.&lt;br/&gt;
In this case, vowels are completely ignored, i.e. are treated like HW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try the following test:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;        Assert.assertEquals(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;L150&quot;&lt;/span&gt;, s.encode(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;Lippmann&quot;&lt;/span&gt;));
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fails with the current code (generates &quot;L155&quot;) unless you set A to behave like HW, i.e. vowels need to be set to &apos;#&apos; (silent).&lt;br/&gt;
Try it and see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3 of the Wikipedia definition says &quot;two letters with the same number separated by &apos;h&apos; or &apos;w&apos; are coded as a single number, whereas such letters separated by a vowel are coded twice&quot;.&lt;br/&gt;
However the Genealogy defintion implies that such letters are coded as a single number for HW &lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; the vowels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The output from the Wikipedia definition allows repeated digits.&lt;br/&gt;
The Genealogy definition explicitly does not. That means it does not have any Wiki-style vowels; for the Genealogy definition vowels + HW are all silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have yet to see a definiton that requires HW to be treated as a vowel rather than silent (or a consonant).&lt;br/&gt;
If you find any examples, please provide links (and test cases if possible).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15950537" author="yossi" created="Fri, 31 Mar 2017 08:39:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Examples:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thoughtco.com/soundex-explained-us-census-1421773&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://www.thoughtco.com/soundex-explained-us-census-1421773&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a period of time, especially between for the 1880, 1900 and 1910 census, Soundex coders sometimes erroneously treated H and W as separators, like the vowels, and assigned a code to both the S and C. This would make the code for ASHCRAFT A226, instead of A261. Basically, any surname with the letter H or W as a separator between adjacent letters having the same code should be coded both ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://west-penwith.org.uk/misc/soundex.htm&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://west-penwith.org.uk/misc/soundex.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15951090" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Fri, 31 Mar 2017 15:06:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The penwith URL is very useful. Thanks.&lt;br/&gt;
It states that HW were treated as vowels in the original &apos;Simplified Soundex&apos;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This difference is not described in the Wikipedia article, and regarded as erroneous in the thoughtco page.&lt;br/&gt;
The thoughtco page is unhelpful in other ways, e.g. it uses SUTTON as an example of a name starting with a double letter! &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;A name like LLOYD would be OK&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is a solution which will allow for the &apos;Simplified Soundex&apos; variant as well as the current American Soundex - without compromising existing behaviour or needing to change the public constant. I hope to update the code in the next few days once it has been tested further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;==&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s wasteful to implement features that are not going to be used, and maintenance is increased.&lt;br/&gt;
Rather more importantly, unless there are usage examples then creating valid test cases is error prone.&lt;br/&gt;
That is why I have been stressing the need for use cases.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15951828" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:55:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think it makes sense to split this issue into two parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) fixing the bug in the American Soundex algorithm implementation&lt;br/&gt;
That is the scope of this issue, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CODEC-199&quot; title=&quot;Bug in HW rule in Soundex&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CODEC-199&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CODEC-199&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) enhancing the class to provide support for other variants, i.e. Simplified Soundex and the Genealogy variant (whatever its name is).&lt;br/&gt;
That will now be dealt with under &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CODEC-233&quot; title=&quot;Soundex should support more algorithm variants&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CODEC-233&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CODEC-233&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15951832" author="sebb@apache.org" created="Fri, 31 Mar 2017 23:59:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?rev=1789764&amp;amp;view=rev&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?rev=1789764&amp;amp;view=rev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Log:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CODEC-199&quot; title=&quot;Bug in HW rule in Soundex&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CODEC-199&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CODEC-199&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Bug in HW rule in Soundex&lt;br/&gt;
Revert to a fix which does not entail change to public API&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modified:&lt;br/&gt;
    commons/proper/codec/trunk/src/changes/changes.xml&lt;br/&gt;
    commons/proper/codec/trunk/src/main/java/org/apache/commons/codec/language/Soundex.java&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13060835">CODEC-233</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12707189" name="better.patch" size="2972" author="yossi" created="Wed, 25 Mar 2015 11:10:40 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12706385" name="soundex.patch" size="1976" author="yossi" created="Sun, 22 Mar 2015 12:44:33 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            8 years, 33 weeks ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i26z2f:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>