<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 07:37:50 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SVN-1709] interrupted client doesn&apos;t stop processing network traffic</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SVN-1709</link>
                <project id="12318828" key="SVN">Subversion</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Jack Repenning witnessed this bug once when fooling with svn privately on Linux,
and so has a Collabnet customer on win32.  And now D.J. Heap has managed to
reproduce the bug on both win32 and fedora.  Apparently it&apos;s possible to hit
&quot;control-C&quot; during a checkout cause apache to spike up to 100% cpu, some sort of
infinite loop.  

I&apos;m filing this as a P1, because this is a major showstopper:  it prevents work
from being done (i.e. a client can bring down an entire server), and there&apos;s no
workaround.  We need a mod_dav_svn or apache expert to hunt this down ASAP.  A
client should *never* be able to bring down a server.

Here&apos;s DJ&apos;s report:

-------------------------------------------

I was able to recreate the problem I think -- if you cancel a checkout 
from Apache it looks to me like mod_dav_svn keeps going.

After cancelling it at the client I attached to Apache and followed the 
loops around a few times, but I couldn&apos;t see how mod_dav_svn would be 
able to tell if the socket was dead.  I&apos;m not sure if it&apos;s supposed to 
check something or if Apache tells it the client died or what.  Also, I 
get the same behavior on Linux (Fedora Core 1).

With svnserve, the client process and server thread exit almost immediately.

The mod_dav_svn stacktrace (a few seconds after the client has been 
Ctrl-C&apos;d) looked like this and just kept looping and sending the xml 
until complete:

 &amp;gt;	mod_dav_svn.so!svn_fs__parse_entries_skel
  	mod_dav_svn.so!get_dir_entries
  	mod_dav_svn.so!dir_entry_id_from_node
  	mod_dav_svn.so!svn_fs__dag_open
  	mod_dav_svn.so!open_path
  	mod_dav_svn.so!txn_body_node_id
  	mod_dav_svn.so!do_retry
  	mod_dav_svn.so!svn_fs__retry_txn
  	mod_dav_svn.so!svn_fs_node_id
  	mod_dav_svn.so!dav_svn_get_safe_cr
  	mod_dav_svn.so!send_vsn_url
  	mod_dav_svn.so!add_helper
  	mod_dav_svn.so!upd_add_file
  	mod_dav_svn.so!add_file_or_dir
  	mod_dav_svn.so!delta_dirs
  	mod_dav_svn.so!add_file_or_dir
  	mod_dav_svn.so!delta_dirs
  	mod_dav_svn.so!add_file_or_dir
  	mod_dav_svn.so!delta_dirs
  	mod_dav_svn.so!add_file_or_dir
  	mod_dav_svn.so!delta_dirs
  	mod_dav_svn.so!add_file_or_dir
  	mod_dav_svn.so!delta_dirs
  	mod_dav_svn.so!svn_repos_dir_delta
  	mod_dav_svn.so!finish_report
  	mod_dav_svn.so!svn_repos_finish_report
  	mod_dav_svn.so!dav_svn__update_report
  	mod_dav_svn.so!dav_svn_deliver_report
  	mod_dav.so!dav_method_report
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12898092">SVN-1709</key>
            <summary>interrupted client doesn&apos;t stop processing network traffic</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="-1">Unassigned</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="sussman">Ben Collins-Sussman</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Mon, 19 Jan 2004 21:58:51 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 16:40:38 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 15:22:22 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>all</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.3.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>libsvn_ra_neon</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>3</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14918780" author="subversion-importer" created="Tue, 20 Jan 2004 00:27:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;In my case, an strace of the bezerker httpd looks like this:

...
pread(24, &quot;\355\3\0\0\22\324\16\0\312\315\3\0\311\315\3\0\313\315&quot;..., 4096, 
1021091840) = 4096
pread(24, &quot;\355\3\0\0\204\344\16\0\313\315\3\0\312\315\3\0\314\315&quot;..., 4096, 
1021095936) = 4096
pread(24, &quot;\355\3\0\0\366\364\16\0\314\315\3\0\313\315\3\0\315\315&quot;..., 4096, 
1021100032) = 4096
writev(16, [{&quot;21c71\r\n&quot;, 7}, {&quot;7QAAhqAADIaffICE7SZEge5MgIGy&quot;, 28}, {&quot;Vm/
jr8lTYbW4\ndhNlzxZenfSg1UVxgfH&quot;..., 138325}, {&quot;\r\n&quot;, 2}], 4) = -1 EPIPE (Broken pipe)
--- SIGPIPE (Broken pipe) ---
pread(24, &quot;\355\3\0\0(\367\f\0\255\315\3\0\254\315\3\0\256\315\3\0&quot;..., 4096, 
1020973056) = 4096







Comments:

The pread of what looks like random garbage is probably legit: this particular repository has a 
bunch of big files whose contents came from /dev/urandom, which definitely ought to be random.

The EPIPE, and/or the SIGPIPE, ought to be a Big Hint to someone or other that this socket&apos;s 
busticated, and we ought to stop writing to it.

The info shown here suggests the question &quot;would this eventually reach the end of the file (or 
repository?), and get back to normal?&quot;  Fine question.  I&apos;m letting it run now, but these are big 
random files, and it&apos;ll be quite a while before I can be sure it &quot;ought&quot; to be done.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Original comment by &lt;b&gt;jackrepenning&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918781" author="subversion-importer" created="Tue, 20 Jan 2004 01:22:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;OK, I don&apos;t think my case is the same as the base case.  In my case, httpd eventually stops spinning 
madly, after about as long as the operation would have taken had it not been interrupted.  Also in 
my case, other SVN operations (httpd or viewcvs) continue to work.  And of course, in my case, if 
it&apos;s working normally httpd runs at something like 100%cpu anyway.  So my case summarizes as 
something like &quot;httpd doesn&apos;t stop even when the client dies.&quot;  That&apos;s rather tacky, but not a critical 
problem.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Original comment by &lt;b&gt;jackrepenning&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918782" author="subversion-importer" created="Tue, 20 Jan 2004 02:41:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;I should have been more clear -- Apache does eventually go back to normal, but
depending on the size of the checkout that can be a very long time during which
it is eating the cpu alive.

As Jack indicated, mod_dav_svn (or Apache or someone) seems not to realize that
the socket is dead and shouldn&apos;t be written to anymore -- so it just keeps
building and sending the checkout data down to the client until it&apos;s done.

And in my case, also, Apache kept going but was *very* severely affected by the
errant checkout -- perhaps it affects Windows more severely due to
process/thread settings or something?

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Original comment by &lt;b&gt;djh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918783" author="subversion-importer" created="Tue, 20 Jan 2004 03:29:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;The repro recipe I used was to just setup a repository in Apache with a sizeable
amount of data (I used three copies of Apache source and binaries) and then do a
normal checkout followed by Ctrl+C after files start coming down.

I did this both in Windows and Fedora Core 1 and observed the same behavior:

The client stops at the Ctrl+C and appears to be hung/waiting.  The server
continues building and sending the checkout data to the client consuming all
available cpu -- possibly because the actual socket i/o is no longer happening
and slowing things down.

Having just repro&apos;d this again, the Apache process doesn&apos;t appear to be as badly
hit (performance wise) as I remember -- I may have had the debugger attached
during the previous repros which would have exaggerated the performance impact.
 That is, during this run I started other client checkouts and they were
noticeably affected by the errant checkout, but not massively so.

Once the server finishes, the client prints the &apos;signal caught&apos; message and
exits...client transcript below:

D:\Temp&amp;gt;svn co http://localhost/reps/stuff stuff-wc2
A  stuff-wc2\ap1
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\proxy
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include\pcre.h
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include\apu_version.h
... [snipped 30 or so Add lines]
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include\util_cfgtree.h
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include\ap_listen.h
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include\apr_user.h
A  stuff-wc2\ap1\Apache2\include\http_main.h 
 *** I pressed Ctrl+C here
 *** and client output stopped for
 *** approximately 3 minutes while server cranked away
svn: Caught signal

D:\Temp&amp;gt;

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Original comment by &lt;b&gt;djh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918784" author="sussman" created="Tue, 20 Jan 2004 03:59:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Here&apos;s a note:  a checkout/update used to be a REPORT, followed by a response
which describes what to fetch, and then client would parse the response and do a
bunch of GET and PROPFIND requests.

The &quot;big change&quot; we made recently was to put *all* information in the REPORT
response... i.e. in-line file contents and properties.

IIRC, mod_dav_svn &quot;streams&quot; the report response as svn_repos_dir_delta()
generates the tree delta.  This streaming happens via the famous apache &quot;bucket
brigades&quot;. 

So it sounds like even when the socket dies, nothing is noticing the problem. 
mod_dav_svn keeps spewing data into the brigade, which continues to spew it to a
dead socket.  I&apos;m guessing we somehow need to add some error-checking into our
brigade somewhere.   Maybe a good apache person can comment... jerenkrantz? 
Gstein? 

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918785" author="gstein" created="Tue, 20 Jan 2004 05:26:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;The assumptions are correct: it is simply that mod_dav_svn does not detect the
closed socket, so it continues generating the report. Without the network I/O
present to throttle the CPU, it takes all it can.

An example of erroneous code is at mod_dav_svn/update.c::send_xml(). The return
value from apr_brigade_printf() is not checked.

One question that I have is why brigade_write_fn&apos;s return value doesn&apos;t seem to
be noticed: if the brigade write fails, it *does* return an error; this is also
in the spot where we write the bulk of the data. So why doesn&apos;t everything abort
there?

In the worst case, some of the apr_brigade_* writing functions might not be
returning errors properly. As a total fallback for a case like this, we can
check the connections &apos;aborted&apos; flag. But the errors from the brigade functions
should be checked first.

Also note things like the ap_fflush() call (its return value isn&apos;t checked in
update.c). Similar types of things with the ap_fputs() and ap_pass_brigade()
calls in merge.c.

(sigh)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918786" author="cmpilato" created="Wed, 21 Jan 2004 22:55:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Starting this.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918787" author="cmpilato" created="Thu, 22 Jan 2004 20:24:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Well, the bad news:

   The bucket code doesn&apos;t seem to return error codes on dead sockets.

The goods news:

    Checking (baton)-&amp;gt;output-&amp;gt;c-&amp;gt;aborted seems to do what we want it to do.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918788" author="gstein" created="Thu, 22 Jan 2004 20:37:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;The bucket code *should*, so it would be best to fix that up. Even if we can&apos;t
rely on that for now, we can put ### markers in our tests for -&amp;gt;aborted to
remove those (eventually) in favor of the bucket code return values.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918789" author="sussman" created="Fri, 23 Jan 2004 20:18:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cmpilato commited a partial fix for this in r8463... the long-lived REPORT
response code is now doing error-checking when writing to the socket.

The effect of this is that when you &apos;kill -9&apos; the client, httpd notices the dead
socket and aborts the response.  

But we still have a problem:  hitting control-c on the client apparently isn&apos;t
closing the socket.  The client just hangs, in a CLOSE_WAIT state, and httpd
continues to spew data.

So I guess this bug is only &quot;half fixed&quot; on trunk at the moment.

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918790" author="subversion-importer" created="Sat, 24 Jan 2004 02:33:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Here&apos;s more info gathered from some irc discussion and debugging and pinging Joe
Orton.  Even after cmpilato&apos;s fixes the server still spins and the client still
hangs...



On Fri, Jan 23, 2004 at 02:39:38PM -0700, D.J. Heap wrote:

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; So after some deeper debugging and irc discussion, it looks like neon is 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; not doing what we expected -- whether that&apos;s a bad assumption in 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Subversion or a bug in neon, I&apos;m not sure.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; After the user hits Ctrl+C we are returning NE_XML_ABORT from our start 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; elem handler which causes neon to set the parser as no longer valid 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; (ne_xml.c line 312).  But it still keeps reading all the data to 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; completion causing the client to &apos;hang&apos; until the server is all done 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; sending it&apos;s report which can be some minutes later.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Is there a better way to tell neon to stop and cancel the connection?


Not currently: it requires a neon API change, to allow the response body
callbacks to return an error, which is on the TODO list.

Regards,

joe

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Original comment by &lt;b&gt;djh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918791" author="kfogel" created="Sat, 24 Jan 2004 07:11:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Changing summary to reflect the remaining client-side bug.

Note that getting the server-side fix in (r8463) was much more important,
though.  When we get the ^C bug fixed on the client side, existing servers will
be ready for it.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918792" author="kfogel" created="Fri, 30 Jan 2004 16:39:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Putting in Post-1.0.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918793" author="kfogel" created="Fri, 3 Dec 2004 18:04:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;I believe r312 of http://svn.webdav.org/repos/projects/neon/ solves this
problem; r308 laid the groundwork by changing the callbacks API to allow error
returns.

Those changes aren&apos;t in the most recent Neon release (0.24.7), but assuming
0.24.8 comes from trunk, presumably they&apos;d be in the next release.

Joe, have I got this all right?
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918794" author="maxb" created="Fri, 3 Dec 2004 18:59:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Given the existance of:

http://svn.webdav.org/repos/projects/neon/branches/0.24.x/

it seems far-fetched that 0.24.8 would come from trunk.

Looks like either the changes need to be backported, or we need to move up to
0.25.x when it arrives.

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918795" author="jorton" created="Fri, 3 Dec 2004 20:05:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Yes, the API change is done for neon 0.25.0 - it can&apos;t go in 0.24.x because it&apos;s
an API change.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918796" author="kfogel" created="Fri, 3 Dec 2004 20:13:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Thanks Joe (&amp;amp; sorry, Max, I just misunderstood the Neon version numbering
system, which is odd, because it&apos;s not *so* dissimilar to our own).
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918797" author="sussman" created="Sun, 24 Apr 2005 13:10:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Neon 0.25 is released!  Can we *please* switch to the new neon API(s) in svn 1.3, and fix this bug?  It&apos;s 
as old as the hills, and quite annoying.

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918798" author="ehuelsmann" created="Mon, 25 Apr 2005 12:25:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Change summary to what the current remaining problem actually is.

Try to reassign so that the status gets reset to NEW as the remaining work in 
this issue is not being worked on, or at least isn&apos;t started.

The remaining work isn&apos;t in mod_dav_svn, but in libsvn_ra_dav, so switching 
that too.

And add myself in the CC list. But in general: yes! I too like to see this 
addressed.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918799" author="kfogel" created="Fri, 6 May 2005 04:18:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Issue #2297 filed regarding upgrading to Neon 0.25.0.  See there for progress.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918800" author="kfogel" created="Thu, 16 Jun 2005 21:25:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Issue #2297 is closed now; Subversion can operate either with Neon 0.24.7 or
0.25.0.  I&apos;ll have to look more closely at why this does not seem to have
improved our client-interrupt behavior very much.  Our log_receiver() callbacks
already check cancellation, and return error if cancellation happened, and that
error (presumably) gets propagated back up to the Neon parser, which should then
abort the parse... But that seems (?) not to be happening in practice.

Haven&apos;t debugged into it yet, though.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918801" author="jorton" created="Mon, 20 Jun 2005 10:53:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;It worked for me with &quot;svn log&quot;, with two caveats:

1) there is a neon 0.25.0 bug which means that if using a compressed response
the callback return value was not propagated to abort the response; disable the
http-compression option to check whether that&apos;s what you&apos;re seeing.  (0.25.1 is
due out with fixes for this as soon as the webdav.org server comes back online)

2) in some cases it looked like ra_dav was having to process a lot of response
data without invoking the receiver callback (I think?) so there would be a
noticeable delay before the cancellation check happened; didn&apos;t look at that
much further, but I guess that&apos;s expected behaviour.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918806" author="jorton" created="Tue, 28 Jun 2005 09:16:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attachment 1_svn_daverr2.diff has been added with description: further error handling fixes&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918802" author="jorton" created="Tue, 28 Jun 2005 09:16:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Created an attachment (id=490)
further error handling fixes

&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918803" author="jorton" created="Tue, 28 Jun 2005 09:17:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Above is the last patch I have on this; just fixes up some of the error handling.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918804" author="jorton" created="Tue, 28 Jun 2005 09:22:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;There is another caveat in that interrupted blocking system calls in neon will
be automatically restarted by neon, so e.g. if you have a slow connect() call,
it cannot be interrupted by a Ctrl-C; neon will just restart it.

This is generally correct; neon does not know whether whatever signals the
application is dealing with are fatal to the particular operation being carried
out or not, so must assume not.

That issue will AFAIK also apply to ra_svn since APR behaves the same.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14918805" author="kfogel" created="Fri, 1 Jul 2005 14:41:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Attachment 490 applied in r15211.

Resolving this issue as FIXED now.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10032">
                    <name>Blocker</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is blocked by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12898682">SVN-2297</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10001">
                    <name>dependent</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="depends upon">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12898682">SVN-2297</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12763010" name="1_svn_daverr2.diff" size="5170" author="jorton" created="Tue, 28 Jun 2005 09:16:36 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>1.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12311024" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:textfield">
                        <customfieldname>External issue ID</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>1709</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            20 years, 22 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313020" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Mailing List</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i2lurr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>