<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:33:05 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-4277] hsha default thread limits make no sense, and yaml comments look confused</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-4277</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;The cassandra.yaml states with respect to &lt;tt&gt;rpc_max_threads&lt;/tt&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;# For the Hsha server, the min and max both &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; to quadruple the number of
# CPU cores.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code seems to indeed do this. But this makes, as far as I can tell, no sense what-so-ever since the number of concurrent RPC threads you need is a function of the throughput and the average latency of requests (that includes synchronously waiting on network traffic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defaulting to anything having to do with CPU cores seems inherently wrong. If a default is non-static, a closer guess might be to look at thread stack size and heap size and infer what &quot;might&quot; be reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;NOTE&lt;/b&gt;: The effect of having this too low, is &quot;strange&quot; (if you don&apos;t know what&apos;s going on) latencies observed form the client on all thrift requests (&lt;b&gt;any&lt;/b&gt; thrift request, including e.g. &lt;tt&gt;describe_ring()&lt;/tt&gt;), that isn&apos;t visible in any latency metric exposed by Cassandra. This is why I consider this &quot;major&quot;, since unwitting users may be seeing detrimental performance for no good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I read this about async:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;# async -&amp;gt; Nonblocking server implementation with one thread to serve 
#          rpc connections.  This is not recommended &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; high throughput use
#          cases. Async has been tested to be about 50% slower than sync
#          or hsha and is deprecated: it will be removed in the next major release.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes even less sense. Running with &lt;b&gt;one&lt;/b&gt; rpc thread limits you to a single concurrent request. How was that 50% number even attained? By single-node testing being completely CPU bound locally on a node? The actual effect should be &quot;stupidly slow&quot; in any real situation with lots of requests on a cluster of many nodes and network traffic (though I didn&apos;t test that) - especially in the event of any kind of hiccup like a node doing GC. I agree that if the above is true, async should &lt;b&gt;definitely&lt;/b&gt; be deprecated, but the reasons seem &lt;b&gt;much&lt;/b&gt; stronger than implied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may be missing something here, in which case I apologize,, but I specifically double-checked after I fixed this setting on on our our clusters after seeing exactly the expected side-effect of having it be too low. I always was under the impression that rpc_max_threads affects the number of RPC requests running concurrently, and code inspection (it being used for the worker thread limit) + the effects of client-observed latency is consistent with my understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect the setting was set strangely by someone because the phrasing of the comments in &lt;tt&gt;cassandra.yaml&lt;/tt&gt; strongly suggest that this should be tied to CPU cores, hiding the fact that this really has to do with the number of requests that can be serviced concurrently regardless of implementation details of thrift/networking being sync/async/etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12557047">CASSANDRA-4277</key>
            <summary>hsha default thread limits make no sense, and yaml comments look confused</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10002" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Normal</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="scode">Peter Schuller</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="scode">Peter Schuller</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 23 May 2012 18:38:49 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:32:33 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Tue, 29 May 2012 16:27:02 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>1.2.0 beta 1</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>5</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13281791" author="scode" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 18:40:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;To be clear: I suggest changing the default to some pretty high number like 512, or possibly be a function of stack size/heap size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, &lt;b&gt;if&lt;/b&gt; my analysis is correct, the &apos;async&apos; stuff should be completely deprecated as no one should ever be using it for any real cluster unless possibly if they use Cassandra as single-node local storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also suggest changing comments to reflect the real meaning of this and what it affects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will provide a patch for the comments and changing the HSHA defaults to a fixed number, if anyone +1:s the idea.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281845" author="vijay2win@yahoo.com" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 19:55:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Peter,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when implemented the solution was intrim (till thrift fix was in a released. &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/THRIFT-1167&quot; title=&quot;Java nonblocking server with more than one thread for select and handling IO&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;THRIFT-1167&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;THRIFT-1167&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), I dont remember or have the test classes which i used to come up with the data mentioned above... &lt;br/&gt;
It is really hard to get all the real world traffic pattern to simulate... &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing which we can do have it configurable and by default (assuming that the clients behave well and keep the CPU busy) choose based on the CPU, i dont think there is a right number of threads which will make sense for the selector to be default.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281850" author="vijay2win@yahoo.com" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 19:59:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also, IMO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear: I suggest changing the default to some pretty high number like 512, or possibly be a function of stack size/heap size.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;512 is really really high and the context switch will be really high and you will not be seeing a lot of advantage with this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281889" author="brandon.williams" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 20:38:18 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;512 is really really high and the context switch will be really high and you will not be seeing a lot of advantage with this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree.  Logically the optimal amount is the number of cores, but benchmarking revealed better results with oversubscription, hence it defaulting to cores*4 now.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281951" author="scode" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 21:49:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Please re-read. What you&apos;re saying is re-iterating the same confusion that seems to be the reason for this setting to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has &lt;b&gt;nothing&lt;/b&gt; to do with CPU cores. This is about concurrent requests, that are not CPU bound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logically the optimal amount &lt;b&gt;IS NOT&lt;/b&gt; the number of cores. See my original submission.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281957" author="scode" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 21:53:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The point is, zoom out of all implementation details. Forget about context switching. Just look at requests. If you have 10 000 requests with an average latency of 15 milliseconds for example, it would take 10000*15/1000=150 seconds to execute them with a single rpc thread. With 10 threads, 15 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you&apos;re trying to push 10 000 requests per second through a node, with an average latency of 15 milliseconds, you cannot possible do so if you limit the number of concurrent requests to less than 15*10=150.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281958" author="scode" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 21:54:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This is a result of the architecture of Cassandra, which fundamentally requires a thread for an active thrift request. Fixing that would mean making the entire thrift front-end asynchronous. But without that happening, it is not correct to consider the number of CPU cores when selecting what is a reasonable limit to the number of concurrent thrift requests.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281968" author="jbellis" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 21:59:52 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a result of the architecture of Cassandra, which fundamentally requires a thread for an active thrift request&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn&apos;t the whole point of HSHA to fix this?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281972" author="scode" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 22:05:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Not unless there&apos;s an entire re-implementation of the StorageProxy interface to be asynchronous that exists in parallel with the synchronous one that I have somehow missed, or we&apos;ve done some bytecode weaving tricks to create continuations on the JVM... Just look at &lt;tt&gt;fetchRows&lt;/tt&gt; for example. Unless I&apos;ve gone completely senile, it&apos;s still standard synchronous code that blocks on futures and finally returns.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13281973" author="scode" created="Wed, 23 May 2012 22:06:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The point of the HSHA as I have been treating it, is to be asynch on the thrift protocol side. In other words, instead of thread-per-&lt;b&gt;connection&lt;/b&gt; we have thread-per-&lt;b&gt;active-request&lt;/b&gt;, which is much much better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have taken it to mean that half (the front-end/connection i/o stuff) being asynch, and the other half (the implementation of the RPC calls) being synchronous.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282171" author="vijay2win@yahoo.com" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 04:11:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Peter, i dont understand how will latency come into picture? Selectors are woken when the data is available, right? if for some reason your connection is taking 15 ms or what even in the middle of a read you are better off disconnecting and reconnecting... I still dont understand how 500 threads will help it will all hang right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically these threads (4*CPU core&apos;s) are used for selection read/write (only during that time) and the TP executes it and the selector is woken up again when the data has to be written. Are we having the same conversation as in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-3590&quot; title=&quot;Use multiple connection to share the OutboutTCPConnection&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-3590&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-3590&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (but this is within the DC&apos;s where latencies are really low)?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282208" author="scode" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 05:44:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The RPC calls, I&apos;m talking about the actual Java methods that correspond to names of methods in the thrift spec, run in threads. Both reads and writes run as such calls. The thread will be &quot;hogged&quot; for that request until the call returns. This is just standard Java, nothing having to do with thrift or selector threads. Whatever thrift is doing, at some point it&apos;s handing off the servicing of an RPC call to a Java method call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to avoid having a thread per request, you would have to actually re-write the relevant code to be asynchronous (keep necessary state explicitly instead of implicitly on the stack, make it up-side-down at each block point, no longer have working exception handling across block points, etc) - that is, barring generalized things like JVM coroutines/bytecode weaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &quot;necessary code&quot; here being things like fetchRows() for example, and everything else involving servicing thrift requests.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282209" author="scode" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 05:46:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;And latency directly translates into the amount of time a thread is &quot;hogged&quot; for the purpose of a request. Thus, it directly affects concurrency.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282213" author="scode" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 05:49:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;If you want an analogy, just compare with any standard LAMP server where you have some PHP script blocking on remote network calls. In the same way as the apache admin would have to tweak max clients to get throughput and saturate resources, we have to have enough RPC worker threads in Cassandra.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282218" author="vijay2win@yahoo.com" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 06:06:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;haaa you are talking about &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;            &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (conf.rpc_min_threads == &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;)
                conf.rpc_min_threads = conf.rpc_server_type.toLowerCase().equals(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;hsha&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)
                                     ? &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;Runtime&lt;/span&gt;.getRuntime().availableProcessors() * 4
                                     : 16;
            &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; (conf.rpc_max_threads == &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;)
                conf.rpc_max_threads = conf.rpc_server_type.toLowerCase().equals(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;hsha&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)
                                     ? &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;Runtime&lt;/span&gt;.getRuntime().availableProcessors() * 4
                                     : &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;Integer&lt;/span&gt;.MAX_VALUE;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was talking about &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CassandraDaemon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;serverEngine = &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; CustomTHsHaServer(serverArgs, executorService, &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;Runtime&lt;/span&gt;.getRuntime().availableProcessors());
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our environment we run @ rpc_min_threads: 16 rpc_max_threads:1024 and has worked well for us &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My bad for misreading the ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a result of the architecture of Cassandra, which fundamentally requires a thread for an active thrift request.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually made me think you are really talking about CustomTHSHA server... because the whole point of THSHA server is to eliminate that as jonathan mentioned. anyways...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282229" author="scode" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 06:23:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&apos;m talking about &lt;tt&gt;rpc_max_threads&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually made me think you are really talking about CustomTHSHA server... because the whole point of THSHA server is to eliminate that as jonathan mentioned. anyways...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t understand why this is still a point of contention though. There&apos;s still no code in Cassandra that in any way avoids having a thread per active (client) request. By &quot;active&quot; here I mean &quot;getting processed by Cassandra&quot; (so I&apos;m not talking about requests that are being read from the client TCP connection, or are queueing to get executed on a worker thread).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We no longer requires a thread &lt;b&gt;per client connection&lt;/b&gt;, which is good. But we still have a thread &lt;b&gt;per client request&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13282596" author="slebresne" created="Thu, 24 May 2012 16:19:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I agree with Peter, StorageProxy being synchronous, we do need on thread per active request (this is &quot;annoying&quot; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-2478&quot; title=&quot;Custom CQL protocol/transport&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-2478&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-2478&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; too). It would be neat to make StorageProxy asynchronous but that&apos;s likely very much non-trivial. So on the thread numbers, I also agree that some big number would be much better. Those threads will mostly spend time waiting, so I don&apos;t think the context switching will kill us anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13283179" author="scode" created="Fri, 25 May 2012 07:07:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attaching suggested patch against trunk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the pre-existing comments claim async will be removed in the next major release, I removed it entirely from comments (but not the code).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I re-phrased some of the stuff and added an attempted explanation for the user as to how to figure out what limit to set. As usual I think I may be too verbose; maybe it&apos;s better to just refer to a separate wiki page than to try to explain inline?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I&apos;d favor making hsha the default despite it being slower on Windows, though that&apos;s a concern not within the scope of this ticket. I didn&apos;t make that change in the patch.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13283264" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 25 May 2012 09:54:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I do think it&apos;s maybe a bit too much info for a config file &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;. I&apos;d remove the two last paragraphs and maybe rewrite the second one with something along the lines of: &quot;The default is unlimited and thus provide no protection against clients overwhelming the server. You are encouraged to set a maximum that makes sense for you in production, but do keep in mind that rpc_max_threads represents the maximum number of client requests this server may execute concurrently.&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there&apos;s a typo: &quot;Regardless of your &lt;b&gt;cohice&lt;/b&gt;&quot;. And for &quot;# rpc_max_threads: (unlimited)&quot;, it suggests that &apos;(unlimited)&apos; is a valid value which is not the case. I&apos;d prefer leaving the 2048 value, it does not have to represent the actual default (it doesn&apos;t always for other configs).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13283706" author="scode" created="Fri, 25 May 2012 19:39:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached v2 that incorporates those changes.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13284913" author="slebresne" created="Tue, 29 May 2012 16:27:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1, committed, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13404686" author="jeromatron" created="Sun, 1 Jul 2012 05:57:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Would a StorageProxy rewrite to be completely asynchronous be a separate ticket to be tackled later?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13404687" author="jeromatron" created="Sun, 1 Jul 2012 05:59:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sounds from Sylvain that a SP asynch rewrite would be good for implementing &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-2478&quot; title=&quot;Custom CQL protocol/transport&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-2478&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-2478&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13404922" author="slebresne" created="Mon, 2 Jul 2012 07:39:42 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Would a StorageProxy rewrite to be completely asynchronous be a separate ticket to be tackled later?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably a separate ticket to be tackled never &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; I mean, it would be neat intellectually speaking to get rid of the one-thread-per-active-request thing, but it&apos;s unclear it is a real problem in practice today and that would require a very substantial effort. Not sure at all it is worth the trouble. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13404994" author="jeromatron" created="Mon, 2 Jul 2012 10:45:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the clarification Sylvain.  I was just going through some past tickets and didn&apos;t want something that sounded like a good opportunity for the future fall through the cracks.  That&apos;s all.  Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12529776" name="CASSANDRA-4277-trunk-v2.txt" size="4539" author="scode" created="Fri, 25 May 2012 19:39:51 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12529684" name="CASSANDRA-4277-trunk.txt" size="5348" author="scode" created="Fri, 25 May 2012 07:07:55 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[scode]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>256019</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            13 years, 21 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i0gu27:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>96300</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>slebresne</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[slebresne]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12962"><![CDATA[Normal]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>