<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:38:00 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-5074] Add an official way to disable compaction</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-5074</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;We&apos;ve traditionally used &quot;min or max compaction threshold = 0&quot; to disable compaction, but this isn&apos;t exactly intuitive and it&apos;s inconsistently implemented &amp;#8211; allowed from jmx, not allowed from cli.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12624486">CASSANDRA-5074</key>
            <summary>Add an official way to disable compaction</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10003" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/trivial.svg">Low</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="marcuse">Marcus Eriksson</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="jbellis">Jonathan Ellis</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 16:13:21 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:32:21 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Tue, 9 Apr 2013 16:38:31 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>2.0 beta 1</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>7</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13535008" author="jbellis" created="Tue, 18 Dec 2012 16:13:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Adding a NoCompactionStrategy may be the simplest approach.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13579332" author="a.gazzarini" created="Fri, 15 Feb 2013 17:12:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi, as far as I understood, that requires writing a NullObject implementation of AbstractCompactionStrategy. Is that enough? I tried in my local Cassandra installation &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; create column family with compaction_strategy=NoCompactionStrategy &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and effectively the compaction never run...but to be honest I&apos;m a Cassandra newbie so I&apos;m wondering if that is enough. In this case I could submit the patch, otherwise please point me to the right direction, i&apos;d like to give a hand. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13580184" author="a.gazzarini" created="Sun, 17 Feb 2013 13:51:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It seems things are not so easy as described in my previous post. At the moment there are two possible strategies: Leveled and SizeTiered compaction. Looking at their code it seems that a disabled compaction should affect only getNextBackgroundTask(...) and not getMaximalTask and getUserDefinedTask (although this latter is not allowed in LeveredCompaction). &lt;br/&gt;
So the question is: what kind of compaction should run when I&apos;m using a NoCompactionStrategy and those two methods are invoked? SizeTiered, Leveled or another that maybe will be implemented tomorrow and plugged in?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious thing that comes in my mind is to think about NoCompactionStrategy as a decorator; something like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; create column family X with compaction_strategy=NoCompactionStrategy AND compaction_strategy_options=&lt;/p&gt;
{delegate_strategy: LeveledCompactionStrategy, &amp;lt;other options&amp;gt;}
&lt;p&gt;;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; create column family X with compaction_strategy=NoCompactionStrategy AND compaction_strategy_options=&lt;/p&gt;
{delegate_strategy: SizeTieredCompactionStrategy, &amp;lt;other options&amp;gt;}
&lt;p&gt;;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically the getNextBackgroundTask will do nothing, effectively disabling (minor) compaction, and the getMaximalTask and getUserDefinedTask will delegate to a wrapped strategy that has been injected (the &quot;delegate_strategy&quot; option). Now, I have a problem with the design of the XXXCompactionStrategy: in general compaction strategies (this is valid both for SizeTiered and Leveled) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;have a lot of initialization code in their constructor, this makes hard to use those strategies as an &quot;inner&quot; state of a decorator, I mean something like : decoratee.init() --&amp;gt; decoratee.getMaximalTask() --&amp;gt; decoratee.close();&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;receive a shared instance of ColumnFamilyStore and eventually (e.g. SizeTieredCompactionStrategy) modify it; the initialization code assumes no other compaction strategy are associated with the column family; so, based on this assumption, the concrete strategy instance is free to modify the state of its context (e.g. column family store)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;All above makes difficult to implement a decorator pattern because the decoratee instance will modify the same column family store of the decorator (for example the SizeTieredCompactionStrategy modifies the min and max threshod which are supposed to be 0 in case of compaction disabled).    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the ColumnFamilyStore has a method isCompactionDisabled that basically checks if min or max threshols are set to 0. Now, when instantiating the NoCompactionStrategy, one of the first thing that shoujld be done is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;store.setCompactionThresholds(0,0);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after that, the wrapped instance should be initialized. Suppose for example that the decoratee instance is a SizeTieredCompactionStrategy; creating a new instance will immediately reset the previous thresholds to 4 and 32 because the STCS has this code in its constructor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cfs.setCompactionThresholds(cfs.metadata.getMinCompactionThreshold(), cfs.metadata.getMaxCompactionThreshold());&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing, just to say that a simple NullObject is not enough, I&apos;m trying to solve that; once did, I&apos;ll submit a patch.  &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13580256" author="slebresne" created="Sun, 17 Feb 2013 19:14:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&apos;m not completely convinced about that NoCompactionStrategy idea. I agree with the ticket premises than using min/max thresholds is adhoc, especially since those threshold have no other meaning for leveled compaction.  However, as Andrea says, we only want to disable automatic (background) compaction, not the user triggered ones, so replacing the strategy entirely feels overkill to me. Overall, a simple boolean in ColumnFamilyStore would seem much simpler to me. And since we already have the disableAutoCompaction call in JMX (for some reason it doesn&apos;t seem the enableAutoCompaction is expose in JMX so we should add it), I&apos;d suggest using that as the sole way to enable/disable auto compactions.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13580494" author="a.gazzarini" created="Mon, 18 Feb 2013 08:48:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Right, I agree...the simplest thing that could possibly work; but in my opinion there&apos;s still something that needs to be changed: setting the min and / or max threshold, strictly speaking doesn&apos;t disable the compaction, because is up to the concrete strategy implementor to check that doing &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if (cfs.isCompactionDisabled()) {&lt;br/&gt;
...&lt;br/&gt;
}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it should be better to move this responsibility to the superlayer. &lt;br/&gt;
So my suggestion is to change a little bit the AbstractCompactionStrategy in order to use a template method. Something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(AbstractCompactionStrategy)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;final synchronized AbstractCompactionTask getNextBackgroundTask(final int gcBefore)
{
    if (!cfs.isCompactionDisabled()) { 
       doGetNextBackgroundTask(gcBefore);
    }
}
...

abstract AbstractCompactionTask doGetNextBackgroundTask(final int gcBefore);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13580725" author="slebresne" created="Mon, 18 Feb 2013 17:27:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In case that wasn&apos;t clear, I didn&apos;t said there is nothing to change. On the contrary, we should &lt;b&gt;stop&lt;/b&gt; relying on setting the min/max compaction threshold to disable compaction (I&apos;d be in favor of always considering that setting them to 0 is disallowed, but we&apos;d have to leave that to 2.0 to not break it in a minor release). So instead I would add a per-cfs &apos;isAutoCompactionEnable&apos; boolean. As for the call to isCompactionDisabled, it should indeed be moved, but I would move it to CompactionManager directly (where I would put 2 checks, one prior to submitting to the compaction executor, to avoid submitting useless task in the first place, and then again before the call to getNextBackgroundTask, just in case the runnable has been sitting for too long on the executor and has missed the first check).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13583140" author="a.gazzarini" created="Thu, 21 Feb 2013 12:08:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Probably that wasn&apos;t clear, but honestly I believe it&apos;s a problem of mine: I have just a little bit of experience on Cassandra source code and its internal architecture. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, now I think I got the point about your idea, so I will continue investigating the code in order to implement that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A question: in case the logic is moved on the CompactionMananger, what should be, from client point of view, a nice and good way to indicate that the (background) compaction must be disabled? I believe the command line of my previous post is no longer appropriate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; create column family XYZ with compaction_strategy=NoCompactionStrategy &lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="13623634" author="krummas" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 13:49:16 +0000"  >&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;adds nodetool commands (disableautocompaction, enableautocompaction)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;makes it possible to set via schema, &quot;update cf x with auto_compaction_disabled=true&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;should be backwards compactible, if someone has disabled compactions with max_compaction_threshold, it will disable compactions using the new way (maybe should output a warning or similar though)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13625263" author="slebresne" created="Mon, 8 Apr 2013 09:59:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The general idea lgtm. A few remarks though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;There is no handling of CQL3 (which is in the package org.apache.cassandra.cql3). I&apos;ll not that for CQL3, this setting should probably be a &apos;compaction&apos; option, not at top-level one. Thruth being told, maybe it would be cleaner to have that be a compaction option in the code too (handled by AbstractCompactionStrategy)?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Currently, whether compaction is disabled or not is checked by the compaction strategy themselves. In particular, SizeTiered directly check the min and max thresholds (rather than calling isCompactionDisabled) in getNextBackgroundSSTables, so that needs to be fixed. Furthermore, those checks are redundant with the newly added checks in CompactionManager. And since there&apos;s the new &apos;isActive&apos; flag that also mean &quot;don&apos;t create a compaction task&quot;, maybe it would be simpler to create an AbstractCompactionStrategy.isEnabled() method that would return &apos;isActive &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !isAutoCompactionDisabled()&apos; and use that exclusively.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We should probably now refuse setting the min/max thresholds to 0 everywhere (and add a mention in the NEWS file).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In nodeCmd, the convention for methods that take a keyspace and column family argument is that if they are not given, the method applies to all keyspace/CF. Could be handy here too.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Nit: For the enableAutoCompaction with an argument, we can add a @VisibleForTesting annotation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13626452" author="krummas" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2013 10:25:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 on all the comments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now it is a compaction_strategy_option in cli, and a compaction = &lt;/p&gt;
{..}
&lt;p&gt; option in CQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i also removed a call to cfs.setCompactionThresholds in the STCS constructor, couldn&apos;t find a reason it was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and, if there is a better way of disallowing min/max thresholds = 0 than checking in cql, cql3 and cli that does not break existing schemas, let me know&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13626667" author="slebresne" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2013 14:45:12 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;i also removed a call to cfs.setCompactionThresholds in the STCS constructor, couldn&apos;t find a reason it was there&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the days (like 1.0 old, when dinosaurs where roaming the earth), we used to set the min/max thresholds to 0/Integer.MAX_VALUE in LCS. So STCS needed to restore the settings to sane levels in case we were switching from LCS to STCS. But since then we&apos;ve fixed our ways (in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-4233&quot; title=&quot;overlapping sstables in leveled compaction strategy&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-4233&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-4233&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; apparently, thanks git pickaxe) so this is just some leftover. It&apos;s fine removing it and you can even remove the comment the patch adds imo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;if there is a better way of disallowing min/max thresholds = 0 than checking in cql, cql3 and cli&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I&apos;ve just realized that following &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-3430&quot; title=&quot;Break Big Compaction Lock apart&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-3430&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-3430&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we need to check the ACS.isActive flag &lt;b&gt;within&lt;/b&gt; getNextBackgroundTask (with the synchronized block in particular) otherwise it could be racy. So I think we should move back the isAutoCompactionDisabled check from CompactionManager to STCS/LCS.getNextBackgroundTask (it&apos;s fine to keep the check at the beginning of CompactionManager.submitBackground however, no point is pushing tasks that will do nothing on the executor). My bad for suggesting otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with the above fixed, +1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nit: could be nice to preserve the comment in CFS.disableAutoCompaction(), it&apos;s still useful.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13626790" author="krummas" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2013 16:38:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;thanks, fixed the comments and pushed as ebefb77c6e8a5046a8c1b1bb0edd258aaf0ad8b7&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13836731" author="vongocminh" created="Mon, 2 Dec 2013 17:56:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you please confirm that KS and CF are &quot;optional&quot; parameter in nodetool disableautocompaction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are running C* v2.0.3 and the command nodetool does not seem working. We disable the auto compaction on all nodes via nodetool and the servers continue to compact CFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;INFO 18:45:03,594 Compacted 4 sstables to &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;D:\AtlasData\titan\pdl_identity\titan-pdl_identity.pdl_identity_portfolio_idx-jb-449,&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;.  183&#225;596 bytes to 183&#225;289 (~99% of original) in 546ms = 0,320143MB&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your help.&lt;br/&gt;
Best regards,&lt;br/&gt;
Minh&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13836776" author="krummas" created="Mon, 2 Dec 2013 18:46:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;yes, without ks/cf it disables for all column families&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;note that it resets on restart though, if you want to disable it forever, you need to set the compaction strategy option &quot;enabled&quot; to false&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if it does not disable all compactions, it is a bug&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13836809" author="vongocminh" created="Mon, 2 Dec 2013 19:15:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m kind of lost here: with nodetool in C* v2.0.1, &lt;b&gt;disableautocompaction&lt;/b&gt; does no effect (servers continue compressing SSTables); with v2.0.3, the &quot;feature&quot; is no longer recorgnized by nodetool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C:\Workspace\apache-cassandra-2.0.3\bin&amp;gt;nodetool -h parw00146880 disableautocompaction&lt;br/&gt;
Starting NodeTool&lt;br/&gt;
Unrecognized command: disableautocompaction&lt;br/&gt;
usage: java org.apache.cassandra.tools.NodeCmd --host &amp;lt;arg&amp;gt; &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13836822" author="krummas" created="Mon, 2 Dec 2013 19:33:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;uh that is weird, just downloaded the 2.0.3 tarball and disableautocompaction exists&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;btw, nodetool disableautocompaction disables for all &lt;b&gt;existing&lt;/b&gt; column families, so if you disableautocompaction and then start stress (for example), it will not be disabled for the cfs it creates&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13837004" author="vongocminh" created="Mon, 2 Dec 2013 22:27:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot for your quick answer.&lt;br/&gt;
It is indeed very weird. I downloaded the binary for Windows from this address last week:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://archive.apache.org/dist/cassandra/2.0.3/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://archive.apache.org/dist/cassandra/2.0.3/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will recheck it tomorrow ...&lt;br/&gt;
(edit)&lt;br/&gt;
The cqlsh shows this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;cqlsh 4.1.0 | Cassandra 2.0.3 | CQL spec 3.1.1 | Thrift protocol 19.38.0&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12577213" name="0001-CASSANDRA-5074-make-it-possible-to-disable-autocompa.patch" size="49606" author="marcuse" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 13:49:43 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12577774" name="0001-CASSANDRA-5074-v2.patch" size="31270" author="marcuse" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2013 10:25:56 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[marcuse]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>300035</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            11 years, 51 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i165fr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>244013</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>slebresne</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[slebresne]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12961"><![CDATA[Low]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>