<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:42:28 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-6503] sstables from stalled repair sessions become live after a reboot and can resurrect deleted data</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-6503</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;The sstables streamed in during a repair session don&apos;t become active until the session finishes.  If something causes the repair session to hang for some reason, those sstables will hang around until the next reboot, and become active then.  If you don&apos;t reboot for 3 months, this can cause data to resurrect, as GC grace has expired, so tombstones for the data in those sstables may have already been collected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12685433">CASSANDRA-6503</key>
            <summary>sstables from stalled repair sessions become live after a reboot and can resurrect deleted data</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10003" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/trivial.svg">Low</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="jasobrown">Jason Brown</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="jeremiah">Jeremiah Jordan</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 18:52:10 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:13:58 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 13:31:05 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>1.2.14</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>2.0.5</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>1</votes>
                                    <watches>10</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13852019" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Wed, 18 Dec 2013 18:53:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;One thing I was thinking that might help with this is if we could leave the sstables named &quot;-tmp&quot; until we are ready to make them become active.  That way when you reboot, any files hanging around will get removed on restart, instead of becoming active.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13852219" author="jbellis" created="Wed, 18 Dec 2013 22:06:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think we should be messing with repair code in 1.2.14, not for something that it took 3 years for someone to run across.  Suggest targetting 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13853437" author="jbellis" created="Thu, 19 Dec 2013 23:10:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;(Not actually sure this is still an issue in 2.0.x but it seems possible.)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13853475" author="yukim" created="Thu, 19 Dec 2013 23:42:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In 1.2 as well as 2.0, every time the node receives SSTable file, it starts writing as &apos;tmp&apos;, but at the end of receiving, it calls SSTableWriter#closeAndOpenReader that moves received file out of &apos;tmp&apos;. At this point, SSTables are still not added to ColumnFamilyStore, though if we shutdown the node and restart, the node would recognize received files even though streaming session was not finished successfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need little tweak to defer renaming of SSTable files to do so after receiving all streamed files.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13863024" author="jasobrown" created="Mon, 6 Jan 2014 14:48:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached patch, 6503_c1.2-v1, defers the release of the sstables to the CFS until the session is complete. Note: that patch is only for 1.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For c* 2.0, I&apos;d like &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yukim&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yukim&quot;&gt;yukim&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s advice. I have a WIP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jasobrown/cassandra/tree/6503_c2.0&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/jasobrown/cassandra/tree/6503_c2.0&lt;/a&gt;. The problem I&apos;m running into is that FileMessage.sstable is of type SSTableReader, which we need on the sender side, but on the receiver side we want SSTableWriter (if we are going to defer the release of the sstables. For hacking things up sake, I&apos;ve just changed FileMessage.sstable to a plain SSTable and let the users do the casting - which is only in two places, one of which is the FileMessage.Serializer.serailize() method. Not very extensive, but perhaps a bit sloppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuki, do you think it&apos;s worthwhile to split up the FileMessage object into two classes like OutFileMessage (which has a SSTR) and InFileMessage (which has SSTW)? &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13863083" author="yukim" created="Mon, 6 Jan 2014 16:32:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jasobrown&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jasobrown&quot;&gt;jasobrown&lt;/a&gt; What I&apos;m thinking to do is to closeAndOpenReader without renaming from tmp as we receive, and rename them at once at the end. And for renaming multiple files at once we probably want some kind of lockfile(also resolve &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-2900&quot; title=&quot;Allow bulk load via streaming to complete &amp;#39;transactionally&amp;#39;&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-2900&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-2900&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though finalizing SSTable write in closeAndOpenReader takes some time, so completely defer finalize as you do may be a good idea. I think splitting FileMessage is better than casting.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13863773" author="jasobrown" created="Tue, 7 Jan 2014 01:28:57 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;we probably want some kind of lockfile&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting. What problems do you see this solving (I&apos;m probably missing something in my understanding)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;splitting FileMessage is better than casting&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I knew you were gonna say that &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13864313" author="jasobrown" created="Tue, 7 Jan 2014 15:01:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yukim&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yukim&quot;&gt;yukim&lt;/a&gt; I can see how modifying closeAndOpenReader() would help here, but there&apos;s one wrinkle (I think): if we defer renaming the files from closeAndOpenReader(), we would need to rename the &lt;b&gt;open&lt;/b&gt; SSTR, and there&apos;s a note in FileUtils.renameWithConfirm():&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;// &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; is not FSWE because usually when we see it it&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&apos;s because we didn&apos;&lt;/span&gt;t close the file before renaming it,
&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;// and Windows is picky about that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&apos;m not sure about the deferred rename of the SSTR, assuming we care about Windows.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868124" author="yukim" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 18:53:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think you are right. We don&apos;t want to close SSTR again for renaming.&lt;br/&gt;
Let&apos;s stick with deferring closeAndOpenReader as you did.&lt;br/&gt;
For the patch, I think it would be nice to call SSTW.abort() to discard already received file when something bad happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting. What problems do you see this solving (I&apos;m probably missing something in my understanding)?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the node goes down during we are doing closeAndOpenReader to received files, there is a chance we have already renamed files.&lt;br/&gt;
So I wanted to make sure the node won&apos;t read those files when the node come up.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868182" author="jasobrown" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 19:30:12 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;call SSTW.abort() ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Makes sense, will add that in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the node goes down during we are doing closeAndOpenReader to received files, there is a chance we have already renamed files&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, got it. Will come up with an idea and drop into the next patch. Thanks&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868321" author="rcoli" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 21:24:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;What is the &quot;since&quot; version for this ticket?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems rather serious that users were still exposed to zombie data even if following repair best practice, if a repair session ever stalled... especially because repair sessions tend to stall. In a way we are fortunate that the only way to restart a failed repair session is to restart the nodes (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-3486&quot; title=&quot;Node Tool command to stop repair&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-3486&quot;&gt;CASSANDRA-3486&lt;/a&gt;) because this workaround has protected some users from this bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think we should be messing with repair code in 1.2.14, not for something that it took 3 years for someone to run across. Suggest targetting 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of impact here seems confused. What has happened is not that it took 3 years for someone to encounter this bug; rather, it took 3 years for someone who ran across this very serious bug to notice and care enough to file a JIRA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs which violate guarantees in the way this one does (&quot;I repaired once every gc_grace_seconds and still ended up with zombie data!&quot;) should IMO be considered Major or Critical and should be candidates for fixes at any point in the release cycle. If we can entirely re-write a broken feature like replace_node in 1.2.12, I fail to see what keeps us from fixing buggy code that erroneously treats temporary files as permanent, in 1.2.14.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868353" author="jasobrown" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 21:52:49 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;What is the &quot;since&quot; version for this ticket?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect it&apos;s been around for a while - I only (knowingly) ran into the problem with 1.1.7.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;3 years&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original descriptions says &quot;3 months&quot;, and that is how long we took to run into the problem (at a serious level). I think perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jbellis&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jbellis&quot;&gt;jbellis&lt;/a&gt; misspoke when he mentioned &quot;3 years&quot; in an earlier comment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for fix version, I would like to see this in 1.2, as well, but it depends on the changes needed. At this point, though, the patch I have now (still WIP) is not too dramatic, so it could reasonably go into 1.2, but we should judge when it&apos;s ready/accepted.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868407" author="jbellis" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 22:29:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m counting 3 years since 0.7 which is at least as long as repair has worked this way.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868423" author="jasobrown" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 22:48:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jbellis&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jbellis&quot;&gt;jbellis&lt;/a&gt; Ahh, OK. Thank you for clarifying.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13868432" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Fri, 10 Jan 2014 22:52:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think most people notice they have hung repairs, and restart the nodes to clear them, before it becomes a problem.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13879925" author="jasobrown" created="Thu, 23 Jan 2014 13:42:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached v2 patch has the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Changed StreamReceiveTask to keep a collection of SSTW rather than SSTR. This allows us to do the conversion of SSTW to SSTR all together after we&apos;ve gotten all the streamed files. Also fixed up the code paths to here so they pass SSTW.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Also in StreamReceiveTask, added an abort() method, which will discard the SSTWs it has buffered up. Changed StreamSession so that when a session ends in failure, it calls the new STR.abort() method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Split FileMessage out into IncomingFileMessage and OutgoingFileMessage. I needed to do this since as each one has a different subclass of SSTable, but also because java generics doesn&apos;t allow me to return different subclasses from StreamMessage.Serializer&amp;lt;V extends StreamMessage&amp;gt;. This necessitated the changes in StreamMessage as I couldn&apos;t have one serializer for both IncomingFileMessage and OutgoingFileMessage.  As it didn&apos;t seem best to create a new StreamMessage.Type (something like FILE_IN and FILE_OUT) just to represent the FILE message type&apos;s behavior on inbound vs. outbound, I instead split the SM.Type.serializer into two variables: inSerializer and outSerializer. For all the other Type&apos;s, the in and out serializers are the same class; in the case of Type.FILE, this is where I&apos;m referencing IncomingFileMessage.serializer and OutgoingFileMessage.serializer, respectively. This seemed the cleanest way to introduce the now-bifurcated life of Type.FILE/FileMessage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;added StreamLockfile to satisfy &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yukim&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yukim&quot;&gt;yukim&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s request for a mechanism to remove, on restart, the subset of SSTRs that were successfully converted when others from it&apos;s stream session failed. Assumes the process crashed in the middle of converting the SSTWs to SSTRs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the first patch, I chose to write the lockfile out to the commitlog directory. I did this as it seems like overkill to add another yaml setting (and Config/DD change) just for this value. Thus, I wanted to piggyback off something else that we already have, and DD.getCommitLogDirectory seemed the least worst. I&apos;m open to suggestions on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once these changes are incorporated into 2.0 and trunk, I would still like to do something for 1.2 but I do not think we need to be as extensive as what we&apos;re doing for 2.0+. Perhaps leave out the lockfile and the abort(), and just leave the deferring of converting SSTW to SSTR until the end of the session (basically what the current 1.2 patch does, but I&apos;ll check it out again after the 2.0 stuff is good).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13885814" author="yukim" created="Wed, 29 Jan 2014 21:07:54 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the first patch, I chose to write the lockfile out to the commitlog directory. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about using SSTable directory itself? You can access it using Directories object so it is easy to perform delete if we do it inside CFS.scrubDataDirectories. Attaching patch for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than that, it seems good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;...I would still like to do something for 1.2 but I do not think we need to be as extensive as what we&apos;re doing for 2.0+. Perhaps leave out the lockfile and the abort(), and just leave the deferring of converting SSTW to SSTR until the end of the session...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree. We can commit attached 1.2 patch as well.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13886836" author="jasobrown" created="Thu, 30 Jan 2014 18:01:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed the 1.2 patch to 1.2, have a few questions for &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yukim&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yukim&quot;&gt;yukim&lt;/a&gt; about 2.0 patch that I&apos;ll add here in a minute (after coffee)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13886961" author="jasobrown" created="Thu, 30 Jan 2014 19:32:32 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;How about using SSTable directory itself?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that is legit as StreamReceiveTask is specific to a CF.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887378" author="yukim" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 01:59:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jasobrown&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jasobrown&quot;&gt;jasobrown&lt;/a&gt; Looks like we need to make a little tweak around complete message since we moved adding received SSTables to different thread.&lt;br/&gt;
It is breaking StreamingTransferTest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patch attach for fix.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887636" author="krummas" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 10:58:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yukim&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yukim&quot;&gt;yukim&lt;/a&gt; i committed the followup patch to 2.0, revert if that was a bad idea &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887789" author="jasobrown" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 14:23:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The followup patch is fine, but I&apos;m not quite sure why it is needed. How does being in a different thread affect the sending of the CompleteMessage, which doesn&apos;t look like it was there before?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13888321" author="yukim" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 23:44:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jasobrown&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jasobrown&quot;&gt;jasobrown&lt;/a&gt; Complete message exchange was actually fragile before and could leave streaming session to WAIT_COMPLETE state on one side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only bellow pattern worked, and it worked because we were sending complete as we receive FileMessage in the same thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;(A) ---&amp;gt; File     ---&amp;gt; (B) ...1
(A) &amp;lt;--- Complete &amp;lt;--- (B) ...2
(A) ---&amp;gt; Complete ---&amp;gt; (B) ...3
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now finalizing all received files moved to another thread. So sending receiving complete from A(3) gets first and B terminates it session without sending back complete, leaving A as WAIT_COMPLETE. Thus we needed to make sure to send complete message.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12917421">CASSANDRA-10797</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is related to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12640213">CASSANDRA-5412</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12696806">CASSANDRA-6756</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12626245" name="6503-2.0-followup.txt" size="1778" author="yukim" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 01:59:10 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12624797" name="6503_2.0-v2.diff" size="40618" author="jasobrown" created="Thu, 23 Jan 2014 13:42:36 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12625969" name="6503_2.0-v3.diff" size="37979" author="yukim" created="Wed, 29 Jan 2014 21:07:54 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12621600" name="6503_c1.2-v1.patch" size="4576" author="jasobrown" created="Mon, 6 Jan 2014 14:48:28 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>4.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[jasobrown]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>364510</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            11 years, 42 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i1qtv3:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>364810</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12311421" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiversion">
                        <customfieldname>Reproduced In</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12323354">1.1.7</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>yukim</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[yukim]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12961"><![CDATA[Low]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:version">
                        <customfieldname>Since Version</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12316026">0.7.0</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>