<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:44:59 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-6643] Limit user types to the keyspace they are defined in</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-6643</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not 100% certain this is a bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current syntax for &quot;alter type rename&quot; requires the keyspace on the old and new table name (if a keyspace is not active). So, to rename the type &apos;foo&apos; to &apos;bar&apos;, you have to issue this statement:&lt;br/&gt;
ALTER TYPE ks.foo rename to ks.bar .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, this syntax will also allow renaming the type into another existing keyspace, which updates the metadata in system.schema_usertypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m wondering if perhaps we can omit the second keyspace prefix and implicitly rename into the same keyspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reproduce:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;cqlsh&amp;gt; create keyspace user_types with replication = {&apos;class&apos;:&apos;SimpleStrategy&apos;, &apos;replication_factor&apos;:3} ;
cqlsh&amp;gt; create keyspace user_types2 with replication = {&apos;class&apos;:&apos;SimpleStrategy&apos;, &apos;replication_factor&apos;:3} ;
cqlsh&amp;gt; CREATE TYPE user_types.simple_type (user_number int);
cqlsh&amp;gt; alter type user_types.simple_type rename to user_types2.simple_type;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Renaming to another keyspace is also possible when a keyspace is active, like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;cqlsh:user_types&amp;gt; alter type simple_type rename to user_types2.simple_type;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
                <environment>&lt;p&gt;java version &quot;1.7.0_51&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
cassandra from trunk, 4b54b8...&lt;/p&gt;</environment>
        <key id="12692427">CASSANDRA-6643</key>
            <summary>Limit user types to the keyspace they are defined in</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10002" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Normal</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="slebresne">Sylvain Lebresne</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="rhatch">Russ Hatch</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 01:29:45 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:31:55 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 16 May 2014 13:57:12 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>2.1 rc1</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Legacy/CQL</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13887350" author="rhatch" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 01:30:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m working on dtests for user types, so I can add one for this scenario when we know what the behavior ought to be.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887412" author="mishail" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 03:03:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=rhatch&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;rhatch&quot;&gt;rhatch&lt;/a&gt; It doesn&apos;t work if there is a table which uses the type, does it?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887718" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 13:19:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Just to make sure we&apos;re on the same page, are you saying that we can rename to another keyspace but that you wonder if we shouldn&apos;t refuse it? Or that it&apos;s allowed by the syntax but is broken? Something else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but in general, I&apos;d be fine limiting type rename to within the same keyspace if it turns out there is a technical difficulty to make it work across keyspaces, but skimming quickly over the code suggest it might be just be working alright (or rather, it was the intent that it would work but I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve tested it) and I don&apos;t see why we&apos;d limit it if it works. But again, I might me missing your point.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887794" author="jbellis" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 14:37:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;limiting rename to the same ks would simplify the security concerns imo&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13887915" author="rhatch" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 17:22:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=slebresne&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;slebresne&quot;&gt;slebresne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
yeah, I can currently rename to another keyspace but think maybe we shouldn&apos;t allow it (or at least implicitly name into the same ks implicitly when no ks prefix is on the rename&apos;s &apos;destination&apos;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rename to another ks works even if a table in the &apos;old&apos; keyspace depends on the type, so I do think as-is it would be possible to get the types/tables into a weird or at least confusing state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scenario shows we can make a table depend on a type then rename that type into another keyspace:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;cqlsh&amp;gt; create keyspace user_types with replication = {&apos;class&apos;:&apos;SimpleStrategy&apos;, &apos;replication_factor&apos;:3} ;
cqlsh&amp;gt; create keyspace user_types2 with replication = {&apos;class&apos;:&apos;SimpleStrategy&apos;, &apos;replication_factor&apos;:3} ;
cqlsh&amp;gt; CREATE TYPE user_types.simple_type (user_number int);
cqlsh&amp;gt; CREATE TABLE user_types.simple_table (
   ... id uuid PRIMARY KEY,
   ... number simple_type
   ... );
cqlsh&amp;gt; alter type user_types.simple_type rename to user_types2.simple_type;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do still enforce the correct relationship when trying to drop the type in use though, but now there&apos;s a type in one ks dependent on a table in another ks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;cqlsh&amp;gt; drop type user_types2.simple_type;
Bad Request: Cannot drop user type user_types2.simple_type as it is still used by table user_types.simple_table
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13888111" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 20:15:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thinking a bit more about that, I think the right question is whether we want to allow a table to depend on a type in another keyspace. Currently, you can (it has been designed for it), and you don&apos;t need type renames for that, it&apos;s enough to simply refer to a type using it&apos;s fullly qualified name at table creation. Now, this does present a problem if a keyspace is dropped but contains types used in another keyspace. I suppose we&apos;d need to check for that case and refuse the drop in that case. It&apos;s not done right now though. And that does complicate security rules a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe having tables reference types in another keyspace is not that useful and it&apos;s better to keep things simpler and just forbid it. The reason I left that option initially however was for the case where someone have a type he uses in multiple keyspace, to avoid having to re-declare it multiple times (re-declaring the type multiple time is probably not a huge deal in itself, but that will mean the types will be different which could end up being slightly annoying on the client driver side if you really want those per-keyspace types to be the same).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyway, I don&apos;t think I have an extremely strong opinion on that one. But if we do let table reference type in another keyspace, it feels relatively natural to me to let type rename change the keyspace. But if we don&apos;t (let table reference type in another keyspace), then I agree that it&apos;s natural to forbid type rename to change the keyspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;or at least implicitly name into the same ks implicitly when no ks prefix is on the rename&apos;s &apos;destination&apos;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a type name is not fully qualified, it refers to the current keyspace everywhere else, so I really don&apos;t want to make a special case for that one. Would be confusing for no much value added imo.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13888121" author="jbellis" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 20:19:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think one keyspace should be isolated from others.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13888158" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 31 Jan 2014 20:59:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You&apos;re right, that&apos;s probably simpler that way. And we can always change it later if it turns out it would be really more useful, while the contrary is harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ll workup a patch to limit it to one keyspace.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13935237" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 14 Mar 2014 16:42:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Actually, just to make sure we agree here before I go ahead and remove code, do we agree that this means user types can never be fully qualified and always implicitly refer to the keyspace of whatever query the name is part of? Cause contrarily to what I said just above, if we do so, I don&apos;t think we&apos;ll be able to change our mind later and allow referencing other keyspace type. I can leave with that &quot;limitation&quot; but just wanted to double check we&apos;re fine with that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13935250" author="rhatch" created="Fri, 14 Mar 2014 16:55:29 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;can never be fully qualified and always implicitly refer to the keyspace of whatever query the name is part of&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does that mean user types couldn&apos;t be created or added like so? (from the global keyspace):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;cqlsh&amp;gt; CREATE TYPE user_types.simple_type (user_number int);
cqlsh&amp;gt; CREATE TABLE user_types.simple_table (
   ... id uuid PRIMARY KEY,
   ... number simple_type
   ... );
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13935282" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 14 Mar 2014 17:22:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Right, right, we do need to allow fully qualified type names, my bad. But now that&apos;s means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;USE ks1;
CREATE TYPE mytype (f int);

USE ks2;
CREATE TABLE ks1.mytable (k mytype PRIMARY KEY);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;would be invalid because mytype would refer to ks2 (since it&apos;s not fully qualified).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13946754" author="slebresne" created="Tue, 25 Mar 2014 16:31:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So I just realized that in the current code, a non qualified user type name refers to the keyspace of the statement it&apos;s in, not the keyspace logged into. Meaning that in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;USE ks2;
CREATE TABLE ks1.mytable (k mytype PRIMARY KEY);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;mytype&lt;/tt&gt; refers to &lt;tt&gt;ks1&lt;/tt&gt;, not &lt;tt&gt;ks2&lt;/tt&gt;. Honestly, that&apos;s kind of an oversight, as imo that&apos;s somewhat inconsistent with how unqualified table name work (since they do refer to the logged keyspace). That being said, before I go into changing this all over the place (turns out it requires a slight refactoring), just wanted to check that we agree it&apos;s better to change so that non-qualified type name do refer to the keyspace logged in, not the &quot;statement&quot; keyspace?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13947406" author="rhatch" created="Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:49:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t have a strong opinion, but I think it seems reasonable when creating a table with user type to re-use the statement keyspace from the table (falling back to logged in keyspace if table has no prefix), since the tables/types will belong to the same keyspace anyway. But I think if the type keyspace is explicitly given we should use that, and not do anything surprising like switching it. So I guess I vote for leaving it the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the above scenario:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;USE ks2;
CREATE TABLE ks1.mytable (k mytype PRIMARY KEY);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively becomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;USE ks2;
CREATE TABLE ks1.mytable (k [ks1].mytype PRIMARY KEY);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you try this you should get an error (differing table keyspace and type keyspace):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;USE ks2;
CREATE TABLE ks1.mytable (k ks2.mytype PRIMARY KEY);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assume this wouldn&apos;t have any impact on the CREATE TYPE syntax, so I&apos;m assuming that would still be consistent with how CREATE TABLE figures out the keyspace.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13947692" author="slebresne" created="Wed, 26 Mar 2014 09:05:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;First attaching a patch to only allow referencing user types in the keyspace they are defined in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still not entirely convinced that the behavior described above is the best choice. It&apos;s not illogical, but I wonder if saying &quot;non qualified type and table names always refer to the logged keyspace&quot; wouldn&apos;t be simpler that &quot;non qualified table name refers to the logged keyspace, and so do type name, except when they are inside a statement in which case they refer to the statement keyspace&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13947896" author="jbellis" created="Wed, 26 Mar 2014 13:26:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;apologies if this was covered above, but when is logged keyspace different from statement keyspace?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13947904" author="slebresne" created="Wed, 26 Mar 2014 13:32:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;USE ks2;
CREATE TABLE ks1.mytable (k mytype PRIMARY KEY);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyspace for mytype (where we&apos;re look for mytype to be precise) could &lt;tt&gt;ks2&lt;/tt&gt; (the logged keyspace) or &lt;tt&gt;ks1&lt;/tt&gt; (the statement keyspace). Of course this only matter if you mix some fully-qualified names and some non-fully-qualifed ones, which is probably a bad idea in the first place, but well, still need to handle it. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13979741" author="slebresne" created="Thu, 24 Apr 2014 13:56:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Forgot to it the &apos;patch available&apos; button, so just did, but still would be nice to get confirmation regarding what&apos;s above. Don&apos;t want to end up committing a behavior we&apos;re not happy with, even if that&apos;s somewhat a detail.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13993130" author="jbellis" created="Thu, 8 May 2014 21:22:37 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;contrarily to what I said just above, if we do so, I don&apos;t think we&apos;ll be able to change our mind later and allow referencing other keyspace type&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wonder if saying &quot;non qualified type and table names always refer to the logged keyspace&quot; wouldn&apos;t be simpler &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think &quot;type names always refer to the statement keyspace&quot; makes the most sense; if we don&apos;t allow referencing types in a different keyspace, then referring to the logged keyspace is an error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to help people out, we could raise an error if there is ambiguity and require explicitly specifying ks1.mytype if ks1 and ks2 both have a mytype defined.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13997397" author="slebresne" created="Wed, 14 May 2014 08:45:28 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I don&apos;t remember &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;. But I think I confused myself a bit early on, so it should be ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think &quot;type names always refer to the statement keyspace&quot; makes the most sense&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I think I&apos;m warming up to that too. So anyway, let&apos;s go with this then, patch is ready for review (bumping issue to major just to make sure we don&apos;t accidentally release 2.1 without that change since it would be breaking to change it post-release). &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13998787" author="slebresne" created="Thu, 15 May 2014 14:06:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Rebased patch attached.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13998799" author="iamaleksey" created="Thu, 15 May 2014 14:18:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13999808" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 16 May 2014 13:57:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed, thanks&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12645016" name="6643.txt" size="3813" author="slebresne" created="Thu, 15 May 2014 14:06:58 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>1.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[slebresne]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>371022</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            11 years, 27 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i1rxzz:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>371327</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12311421" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiversion">
                        <customfieldname>Reproduced In</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12324159">2.1 rc3</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>aleksey</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[aleksey]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12962"><![CDATA[Normal]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>