<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:51:15 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-8860] Remove cold_reads_to_omit from STCS</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-8860</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;While I upgrading my cluster to 2.1.3, I find some nodes (not all) may have GC issue after the node restarting successfully. Old gen grows very fast and most of the space can not be recycled after setting its status to normal immediately. The qps of both reading and writing are very low and there is no heavy compaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jmap result seems strange that there are too many java.util.HashMap$Entry objects in heap, where in my experience the &quot;[B&quot; is usually the No1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I downgrade it to 2.1.1, this issue will not appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I uploaded conf files and jstack/jmap outputs. I&apos;ll upload heap dump if someone need it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment>&lt;p&gt;Cassandra 2.1.3, jdk 1.7u51&lt;/p&gt;</environment>
        <key id="12777272">CASSANDRA-8860</key>
            <summary>Remove cold_reads_to_omit from STCS</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10002" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Normal</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="marcuse">Marcus Eriksson</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="yangzhe1991">Phil Yang</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:47:07 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:31:19 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 4 Mar 2015 08:10:35 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>2.1.5</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Local/Compaction</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>10</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14337197" author="jbellis" created="Wed, 25 Feb 2015 21:06:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s odd, it sounds like the cache code but I don&apos;t know of any changes there in 2.1.3.  It would probably be useful to have the full heap dump to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14338466" author="benedict" created="Thu, 26 Feb 2015 14:36:04 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;it sounds like the cache code&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s a regular HashMap, not a CLHM, causing this heap pressure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;CompactionExecutor:14&quot; daemon prio=10 tid=0x00002aaace7a7800 nid=0x7e31 runnable &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;0x0000000042a79000&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
   java.lang.Thread.State: RUNNABLE&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.HashMap.transfer(HashMap.java:605)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.HashMap.resize(HashMap.java:585)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.HashMap.addEntry(HashMap.java:883)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.HashMap.put(HashMap.java:509)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.HashSet.add(HashSet.java:217)&lt;br/&gt;
	at org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.createOverlapChain(SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.java:235)&lt;br/&gt;
	at org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.filterColdSSTables(SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.java:202)&lt;br/&gt;
	at org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.getNextBackgroundSSTables(SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.java:85)&lt;br/&gt;
	at org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.getNextBackgroundTask(SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.java:320)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;locked &amp;lt;0x000000064f254560&amp;gt; (a org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.SizeTieredCompactionStrategy)&lt;br/&gt;
	at org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.WrappingCompactionStrategy.getNextBackgroundTask(WrappingCompactionStrategy.java:72)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;locked &amp;lt;0x000000064f254500&amp;gt; (a org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.WrappingCompactionStrategy)&lt;br/&gt;
	at org.apache.cassandra.db.compaction.CompactionManager$BackgroundCompactionTask.run(CompactionManager.java:234)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.concurrent.Executors$RunnableAdapter.call(Executors.java:471)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.concurrent.FutureTask.run(FutureTask.java:262)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor.runWorker(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:1145)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.util.concurrent.ThreadPoolExecutor$Worker.run(ThreadPoolExecutor.java:615)&lt;br/&gt;
	at java.lang.Thread.run(Thread.java:744)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like a viable candidate, and was introduced recently. I can&apos;t see anything fundamentally broken about it, although it does have O(n^2) memory utilisation in the number of sstables. This would require around 8500 sstables to be considered for compaction to create the current heap pressure, which is both: 1) possible for some users (so probably we need to rethink); and 2) also pretty uncommon? so perhaps not the issue here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could we get a list of the data files present on disk for this table, your log file, and perhaps a heap dump?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14338671" author="krummas" created="Thu, 26 Feb 2015 16:41:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sounds likely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workaround would be to set cold_reads_to_omit to 0.0, but we should limit the amount of entries in that map.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14339580" author="benedict" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 01:52:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;One way to do this might be, for each reader:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;find its overlaps;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;for each overlap, find &lt;em&gt;its&lt;/em&gt; set of overlaps, but discard these unless they&apos;re both larger than the one we&apos;ve most recently kept, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the estimated win is sufficient&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;remove all of the (first layer of) overlaps from the readers we visit, and continue with the next remaining reader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This gives us linear space complexity, but possibly still quadratic time complexity in the worst case, which is trickier to improve.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14339777" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 06:10:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The heapdump is still being uploaded, I find these Entry objects is indeed generated by SizeTieredCompactionStrategy.createOverlapChain. So do you still need the heapdump?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, in the node which has this issue , there is a table which has 8935 SSTables because this table is rarely being read.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14339828" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 07:11:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I submit a patch to fix this issue. &lt;br/&gt;
The idea is very simple: keep only one overlapChain in heap whose estimateCompactionGain &amp;lt; 0.7 and has the max size from any other overlapChains. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still O(N^2) time complexity and generates O(N^2) Entry objects, but useless Entry objects will be recycled because it only keeps at most O(N) Entry objects simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14339957" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 09:57:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I tested my patch in my node on 2.1.3. The patch works to me that it won&apos;t exhaust the heap although the gc pressure is high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if my understanding is not wrong, I think there is an improvement on this O(N^2) algorithm:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If createOverlapChain(a, overlapMap) return {a,b,c}, createOverlapChain(b, overlapMap) must also return {a,b,c}  because &quot;overlapping&quot; is a bidirectional relationship. So if we have already get {a,b,c} by SStableReader a, we needn&apos;t check b and c at all.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So this algorithm is O(N) both in time and space.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14339970" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:19:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I upload a new patch according to my new algorithm. We can compare three jstat outputs with different versions&apos; code in my cluster and see that v1 will not exhaust the heap but still have high gc pressure,  while v2&apos;s gc pressure is much lower.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14341781" author="benedict" created="Sat, 28 Feb 2015 21:10:03 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If createOverlapChain(a, overlapMap) return {a,b,c}, createOverlapChain(b, overlapMap) must also return {a,b,c} because &quot;overlapping&quot; is a bidirectional relationship. So if we have already get {a,b,c} by SStableReader a, we needn&apos;t check b and c at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is unfortunately not true. &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt; may overlap &lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;, but &lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt; may only overlap &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;, and not &lt;em&gt;c&lt;/em&gt;, for instance. I knocked together a patch on the plane with an average time complexity closer to O(N) but with worst case still O(N^2), and achieved by filtering out sets of readers that are wholly contained in other sets of overlapping readers. This may not be desirable, though, as it may be that by considering a smaller group of readers we see a larger yield from rewriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the best (medium term) solution to this complexity is to take ownership of the hyperloglog implementation and to build a structure that can yield overlaps efficiently from a multitude of hyperloglogs. If each hyperloglog bucket maintained an ordered map from bucket cardinality to the set of objects with that cardinality, an efficient search could be performed for overlap candidates. Within each bucket we could find the largest overlapping cardinalities, then take the intersection of these across all buckets, leaving the top-ranked partition overlaps, and applying correction for the amount of clustering column overlap between the candidates. We could then post-process to include any files that are almost wholly overlapping with this set of best overlaps. This is just a quick off-the-cuff sketch of a design, and no doubt there are better and more developed approaches along these lines.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14341913" author="jbellis" created="Sun, 1 Mar 2015 03:23:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s a lot of complexity for something whose benefit I&apos;m unclear on (I&apos;m talking about the &quot;ignore cold sstables&quot; feature).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the best of my knowledge, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-8635&quot; title=&quot;STCS cold sstable omission does not handle overwrites without reads&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-8635&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-8635&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has never been observed as a problem in the wild.  I&apos;d be in favor of reverting it and documenting &quot;don&apos;t enable cold sstable elision if you do a lot of overwrites.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14342007" author="yangzhe1991" created="Sun, 1 Mar 2015 07:10:02 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is unfortunately not true. a may overlap b and c, but b may only overlap a, and not c, for instance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your case is just like this, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;b -----
a    -----
c       ------
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in the code of createOverlapChain, all the overlapping SSTables with b will be pushed into the queue(for this case is a). When a is popped, all the overlapping SSTables with a(for this case is c) will also be pushed, until there is no more SSTables that overlap any of SSTables in overlapChain({a,b,c} for this case). Just like the comment on this function says: &quot;if we have 3 sstables, a, b, c where a overlaps with b, but not c and b overlaps with c, all sstables would be returned.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in graph theory, this function input &quot;Map&amp;lt;SSTableReader, Set&amp;lt;SSTableReader&amp;gt;&amp;gt; m&quot; as an undirected graph and &quot;SSTableReader s&quot; as a node of this graph, will return the connected component which contains this node. If this connected component is {a,b,c}, input a, b or c will return the same connected component.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14342032" author="yangzhe1991" created="Sun, 1 Mar 2015 07:41:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, if my algorithm is correct, my patch-v2 still need a 2-d loop to get the undirected graph. The space complexity is still O(N^2) if all the SSTables overlap each other and the graph is a complete graph. So I think there is a way to optimize it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use a 2-d bitmap matrix with the boolean which means whether coldSSTables&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;i&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; overlaps coldSSTables&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;j&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; to replace the 2-d collection of SSTableReader. Each HashMap$Entry need 32*8=256 bits but each bitmap boolean needs only 1 bit. This method may need more memory in some case, but need much less in the worst case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If my algorithm is not wrong, we can discuss if this optimization is needed or not &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14342128" author="benedict" created="Sun, 1 Mar 2015 10:40:49 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s a lot of complexity for something whose benefit I&apos;m unclear on (I&apos;m talking about the &quot;ignore cold sstables&quot; feature).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite possibly. I&apos;ve no idea how much use this is. The ability to select overlaps efficiently I assumed would be of wider applicability, but it looks like we don&apos;t use it anywhere else. However we might in future? The compaction exercise Marcus runs to intro devs to C* utilises it, so not sure if that is just a toy problem or of wider potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like the comment on this function says: &quot;if we have 3 sstables, a, b, c where a overlaps with b, but not c and b overlaps with c, all sstables would be returned.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good point. With that realisation, the code I knocked out on the plane is trivially made guaranteed O(n lg n) (for sorting, O&lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/thumbs_down.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; for the remainder of the work), with O&lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/thumbs_down.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; space complexity. It is untested, and could be refactored not to use an Iterable (which might be less code complexity), but I upload it &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/tree/8860-alt&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for you and Marcus to decide what to do with.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14342212" author="krummas" created="Sun, 1 Mar 2015 12:55:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;We should probably remove this feature alltogether (cold_reads_to_omit), using DTCS suits these kinds of workloads much better&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14343255" author="jbellis" created="Mon, 2 Mar 2015 15:18:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14344492" author="yangzhe1991" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2015 04:27:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I had a look at the code and I have some questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In L241, if previ==prevj, it will return an empty list? Should this be readers.subList(previ, prevj+1)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In L255, it will find the last sstable that overlaps sstable&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;i&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;, but sstable&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;j&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; may not have the biggest maxColumnNames so there may be another between i and j that overlaps sstable&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;j+1&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; but sstable&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;j&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; doesn&apos;t overlap &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;j+1&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;. The chain will be broken. I think we should record the sstable with the biggest maxColumnNames  from i to j and compare it with each sstable&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;j+1&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14344879" author="benedict" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2015 10:17:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yangzhe1991&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yangzhe1991&quot;&gt;yangzhe1991&lt;/a&gt; yes, both statements are correct, but it&apos;s kind of moot since it looks like we&apos;ll be removing it &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14344917" author="krummas" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2015 10:50:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;patch to remove option attached&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keeping the actual parameter in 2.1 if anyone has automated creating tables etc, but will remove entirely in 3.0&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14345431" author="thobbs" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2015 18:16:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1, patch looks good&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14346583" author="krummas" created="Wed, 4 Mar 2015 08:10:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;committed, thanks&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14348034" author="graham sanderson" created="Thu, 5 Mar 2015 02:51:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Note we are going to try a simpler patch on 2.1.3 (because we believe we are seeing this too, though our heaps are simply too big to dump reasonably it would seem). We&apos;re just reverting the cold_reads_to_omit default to 0.0, and adding logging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could probably change the schema for all tables to do this explicitly, but I haven&apos;t looked at whether this affects LCS L0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just an FYI to see if it helps us - we are seeing memory issue that we did not see in testing with 2.1.3, but may well be related to a proliferation of sstables&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14349220" author="rcoli" created="Thu, 5 Mar 2015 18:35:50 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should probably remove this feature alltogether (cold_reads_to_omit), using DTCS suits these kinds of workloads much better&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record (not that anyone asked... ;D) I am +1 here; seems like lots of complexity for a questionable potential win, and initial implementation has exposed some serious potential edge cases. DTCS FTW.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14497726" author="tommy_s" created="Thu, 16 Apr 2015 08:31:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;But this patch actually remove the parameter in 2.1. I created &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9203&quot; title=&quot;Removing cold_reads_to_omit is not backwards compatible&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9203&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9203&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14525163" author="yarongu" created="Sat, 2 May 2015 10:13:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;br/&gt;
In our testing environment we noticed that it causes a huge pressure on the GC with x4 cpu consumption than a version without the cold_reads_to_omit feature. Once we set it to 0, the problem solved. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310000">
                    <name>Duplicate</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is duplicated by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12785340">CASSANDRA-9033</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12821455">CASSANDRA-9203</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is related to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12767891">CASSANDRA-8635</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12702143" name="0001-remove-cold_reads_to_omit.patch" size="18638" author="marcuse" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2015 10:50:56 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12701321" name="8860-v2.txt" size="3000" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:19:39 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12701291" name="8860.txt" size="2529" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 07:11:39 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12700562" name="cassandra-env.sh" size="11105" author="yangzhe1991" created="Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:47:07 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12700565" name="cassandra.yaml" size="35254" author="yangzhe1991" created="Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:47:07 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12700563" name="jmap.txt" size="225338" author="yangzhe1991" created="Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:47:07 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12700564" name="jstack.txt" size="276484" author="yangzhe1991" created="Tue, 24 Feb 2015 19:47:07 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12701323" name="jstat-afterv1.txt" size="66896" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:19:39 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12701322" name="jstat-afterv2.txt" size="60093" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:19:39 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12701324" name="jstat-before.txt" size="37036" author="yangzhe1991" created="Fri, 27 Feb 2015 10:19:39 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>10.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[marcuse]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            10 years, 29 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i25znz:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>thobbs</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[thobbs]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12962"><![CDATA[Normal]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>