<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:52:29 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-9195] PITR commitlog replay only actually replays mutation every other time</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9195</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Version: Cassandra 2.1.4.374 | DSE 4.7.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main issue here is that the restore-cycle only replays the mutations&lt;br/&gt;
every other try.  On the first try, it will restore the snapshot as expected&lt;br/&gt;
and the cassandra system load will show that it&apos;s reading the mutations, but&lt;br/&gt;
they do not actually get replayed, and at the end you&apos;re left with only the&lt;br/&gt;
snapshot data (2k records).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you re-run the restore-cycle again, the commitlogs are replayed as expected,&lt;br/&gt;
and the data expected is present in the table (4k records, with a spot check of &lt;br/&gt;
record 4500, as it&apos;s in the commitlog but not the snapshot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then if you run the cycle again, it will fail.  Then again, and it will work. The work/&lt;br/&gt;
not work pattern continues.  Even re-running the commitlog replay a 2nd time, without&lt;br/&gt;
reloading the snapshot doesn&apos;t work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The load process is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Modify commitlog segment to 1mb&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Archive to directory&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;create keyspace/table&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;insert base data&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;initial snapshot&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;write more data&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;capture timestamp&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;write more data&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;final snapshot&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;copy commitlogs to 2nd location&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;modify cassandra-env to replay only specified keyspace&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;modify commitlog properties to restore from 2nd location, with noted timestamp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The restore cycle is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;truncate table&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;sstableload snapshot&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;flush&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;output data status&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;restart to replay commitlogs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;output data status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;====&lt;br/&gt;
See attached .py for a mostly automated reproduction scenario.  It expects DSE (and I found it with DSE 4.7.0-1), rather than &quot;actual&quot; Cassandra, but it&apos;s not using any DSE specific features.  The script looks for the configs in the DSE locations, but they&apos;re set at the top, and there&apos;s only 2 places where dse is restarted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12821212">CASSANDRA-9195</key>
            <summary>PITR commitlog replay only actually replays mutation every other time</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10002" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Normal</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="blambov">Branimir Lambov</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="jmoses">Jon Moses</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 15 Apr 2015 15:48:56 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:13:58 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 15:31:30 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>2.1.6</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>12</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14496661" author="jbellis" created="Wed, 15 Apr 2015 18:33:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;To clarify, this is a regression in 2.1?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14496662" author="brandon.williams" created="Wed, 15 Apr 2015 18:34:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I spoke with Jon and he confirmed it does not happen on 2.0&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14506733" author="blambov" created="Wed, 22 Apr 2015 09:47:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The reason for this happening is that a truncation record with the latest replay position in the existing SSTables is written to the system keyspace, and the following commit log restore skips over data that has been truncated. In the next run less data exists, hence the truncation position is earlier than the replayed commit log, and the stored mutations do get applied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commit log behaviour is correct, it should not be restoring truncated data. Thus I&apos;m not sure if the restore cycle in its current form is correct. It should be resetting the truncation data as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may be possible to make this part of the sstableload process, but before I do that I need to look closer at the process to see if it won&apos;t cause more serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14508427" author="jbellis" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 04:17:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, it sounds to me like the restore is being &quot;too clever.&quot;  Truncate means &quot;I don&apos;t want the data before now anymore.&quot;  PITR shouldn&apos;t truncate.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14508429" author="jbellis" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 04:18:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, it sounds to me like the restore is being &quot;too clever.&quot;  Truncate means &quot;I don&apos;t want the data before now anymore.&quot;  PITR shouldn&apos;t truncate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit: that said, it&apos;s valid to want to restore after a user incorrectly truncates.  I think you&apos;ll need to edit the system keyspace before restoring.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509108" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 14:01:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Restoring data you truncated would just be putting back the auto snapshot sstables.  For PITR  where the restore time is after truncate time I think the correct thing to do is is you want to only restore the stuff from after truncate until the PITR time.  If the PITR time is before the truncate time, then you would clear the truncate meta data before restoring.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509236" author="blambov" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:45:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached patch (comparison &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...blambov:9195-reset-truncation-2.1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) that adds a --reset-truncation-record option to sstableloader. The option deletes the truncation record for the column families being loaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The option should be added to the sstableloader call in the restore cycle. When this is in place the process completes successfully with the commitlog correctly replaying the data.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509246" author="nickmbailey" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:53:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I see how the truncation record is necessary when replaying commitlogs for a normal node restart, but I&apos;m trying to imagine the case where you would ever want that when replaying archived commitlogs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess if truncating tables is part of your application design? If thats the case we are trying to handle then simply storing the last truncate in the system tables doesn&apos;t really help since I&apos;ll be able to restore across all the previous truncates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me it seems like the correct solution is for replaying of archived commitlogs to ignore the truncate metadata or clear it automatically for the user, although manually clearing it can be a workaround until that gets implemented.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509255" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:56:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=barnie&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;barnie&quot;&gt;barnie&lt;/a&gt; confused why you are changing sstable loader and not commit log replay?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509266" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:01:02 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I see how the truncation record is necessary when replaying commitlogs for a normal node restart, but I&apos;m trying to imagine the case where you would ever want that when replaying archived commit logs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of replaying archived commitlogs is to restore your database to a certain point in time.  If that point in time is before the truncate happened, then yes, you would want to ignore the truncate.  If that point in time is &lt;b&gt;after&lt;/b&gt; the truncate happened, then you want to only replay data from truncate time to restore time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to restore the data you truncated, then you shouldn&apos;t be using PITR restore for that, you should be putting the sstables from the auto snapshot back in place.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509273" author="nickmbailey" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:05:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jjordan&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jjordan&quot;&gt;jjordan&lt;/a&gt; Ok right makes sense, but as I mentioned it appears we are only storing the latest truncate metadata so if that is the behavior we expect out of the database then it is broken since we forget about any past truncates whenever we do a new one. It seems we should be writing truncate records to the commitlog and then processing those correctly when doing the replay.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509278" author="blambov" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:08:27 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Branimir Lambov confused why you are changing sstable loader and not commit log replay?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because commitlog is acting correctly, it should not replay truncated data regardless of where it comes from. In this particular case sstable loader is leaving the table in a bad state; rather than try to live with it I prefer to correct it at the origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your goal is to restore the data you truncated, then you shouldn&apos;t be using PITR restore for that, you should be putting the sstables from the auto snapshot back in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The PITR process &lt;em&gt;includes&lt;/em&gt; a truncation step. What I am doing here is giving PITR the option to correctly continue after that step.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509286" author="nickmbailey" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:16:11 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because commitlog is acting correctly, it should not replay truncated data regardless of where it comes from. In this particular case sstable loader is leaving the table in a bad state; rather than try to live with it I prefer to correct it at the origin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PITR process includes a truncation step. What I am doing here is giving PITR the option to correctly continue after that step.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think this is right. The attached reproduction step does include a truncation step but that step is just there to clear the database before verifying that restore works. It could be replaced with drop and recreate (and then you wouldn&apos;t see this bug). But in any case, users may end up truncating and then regretting it and trying to restore from commitlogs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think sstableloader is the right place for this because restoring from a snapshot is not required for point in time restore. You can simply archive every commitlog from the start rather than ever taking snapshots if you want. Then if you go and replay those commitlogs up to some time before the truncation C* should recognize that the replay is strictly before any truncation took place and let things replay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I still think it seems like truncation records should exist in the commitlogs themselves, or at the very least be a historical list of truncations.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509289" author="mbulman" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:18:01 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It could be replaced with drop and recreate (and then you wouldn&apos;t see this bug)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fyi, you would not see this bug, but you would see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9179&quot; title=&quot;Unable to &amp;quot;point in time&amp;quot; restore if table/cf has been recreated&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9179&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9179&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; instead&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509353" author="blambov" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 16:55:37 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then if you go and replay those commitlogs up to some time before the truncation C* should recognize that the replay is strictly before any truncation took place and let things replay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a big problem with this: you now have a table with a lot of data that is before the table&apos;s known truncation time. This violates assumptions, may cause all sorts of trouble, and is generally a state that should not be tolerated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus a truncation record reset has to be part of the process. And if it is present, it doesn&apos;t make any sense to have it anywhere else than at the start, which in turn allows the commitlog to operate correctly. To my limited understanding the restore was started by the sstableloader call, hence I put the flag there. As now I see this is not always the case, perhaps a standalone reset-truncation-record utility is required?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509380" author="jbellis" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 17:12:17 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;it appears we are only storing the latest truncate metadata so if that is the behavior we expect out of the database then it is broken since we forget about any past truncates whenever we do a new one&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree.  However, fixing that is probably out of scope for 2.1.  Let&apos;s open another ticket for that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509558" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 18:33:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=barnie&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;barnie&quot;&gt;barnie&lt;/a&gt; The -D is what triggers it to happen on C* startup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;-Dcassandra.replayList=&amp;lt;ks.table&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="14509729" author="blambov" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 20:30:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So the suggested approach to solve this problem is to clear the truncation record for the specified tables on startup if the &lt;tt&gt;cassandra.replayList&lt;/tt&gt; definition is set?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What about the case where the data is loaded from a snapshot and no commitlog is replayed? Is that a valid action, and would it not also lead to an invalid state (i.e. data present before truncation record)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that the best course of action is to have both an option to sstableloader as well as automatic clear on startup. Let me know if this sounds good (or if anyone has something better in mind) and I&apos;ll implement it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14509814" author="nickmbailey" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 21:12:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think we need to worry about sstableloader. First, it isn&apos;t affected by the truncate metadata because it just streams the sstables directly to the nodes. Also, when you load a snapshot, you are loading data at a specific point in time rather than a range of time. Presumably when you go to load a snapshot you know that you want exactly the state of the node/cluster at that point in time. Any sort of behavior where truncating now and then loading a snapshot taken before the truncation, but not having any of that data present would be very strange IMO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that we are going to fix it The Right Way in 3.0, I&apos;d say just an automatic clear when replaying archived commitlogs is sufficient for 2.1. Can we also document on this ticket the workaround for older versions? Specifically what table/row/column needs to be wiped out before replaying archived commitlogs?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14510139" author="jbellis" created="Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:29:06 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d say just an automatic clear when replaying archived commitlogs is sufficient for 2.1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, not quite.  I think Jeremiah had it right earlier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of replaying archived commitlogs is to restore your database to a certain point in time. If that point in time is before the truncate happened, then yes, you would want to ignore the truncate. If that point in time is after the truncate happened, then you want to only replay data from truncate time to restore time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately since I am proposing we avoid storing full TRUNCATE history until 3.0, we may replay &quot;extra&quot; data that should have been left out.  (Suppose that we TRUNCATE at 21:00 and 22:00.  We restore to 21:30.  If we had the historical record, we would ignore data before 21:00.)  But I think this is an acceptable limitation for 2.1.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14510769" author="blambov" created="Fri, 24 Apr 2015 10:16:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;New patch attached (comparison &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...blambov:9195-replaylist-2.1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). Commitlog replayer will now clear truncation record if the restore point in time is earlier than the truncation for any table specified in cassandra.replayList.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14511302" author="nickmbailey" created="Fri, 24 Apr 2015 16:26:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So you can replay archived commitlogs without specifying a list of keyspaces and column families and it will restore everything. I think we should handle that case as well here.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14514352" author="blambov" created="Mon, 27 Apr 2015 16:01:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...blambov:9195-replaylist-2.1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Branch&lt;/a&gt; updated with new version that also resets truncation record when replayList is not specified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not convinced this is safe, though. It also affects system tables (e.g. system.compactions_in_progress).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14517693" author="JIRAUSER308715" created="Tue, 28 Apr 2015 19:11:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 looks good to me.  Talked with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jmoses&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jmoses&quot;&gt;jmoses&lt;/a&gt; and his testing works as expected now.  Did someone make a JIRA about storing multiple truncation records so we could possibly do this the right way when someone wants to restore to a time in between two truncates?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14521741" author="iamaleksey" created="Thu, 30 Apr 2015 16:13:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed to 2.1 as &lt;tt&gt;1f6bf3651a76f0ae2c61ee7fd994573f249e78d5&lt;/tt&gt;. Had to do some modifications on trunk, to avoid blocking others (realised it didn&apos;t merge well only after I already pushed to 2.1).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&apos;d be grateful if you (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=blambov&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;blambov&quot;&gt;blambov&lt;/a&gt;) could look at trunk now and double check my merge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, some tests would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14523040" author="blambov" created="Fri, 1 May 2015 10:56:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attached patch adds two new tests of truncation and point-in-time restore. Comparison &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...blambov:9195-tests-2.1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14523064" author="blambov" created="Fri, 1 May 2015 11:25:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The trunk changes you did are ok, but I&apos;d also remove the replayFilter argument from two methods in CommitLogReplayer where it is no longer necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attached a version of the new tests built on trunk, which also includes this change. Comparison &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...blambov:9195-newtests-trunk&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14523437" author="iamaleksey" created="Fri, 1 May 2015 16:50:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Branimir. Committed to 2.1 as &lt;tt&gt;f43efaa1bdeec1057a8097fdb5ab62b4c9c19e67&lt;/tt&gt; and merged into trunk, with your further improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12727875" name="9195-2.1-v2.patch" size="3256" author="blambov" created="Fri, 24 Apr 2015 10:16:42 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12729739" name="9195-newtest-2.1.txt" size="8112" author="blambov" created="Fri, 1 May 2015 10:56:18 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12729747" name="9195-newtest-trunk.txt" size="12244" author="blambov" created="Fri, 1 May 2015 11:25:29 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12727633" name="9195-v2.1.patch" size="9033" author="blambov" created="Thu, 23 Apr 2015 15:42:37 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12725611" name="loader.py" size="8501" author="jmoses" created="Wed, 15 Apr 2015 15:49:15 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>5.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[blambov]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            10 years, 29 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i2dajb:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>jjordan</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[jjordan]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12962"><![CDATA[Normal]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>