<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 22:55:33 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-9863] NIODataInputStream has problems on trunk</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9863</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;As the title says, there is cases where method calls to NIODataInputStream, at least &lt;tt&gt;readVInt&lt;/tt&gt; calls can loop forever. This is possibly only a problem for vints where the code tries to read 8 bytes minimum but there is less than that available, and in that sense is related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=benedict&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;benedict&quot;&gt;benedict&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s observation in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9708&quot; title=&quot;Serialize ClusteringPrefixes in batches&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9708&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9708&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but it is more serious than said observation because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;this can happen even if the buffer passed to NIODataInputStream ctor has more than 8 bytes available, and hence I&apos;m relatively confident &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=benedict&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;benedict&quot;&gt;benedict&lt;/a&gt;&apos;s fix in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9708&quot; title=&quot;Serialize ClusteringPrefixes in batches&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9708&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9708&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is not enough.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;this doesn&apos;t necessarily fail cleanly by raising assertions, this can loop forever (which is much harder to debug).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Due of that, and because that is at least one of the cause of &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9764&quot; title=&quot;dtest for many UPDATE batches, low contention fails on trunk&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9764&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9764&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I think the problem warrants a specific ticket (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9708&quot; title=&quot;Serialize ClusteringPrefixes in batches&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9708&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9708&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that is).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the exact reason of this is looping is if &lt;tt&gt;readVInt&lt;/tt&gt; is called but the buffer has less than 8 byte remaining (again, the buffer had more initially). In that case, &lt;tt&gt;readMinimum(8, 1)&lt;/tt&gt; is called and it calls &lt;tt&gt;readNext()&lt;/tt&gt; in a loop. Within &lt;tt&gt;readNext()&lt;/tt&gt;, the buffer (which has &lt;tt&gt;buf.position() == 0 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; buf.hasRemaining()&lt;/tt&gt;) is actually unchanged (through a very weird dance of setting the position to the limit, then the limit to the capacity, and then flipping the buffer which resets everything to what it was), and because &lt;tt&gt;rbc&lt;/tt&gt; is the &lt;tt&gt;emptyReadableByteChannel&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;rbc.read(buf)&lt;/tt&gt; does nothing and always return &lt;tt&gt;-1&lt;/tt&gt;. Back in &lt;tt&gt;readMinimum&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;read == -1&lt;/tt&gt; but &lt;tt&gt;remaining &amp;gt;= require&lt;/tt&gt; (and &lt;tt&gt;remaining&lt;/tt&gt; never changes), and hence the forever looping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, not sure what the best fix is because I&apos;m not fully familiar with that code, but that does leads me to a 2nd point: &lt;tt&gt;NIODataInputSttream&lt;/tt&gt; can IMHO use a bit of additional/better comments. I won&apos;t pretend having tried very hard to understand the whole class, so there is probably some lack of effort, but at least a few things felt like they should clarified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Provided I understand &lt;tt&gt;readNext()&lt;/tt&gt; correctly, it only make sense when we do have a &lt;tt&gt;ReadableByteChannel&lt;/tt&gt; (and the fact that it&apos;s not the case sounds like the bug). If that&apos;s the case, this should be explicitly documented and probably asserted. As as an aside, I wonder if using &lt;tt&gt;rbc == null&lt;/tt&gt; when we don&apos;t have wouldn&apos;t be better: if we don&apos;t have one, we shouldn&apos;t try to use it, and having a &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt; would make things fail loudly if we do.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I&apos;m not exactly sure what &lt;tt&gt;readMinimum&lt;/tt&gt; arguments do. I&apos;d have expected at least one to be called &quot;minimum&quot;, and an explanation of the meaning of the other one.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;prepareReadPaddedPrimitive&lt;/tt&gt; says that it &quot;Add padding if requested&quot; but there is seemingly no argument that trigger the &quot;if requested part&quot;. Also unclear what that padding is about in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As a final point, it looks like the case where &lt;tt&gt;NIODataInputStream&lt;/tt&gt; is constructed with a &lt;tt&gt;ByteBuffer&lt;/tt&gt; (rather than a &lt;tt&gt;ReadableByteChannel&lt;/tt&gt;) seems to be completely untested by the unit tests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12846857">CASSANDRA-9863</key>
            <summary>NIODataInputStream has problems on trunk</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10000" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/critical.svg">Urgent</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="aweisberg">Ariel Weisberg</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="slebresne">Sylvain Lebresne</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:38:48 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:31:03 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 24 Jul 2015 10:21:30 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>3.0 alpha 1</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Legacy/Local Write-Read Paths</component>
                    <component>Legacy/Streaming and Messaging</component>
                    <component>Local/Compaction</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>2</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="14636716" author="benedict" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 10:56:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That looks like actually a very simple bug: we should return immediately if &lt;tt&gt;read == -1&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;remaining &amp;gt;= attempt&lt;/tt&gt;. This is a different problem to the one in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9708&quot; title=&quot;Serialize ClusteringPrefixes in batches&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9708&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9708&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The testing should certainly have caught this (as should I in review), as it&apos;s a pretty basic requirement of the contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comments can certainly always be improved, although it isn&apos;t always clear upfront where the confusion will be (more of a problem when both reviewer and author are more closely involved in development, as in this case). In the case of &lt;tt&gt;readMinimum&lt;/tt&gt; the hope was that the parameter names would be suffiicent. Both parameters are minima, but one is &lt;em&gt;enforced&lt;/em&gt; and the other is &lt;em&gt;desired&lt;/em&gt;. i.e. we &lt;tt&gt;attempt&lt;/tt&gt; to read a minimum, and fail if we get less than &lt;tt&gt;required&lt;/tt&gt;. Perhaps somebody else should take review of updates to the comments in this instance, to ensure we don&apos;t repeat the mistake of too much knowledge weakening the explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14636778" author="slebresne" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 12:03:57 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That looks like actually a very simple bug&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might be. But I still find &lt;tt&gt;readNext()&lt;/tt&gt; fairly dodgy for the case where we don&apos;t have a &lt;tt&gt;ReadableByteChannel&lt;/tt&gt;. First because in that case we don&apos;t refill anything, but also because it&apos;s a costly no-op in that case but that&apos;s far from evident from the code (the &lt;tt&gt;buf.limit(buf.capacity())&lt;/tt&gt; line is particularly weird at first glance since in that case (where the buffer you use has been externally provided), you should absolutely not read/write after the initial limit (not saying that&apos;s what we do, the &lt;tt&gt;flip()&lt;/tt&gt; makes it ok, but it makes understanding harder than it should)). As a minor aside, I would have renamed that method &lt;tt&gt;refill()&lt;/tt&gt; or something since readNext() make it sounds like it&apos;s returning what it reads which it isn&apos;t. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it would make me happy if we could use that ticket to also fix that (maybe by having readNext() first check if we&apos;re in the &quot;no &lt;tt&gt;ReadableByteChannel&lt;/tt&gt;&quot; case upfront and directly exit with -1 in that case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a different problem to the one in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9708&quot; title=&quot;Serialize ClusteringPrefixes in batches&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9708&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9708&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;True, but I&apos;d still prefer fix all &lt;tt&gt;NIODataInputStream&lt;/tt&gt; problems we have here since that&apos;s a more targeted issue (I&apos;ll rename the issue even to make that more clear).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14636788" author="benedict" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 12:15:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s a &quot;costly&quot; no-op that under correct usage we never incur, but without any code complexity results in correct behaviour under incorrect usage, i.e. throwing an exception (except in this case, which is absolutely nothing to do with &lt;tt&gt;readNext&lt;/tt&gt;, so modifying it off the back of it does not seem a justifiable course of action). The alternative is making every &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt; usage that does perform this more costly and - more importantly - more confusing, as the code you&apos;re suggesting entails more special casing. I don&apos;t want to try and ensure we miss a null or some other behaviour somewhere where we misinterpret correct behaviour on empty, when we can just always get that correct behaviour for free by providing an empty RBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the ByteBuffer interface itself being ugly to work with, re: flips, etc. I agree, but there&apos;s really not much to be done about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;edit: Hmm. Rethinking that, you&apos;re right that vints change this a little. Not sure they change it often enough to be worth modifying the code and incurring that cost/risk of having null / broken behaviour on empty, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;edit2: Except no, it doesn&apos;t. If we go with the slightly modified approach to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9708&quot; title=&quot;Serialize ClusteringPrefixes in batches&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9708&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9708&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I was planning to propose, which is always ensuring there are at least 8 bytes spare at the end of any ByteBuffer. So we never have to extend and call the empty RBC.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14636833" author="benedict" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 12:35:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s worth pointing out that the cost is also not really that high, compared to every other cost involved here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it looks like we also barely use the RBC anywhere anymore, so I&apos;m actually perfectly cool with making it null in this case. I thought it was exposed, but I must be remembering a much older variant of the class and its uses.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14636855" author="slebresne" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 12:39:03 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m actually perfectly cool with making it null in this case&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That, and asserting that readNext() is never called if it&apos;s null (plus of course the fix to make it so it&apos;s true) is all I&apos;m asking. My remark about &quot;costly&quot; no-op was not so much in term of CPU usage, than in term of cost to the comprehension of the class (and that method in particular).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14636887" author="benedict" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 13:14:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Well, it actually would be necessary to call it if it&apos;s &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt; in some circumstances, because we may have a large buffer that has a vint right at the end, that has no spare room to increase the buffer size beyond for cheaply performing vint reads at the end. In this case we would need to confirm we haven&apos;t got more to read - the easiest way being to return -1 if it&apos;s &lt;tt&gt;null&lt;/tt&gt; in &lt;tt&gt;readNext&lt;/tt&gt; as you previously suggested. Of course, we could enforce this earlier in &lt;tt&gt;readPaddedPrimitive&lt;/tt&gt;, but we need to shuffle our data back in this case, so we really are best leaving this to &lt;tt&gt;readNext&lt;/tt&gt; I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we&apos;re here, I notice that at some point we changed &lt;tt&gt;readNext&lt;/tt&gt;&apos;s shuffling to use a duplicated &lt;tt&gt;ByteBuffer&lt;/tt&gt;, which is probably much more costly than just looping ourselves calling put/get (especially since this is all it does). Or calling &lt;tt&gt;FastByteOperations.copy&lt;/tt&gt; (and making this faster for this case, since &lt;tt&gt;copyMemory&lt;/tt&gt; is costly).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14637637" author="aweisberg" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 21:13:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Waiting on tests for patch available, but you can see what I did to address the issues here. You should get accurate EOF behavior in all cases even when there is padding. It doesn&apos;t throw an unique exception for corrupt/invalid varint just EOF exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...aweisberg:C-9863?expand=1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...aweisberg:C-9863?expand=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14637755" author="benedict" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 22:19:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks. Mostly looks good. However I must admit that now I&apos;m looking at it again, I&apos;m more than a little worried that we mutate the buffer by shuffling if we run out of room at the end for reading our vint. In the case where we may have future (or concurrent) accesses of the buffer, this would corrupt our readers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we may have to go back to the drawing board, and most likely offer a slow path (after all our prior work to avoid it). Of course, if we can extend the ByteBuffer in the constructor we can avoid this, but this won&apos;t always be possible.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14637783" author="aweisberg" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 22:41:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hmmm yeah... the shuffling is absolutely evil. It would do it for EOF as well. Seems like we need to differentiate between fixed and non-fixed buffers for real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think a derived class that copies to a thread-local to provide padding and throws EOF immediately without shuffling would be good?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14637892" author="benedict" created="Wed, 22 Jul 2015 23:11:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Some ugliness there, though. Mostly: how do we guarantee there aren&apos;t two streams being read by the same thread? Or do we copy into the TL BB afresh each time we perform a read primitive? Or perhaps we have a queue that we return them to on close?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d be tempted to inflate that latter approach to handle the case where our provided buffer is too small as well.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14638960" author="aweisberg" created="Thu, 23 Jul 2015 15:06:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I updated the branch. There is a derived class for wrapping fixed immutable buffers without a channel and it ensures that no shuffling takes place by overriding readNext(). It also throws AssertionError if it gets far enough to try reading from the empty channel. You should never see the AssertionError since read next always returns -1 and doesn&apos;t touch the channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For varints if there are &amp;lt; 9 bytes remaining in the buffer it uses the slow path in VIntCoding that reads byte at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14639090" author="benedict" created="Thu, 23 Jul 2015 16:26:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Mostly LGTM, however we can now call buf.get() directly (instead of readByte), and you&apos;re using non-idiomatic array declarations.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14639106" author="aweisberg" created="Thu, 23 Jul 2015 16:42:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Tests look good in Cassci&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...aweisberg:C-9863?expand=1&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/trunk...aweisberg:C-9863?expand=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14639160" author="aweisberg" created="Thu, 23 Jul 2015 17:20:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;I don&apos;t think I introduced new non-idiomatic lines. Which files do you want me to refactor to make them idiomatic?&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Nevermind found what you are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="14639379" author="benedict" created="Thu, 23 Jul 2015 19:10:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks. I&apos;ve pushed a single line change to use &lt;tt&gt;DataInputBuffer&lt;/tt&gt; in &lt;tt&gt;ReadResponse&lt;/tt&gt;. I&apos;ll wait on CI before committing this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310050">
                    <name>Regression</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="breaks">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12843657">CASSANDRA-9764</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[aweisberg]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            10 years, 17 weeks, 5 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i2hjrr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_10022" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:userpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewer</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>benedict</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[benedict]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12963"><![CDATA[Critical]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>