<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 23:12:03 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-14568] Static collection deletions are corrupted in 3.0 -&gt; 2.{1,2} messages</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-14568</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2.1 and 2.2, row and complex deletions were represented as range tombstones. &#160;LegacyLayout is our compatibility layer, that translates the relevant RT patterns in 2.1/2.2 to row/complex deletions in 3.0, and vice versa. &#160;Unfortunately, it does not handle the special case of static row deletions, they are treated as regular row deletions. Since static rows are themselves never directly deleted, the only issue is with collection deletions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collection deletions in 2.1/2.2 were encoded as a range tombstone, consisting of a sequence of the clustering keys&#8217; data for the affected row, followed by the bytes representing the name of the collection column. &#160;STATIC_CLUSTERING contains zero clusterings, so by treating the deletion as for a regular row, zero clusterings are written to precede the column name of the erased collection, so the column name is written at position zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can exhibit itself in at least two ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If the type of your first clustering key is a variable width type, new deletes will begin appearing covering the clustering key represented by the column name.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;If you have multiple clustering keys, you will receive a RT covering all those rows with a matching first clustering key.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;This RT will be valid as far as the system is concerned, and go undetected unless there are outside data quality checks in place.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Otherwise, an invalid size of data will be written to the clustering and sent over the network to the 2.1 node.
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The 2.1/2.2 node will handle this just fine, even though the record is junk. &#160;Since it is a deletion covering impossible data, there will be no user-API visible effect. &#160;But if received as a write from a 3.0 node, it will dutifully persist the junk record.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The 3.0 node that originally sent this junk, may later coordinate a read of the partition, and will notice a digest mismatch, read-repair and serialize the junk to disk&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The sstable containing this record is now corrupt; the deserialization expects fixed-width data, but it encounters too many (or too few) bytes, and is now at an incorrect position to read its structural information&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;(Alternatively when the 2.1&#160;node is&#160;upgraded this will occur on eventual compaction)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13172138">CASSANDRA-14568</key>
            <summary>Static collection deletions are corrupted in 3.0 -&gt; 2.{1,2} messages</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10000" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/critical.svg">Urgent</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="benedict">Benedict Elliott Smith</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="benedict">Benedict Elliott Smith</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 22:31:03 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 2 Aug 2019 02:47:59 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 10:28:24 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>3.0.17</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>3.11.3</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Messaging/Internode</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>7</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16543875" author="benedict" created="Fri, 13 Jul 2018 23:35:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/tree/CASSANDRA-14568&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16545241" author="iamaleksey" created="Mon, 16 Jul 2018 14:09:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1, ship it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16545537" author="benedict" created="Mon, 16 Jul 2018 17:44:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed as&#160;d52c7b8c59,&#160;31d5d870f9 and&#160;d3a994b105&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tests were run against &lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/workflow-run/c818c58a-83e3-4731-89d7-ab0b04d26d62&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;circleci&lt;/a&gt;&#160;(unfortunately right now this link is down); this showed some failing auth dtests, but these&#160;code paths were unaffected by this patch and I confirmed they pass locally.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16581274" author="slebresne" created="Wed, 15 Aug 2018 15:59:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry I&apos;m a bit slow to check this one, but I don&apos;t think the fix here is correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, while it makes sure complex deletions are handled for static rows, I believe it also doesn&apos;t encode the &quot;composite&quot; in the same way than 2.x was (the added unit test passes because it only check the encoding round-trips, which it does, but I believe things don&apos;t work properly if tested against a true 2.1 node).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namely, the encoding of the &quot;clustering prefix&quot; (what comes before the column name) for a static cell in 2.x uses N empty components (see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-2.1/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/composites/CompoundSparseCellNameType.java#L68-L69&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), where N is the table clustering size, while the patch uses an empty clustering (that is, put the column name as first component, no matter how many clustering the table has; see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L210-L214&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and, in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L2394-L2400&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;serializeCompound&lt;/a&gt;, there will be no clustering elements since &lt;tt&gt;STATIC_PREFIX&lt;/tt&gt; has size 0 and &lt;tt&gt;CompositeType.Builder&lt;/tt&gt; does not compensate for that in any way). &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16581429" author="benedict" created="Wed, 15 Aug 2018 18:07:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the input, when fixing this I had indeed assumed the issue was only with deserialization on 3.0, not serialization also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can now see there is an existing method for creating a staticBound, although it&apos;s not presently clear to me if it was ever plausibly invoked, so it will take a while to corroborate that we don&apos;t break any other assumptions by setting the LegacyLayout.bound to something that breaks the 3.0 definition of a static clustering.  AFAICT, we do directly reference it in places where the distinction matters, so we may have to introduce a legacyBound and modernBound for which a distinction is only made in the static case.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16582108" author="slebresne" created="Thu, 16 Aug 2018 07:50:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s absolutely possible I&apos;m missing some problem, as god knows those backward compatibility issues often comes with nasty surprises, but I don&apos;t think the problem is too hard to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, &lt;tt&gt;LegacyBound&lt;/tt&gt; is only here for backward compatibility and never used by 3.0 before being converting first, so I&apos;m sure to understand what you mean by &quot;(setting it) to something that breaks the 3.0 definition of a static clustering&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe we should simply make sure that when encoding to 2.x a &lt;tt&gt;STATIC_CLUSTERING&lt;/tt&gt;, we append &quot;clustering size&quot; empty values before adding the rest (the column name), and when decoding, we assume those empty values are here (but ignore them). This is what we do for &quot;cell names&quot; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L287-L291&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L329-L330&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and to the best of my knowledge is working properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, I &quot;think&quot; we need to do the 2 following changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;revert the change made by this patch in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L210-L215&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;LegacyLayout.decodeBound&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;make sure that in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L2394-L2400&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;LegacyLayout.serializeCompound&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and &lt;tt&gt;serializeSizeCompound&lt;/tt&gt;), the static case is specialized to automatically add the empty values, which might possibly be better handler directly within &lt;tt&gt;CompositeType.Builder&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16582147" author="benedict" created="Thu, 16 Aug 2018 08:10:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&apos;t the &quot;more correct&quot; place to change it be &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/blob/cassandra-3.0/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/LegacyLayout.java#L803&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;in the bound construction&lt;/a&gt;?  Presumably the LegacyBound.bound property should be correctly legacy-fied so that any other LegacyLayout code correctly interprets / sorts it?  This is what I was planning on with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/commit/5b6742a7a6104bbd88d784db4d3bf7cd990cf057#diff-1a4af2aebd51e301cf0e73126722a8a4R805&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;my wip branch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My concern was that LRT.start.bound is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/blob/14568-2/src/java/org/apache/cassandra/db/UnfilteredDeserializer.java#L728&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;directly referenced in UnfilteredDeserializer when converting to a RTMarker&lt;/a&gt;.  I realise in the light of morning that this would not be a problem during &lt;em&gt;serialization&lt;/em&gt;, but maybe this is another bug in deserialization?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16582245" author="benedict" created="Thu, 16 Aug 2018 09:07:56 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My concern was that LRT.start.bound is directly referenced in UnfilteredDeserializer when converting to a RTMarker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm.  Thinking on it some more, I guess this is not a problem due to the fact that we never (in any extant version) actually issue any deletions that (in 3.0) would be represented as RTs spanning static rows, so the problematic cases &lt;b&gt;should&lt;/b&gt; all be converted to collection tombstones only.  I will add some comments to LegacyLayout elaborating the inconsistencies of modern/legacy static clusterings as part of the patch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I&apos;m now comfortable with fixing either location, I think.  Though I need to code dive a bit more to be absolutely certain.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16582286" author="benedict" created="Thu, 16 Aug 2018 09:47:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;OK. So, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/commits/14568-2&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is may second attempt at fixing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of adding improved assertion logic, I realised we might have another bug around dropped static collection column, that could have resulted in decoding a static collection deletion as a whole-static-row deletion (with unknown semantics, since I vaguely recall that our correctness in some places depends on there being no such deletions).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence: if on looking up the collectionNameBytes, we found no collectionName (due, for instance, to it having been dropped), we would be left with a only a complete static row bound to construct.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I should split this fix into a separate ticket, for a separate CHANGES.txt mention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We clearly need to introduce some upgrade dtests to cover these cases as well&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16591668" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 24 Aug 2018 13:42:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the slow turn over. Last version lgtm, though as mention, upgrade dtests would be great to validate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Re: dropped static collection columns, the bug looks legit as well so kudos for noticing that. And I personally don&apos;t mind committing it here directly.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16591674" author="benedict" created="Fri, 24 Aug 2018 13:46:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Great, thanks for taking the time to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;upgrade dtests would be great to validate it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, absolutely.  That will have to wait until things settle down in a couple of weeks,  after the freeze.  I may commit this ahead of then, just so we have the bug (at least much more probably) fixed for anyone who might need it more urgently.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16591837" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 24 Aug 2018 15:49:31 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I may commit this ahead of then&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wfm. Maybe have &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=iamaleksey&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;iamaleksey&quot;&gt;iamaleksey&lt;/a&gt; check our logic one more time but otherwise +1 from me.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16595319" author="iamaleksey" created="Tue, 28 Aug 2018 17:12:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Looks good to me as well. Sorry for failing to spot this in the first place. Old memories are fading.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16613724" author="benedict" created="Thu, 13 Sep 2018 16:25:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/tree/14568&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;3.0&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/workflow-run/70397395-3585-4b4c-904f-a55c070cf359&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;CI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks both for your review.  I have split out &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-14749&quot; title=&quot;Collection Deletions for Dropped Columns in 2.1/3.0 mixed-mode can delete rows&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-14749&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-14749&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and pushed an updated patch simply missing this part.  If either of you could give a quick cursory +1, I&apos;ll commit them both.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16614518" author="slebresne" created="Fri, 14 Sep 2018 08:36:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 on this one.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16614640" author="benedict" created="Fri, 14 Sep 2018 10:28:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks.  Committed as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/commit/68dbeb34c9404ee3cd7db00cc112e27c9a4b1f6f&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;68dbeb34c9404ee3cd7db00cc112e27c9a4b1f6f&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[benedict]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12313825" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:cascadingselect">
                        <customfieldname>Bug Category</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                                    <customfieldvalue key="12982" cascade-level=""><![CDATA[Correctness]]></customfieldvalue>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12986" cascade-level="1"><![CDATA[Recoverable Corruption / Loss]]></customfieldvalue>
            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313821" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Complexity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12966"><![CDATA[Challenging]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313822" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Discovered By</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12975"><![CDATA[Code Inspection]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            7 years, 9 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i3vw0f:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[aleksey]]></customfieldvalue>
        <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[slebresne]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12963"><![CDATA[Critical]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:version">
                        <customfieldname>Since Version</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12333891">3.0.0</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>