<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 23:13:22 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-15059] Gossiper#markAlive can race with Gossiper#markDead</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-15059</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gossiper class is not threadsafe and assumes all state changes happen in a single thread (the gossip stage). Gossiper#convict, however, can be called from the GossipTasks thread. This creates a race where calls to Gossiper#markAlive and Gossiper#markDead can interleave, corrupting gossip state. Gossiper#assassinateEndpoint has a similar problem, being called from the mbean server thread.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13223180">CASSANDRA-15059</key>
            <summary>Gossiper#markAlive can race with Gossiper#markDead</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10002" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/minor.svg">Normal</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="bdeggleston">Blake Eggleston</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="bdeggleston">Blake Eggleston</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 19:59:32 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 15 May 2020 08:00:00 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:28:26 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>3.0.19</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>3.11.5</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>4.0-alpha1</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>4.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Cluster/Gossip</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>8</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16799342" author="bdeggleston" created="Fri, 22 Mar 2019 20:51:37 +0000"  >&lt;div class=&apos;table-wrap&apos;&gt;
&lt;table class=&apos;confluenceTable&apos;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&apos;confluenceTd&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bdeggleston/cassandra/tree/15059-3.0&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&apos;confluenceTd&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/workflow-run/a863b2af-db01-4f7a-b059-a0ed2496f286&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&apos;confluenceTd&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bdeggleston/cassandra/tree/15059-3.11&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;3.11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&apos;confluenceTd&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/workflow-run/c271d33b-92c4-4579-80ce-cab20f4aac6c&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&apos;confluenceTd&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bdeggleston/cassandra/tree/15059-trunk&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;trunk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&apos;confluenceTd&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://circleci.com/workflow-run/d476de41-c374-40f1-bdae-b464149b703a&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;circle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16801208" author="aweisberg" created="Mon, 25 Mar 2019 22:49:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/cassandra-3.0...bdeggleston:15059-3.0?expand=1#diff-8be666c70553b1f0017a01458c490f47R332&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;You don&apos;t need to create a ListenableFutureTask you can just &lt;tt&gt;submit&lt;/tt&gt; the &lt;tt&gt;Runnable&lt;/tt&gt; to the &lt;tt&gt;ExecutorService&lt;/tt&gt; and it will return a &lt;tt&gt;Future&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/cassandra-3.0...bdeggleston:15059-3.0?expand=1#diff-8be666c70553b1f0017a01458c490f47R323&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;This creates significant risk of deadlock if the Gossiper ends up needing to acquire something owned by the thread submitting the task. Document that risk here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is extremely fragile. &lt;tt&gt;Gossiper.markDead&lt;/tt&gt; calls out to every subscriber. Also we call into &lt;tt&gt;Gossiper.convict&lt;/tt&gt; from &lt;tt&gt;FailureDetector&lt;/tt&gt; but then call back out to &lt;tt&gt;FailureDetector&lt;/tt&gt; from &lt;tt&gt;Gossiper&lt;/tt&gt;. I am only just beginning to track down where we call in and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Gossiper.assassinate&lt;/tt&gt; also calls out to various things via &lt;tt&gt;Gossiper.handleMajorStateChange&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not 100% on the right way to tease this out to be a good design. If this action is occurring asynchronously then it should be explicit and return a ListenableFuture that is either ignored if it can really occur asynchronously without issue, waited on safely while not holding any locks, or execution resumed later by attaching a listener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fan in and fan out is high enough it&apos;s going to take some time to for me to figure out if the proposed change is safe.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16801210" author="aweisberg" created="Mon, 25 Mar 2019 22:50:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also if these methods are supposed to be called from only one thread that should be enforced at compile time? You can also use runtime assertions to validate the correct thread is invoking it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16802986" author="aweisberg" created="Wed, 27 Mar 2019 16:13:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Finished my review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/compare/cassandra-3.0...bdeggleston:15059-3.0?expand=1#diff-8be666c70553b1f0017a01458c490f47R340&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Should this always wrap in AssertionError?&lt;/a&gt;. I get that InterruptedException is probably an Error, but ExecutionException is just a run of the mill exception. It&apos;s not super important as it won&apos;t have a functional difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this fixes the problem it sets out to fix. I checked the call hierarchy for &lt;tt&gt;Gossiper.runInGossipStageBlocking&lt;/tt&gt; and I think that every caller is not holding any locks or resources that might stop the Gossip thread from making progress. All of them don&apos;t appear to be holding anything obvious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Documentation wise definitely document &lt;tt&gt;runInGossipStageBlocking&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt&gt;assassinate&lt;/tt&gt;, and &lt;tt&gt;convict&lt;/tt&gt; warning about the risk of deadlock if the Gossip thread ends up needing to acquire a resource via a listener (or FD&apos;s listener if there is a path for that) the calling thread holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future wise this doesn&apos;t do anything to address the underlying fragility in how Gossiper doesn&apos;t document what is safe to call from outside the Gossip thread and what isn&apos;t. It also doesn&apos;t validate the correct thread is running a given method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we want to add two (or three?) interfaces that Gossiper can implement. One is for methods that are non-mutating and safe to call from any thread. The other is for methods for that should only be called from the Gossip stage thread. And maybe a third which contains methods that mutate, but block on the Gossip stage. So &lt;tt&gt;Gossiper.instance&lt;/tt&gt; would go away and you would have a reference to the Gossiper via one of the 2-3 interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally any method that should only run in Gossip stage interface should have a &lt;tt&gt;Preconditions.checkState&lt;/tt&gt; checking that it&apos;s actually running in the Gossip stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WDYT?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16803112" author="bdeggleston" created="Wed, 27 Mar 2019 17:30:51 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future wise this doesn&apos;t do anything to address the underlying fragility in how Gossiper doesn&apos;t document what is safe to call from outside the Gossip thread and what isn&apos;t. It also doesn&apos;t validate the correct thread is running a given method.&lt;br/&gt;
I think we want to add two (or three?) interfaces that Gossiper can implement. One is for methods that are non-mutating and safe to call from any thread. The other is for methods for that should only be called from the Gossip stage thread. And maybe a third which contains methods that mutate, but block on the Gossip stage. So Gossiper.instance would go away and you would have a reference to the Gossiper via one of the 2-3 interfaces.&lt;br/&gt;
Additionally any method that should only run in Gossip stage interface should have a Preconditions.checkState checking that it&apos;s actually running in the Gossip stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you mean as part of this ticket, or as future improvements to gossip?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16803221" author="aweisberg" created="Wed, 27 Mar 2019 18:53:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Well as part of this ticket. There is a question of scope. Yes this fixes the bug, but it arguably doesn&apos;t address the reason the bug exists.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16812769" author="bdeggleston" created="Mon, 8 Apr 2019 20:35:56 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future wise this doesn&apos;t do anything to address the underlying fragility in how Gossiper doesn&apos;t document what is safe to call from outside the Gossip thread and what isn&apos;t. It also doesn&apos;t validate the correct thread is running a given method.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve been thinking about this a lot, and I think it would be safer if we didn&#8217;t do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding some preconditions isn&#8217;t going to fix the underlying fragility of Gossiper. Given the &#8220;realities&#8221; of the Gossiper class, I think it would end up causing more harm that good. Just starting to pull on that thread reveals at least one situation where we modify gossip state out of the gossip stage that makes sense (on startup). There are probably one or two more (at least), and I&#8217;d hate to break a nodetool command or something.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16812971" author="aweisberg" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2019 03:23:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It will and it won&apos;t fix it. We will know really quickly if it doesn&apos;t work because it&apos;s going to fail whatever it was doing. By learning the exceptions we will be able to evaluate whether they are correct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major changes like preconditions would be 4.0 only so if we break it we at least won&apos;t be breaking it in production anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making the API less fragile is also helps reduce the surface area for people to use Gossiper incorrectly. I don&apos;t see why we shouldn&apos;t do that.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16813615" author="bdeggleston" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2019 16:58:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think both of these changes are worth considering, but I don&#8217;t think would be&#160;appropriate to include them as part of this ticket. They are both out of scope and too risky to be putting in 3.x, and I&#8217;d argue the same for 4.0 at this point as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gossiper is very brittle, critical to the operation of a cluster, and has little to no&#160;test coverage. Any bugs that aren&apos;t&#160;caught by a&#160;manual review&#160;or&#160;raise any red flags in the dtests will become production issues at some point.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16815537" author="bdeggleston" created="Thu, 11 Apr 2019 16:02:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Maybe we could compromise a bit here. There&#8217;s definitely value in rooting out places where we violate the assumptions gossiper makes about concurrency, but I worry that if we don&#8217;t catch all of them we&apos;ll turn a race that &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; cause a problem into a hard failure. What if we logged an error by default, but threw an exception if a system property was set? This way we can get feedback and scary messages in the logs, but we haven&apos;t made things any less stable, and our tests will fail if we&#8217;re doing something we shouldn&#8217;t be. I have no problem putting that in 3.x and up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to punt the refactor to 4.next though. I do think it&#8217;s valuable, but I think it&#8217;s a bit late in the game to add it to 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WDYT?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16816665" author="aweisberg" created="Fri, 12 Apr 2019 21:19:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think that&apos;s a good way to resolve the concerns with destabilizing 4.0 while still getting the benefit of doing more runtime checking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we want to create a single property (not specific to Gossip?)  for this class of conditional logging or assertion. That way when we invoke the tests we don&apos;t have to specify multiple properties to specify whether we want fail fast or logging behavior if we want this elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I would be +1 if we did that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree the refactor is a bit of an ask for 4.0, but I don&apos;t see it as a refactor really. It&apos;s all type system stuff with no actual changes to what methods are invoked and where. It&apos;s really just bucketing every method in Gossiper into a interfaces and instead of having code use Gossiper.instance we would have it use the appropriate interface reference. That is pretty low risk although the LOC churn would not be small.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16821569" author="bdeggleston" created="Thu, 18 Apr 2019 23:59:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve updated my branches with the runtime checking, could you take a look? The checks discovered a few more places where we were mutating Gossip state from the wrong thread,&#160;which I fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16823290" author="bdeggleston" created="Mon, 22 Apr 2019 17:54:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I opened &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-15095&quot; title=&quot;Split Gossiper into separate interfaces&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-15095&quot;&gt;CASSANDRA-15095&lt;/a&gt; as a follow on JIRA.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16823408" author="aweisberg" created="Mon, 22 Apr 2019 20:10:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;quarantineEndpoint&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;replacementQuarantine&lt;/tt&gt; are private, but maybe check there as well? I don&apos;t feel strongly about it, but it&apos;s slightly safer when they are called indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;assassinateEndpoint&lt;/tt&gt; asserts on the thread inside the lambda for run in Gossip stage. Harmless, but is it too much?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;notifyFailureDetector&lt;/tt&gt; seems like it could tolerate having this assertion since it is called from VerbHandlers in the gossip stage?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16823419" author="aweisberg" created="Mon, 22 Apr 2019 20:18:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Oops, hit add early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;applyNewStates&lt;/tt&gt; is also private, but maybe check the assertion there?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16823466" author="bdeggleston" created="Mon, 22 Apr 2019 21:00:49 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;quarantineEndpoint and replacementQuarantine are private, but maybe check there as well? I don&apos;t feel strongly about it, but it&apos;s slightly safer when they are called indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;quarantineEndpoint&lt;/tt&gt; (and by extension, &lt;tt&gt;replacementQuarantine&lt;/tt&gt;) modifies the &lt;tt&gt;justRemovedEndpoints&lt;/tt&gt; map. This map is also modified in the GossipTask thread, and is done correctly as far as I can tell. That&apos;s why I didn&apos;t add the assertion there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;assassinateEndpoint asserts on the thread inside the lambda for run in Gossip stage. Harmless, but is it too much?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably overkill, removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;notifyFailureDetector seems like it could tolerate having this assertion since it is called from VerbHandlers in the gossip stage?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing happens in that method that we&apos;d need to assert the thread for. I could see adding an assertion with the interface refactor, but I wouldn&apos;t want make noise in people&apos;s logs if we&apos;re not actually doing anything worth complaining about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;applyNewStates is also private, but maybe check the assertion there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same as above&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also switched to using the NoSpamLogger for the assertion.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16823472" author="aweisberg" created="Mon, 22 Apr 2019 21:10:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1 with one nit. For NoSpamLogger use the fully formatted exception as the key so that different traces are rate limited independently.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16826258" author="bdeggleston" created="Thu, 25 Apr 2019 17:28:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed to 3.0 as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/commit/c3ce32e239b1ba41faf1d58a942465b9bf45b986&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;c3ce32e239b1ba41faf1d58a942465b9bf45b986&lt;/a&gt; and merged up. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[bdeggleston]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12313825" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:cascadingselect">
                        <customfieldname>Bug Category</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                                    <customfieldvalue key="12984" cascade-level=""><![CDATA[Degradation]]></customfieldvalue>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12998" cascade-level="1"><![CDATA[Other Exception]]></customfieldvalue>
            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313821" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Complexity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12965"><![CDATA[Normal]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313822" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Discovered By</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12969"><![CDATA[User Report]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            6 years, 29 weeks, 5 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z00yrs:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[aweisberg]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12962"><![CDATA[Normal]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:version">
                        <customfieldname>Since Version</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12333891">3.0.0</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313823" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:textarea">
                        <customfieldname>Test and Documentation Plan</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>&lt;p&gt;circleci runs looks good&lt;/p&gt;</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>