<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Tue Nov 11 23:16:30 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[CASSANDRA-15375] Remove BackPressureStrategy</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-15375</link>
                <project id="12310865" key="CASSANDRA">Apache Cassandra</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;This is odd:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;INFO &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;main&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; 2019-10-25 10:33:07,985 DatabaseDescriptor.java:803 - Back-pressure is disabled with strategy org.apache.cassandra.net.RateBasedBackPressure{high_ratio=0.9, factor=5, flow=FAST}.&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I saw that, I wasn&apos;t sure if back pressure was actually disabled, or if I was really using&#160;&lt;tt&gt;RateBasedBackPressure.&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should change to output either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Back-pressure is disabled&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;or&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;Back-pressure is enabled with strategy org.apache.cassandra.net.RateBasedBackPressure{high_ratio=0.9, factor=5, flow=FAST}.&lt;/tt&gt;{{}}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13264494">CASSANDRA-15375</key>
            <summary>Remove BackPressureStrategy</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="10003" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/trivial.svg">Low</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="benedict">Benedict Elliott Smith</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="rustyrazorblade">Jon Haddad</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 15:10:18 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 21:19:22 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:17:38 +0000</resolved>
                                        <fixVersion>4.0-beta1</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>4.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Messaging/Client</component>
                    <component>Observability/Logging</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>6</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16961912" author="benedict" created="Tue, 29 Oct 2019 11:23:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Which version of Cassandra are we discussing here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My preference is to remove the back pressure feature entirely, since it&apos;s never really been tested at scale that I know of.  In 4.0 we have the capability of pushing the actual internode backpressure back to clients, in a similar manner to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sumanth.pasupuleti&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sumanth.pasupuleti&quot;&gt;sumanth.pasupuleti&lt;/a&gt; achieved recently in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-15013&quot; title=&quot;Prevent client requests from blocking on executor task queue&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-15013&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-15013&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if that&apos;s too contentious, sure, let&apos;s clean up our logging &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16962346" author="rustyrazorblade" created="Tue, 29 Oct 2019 19:38:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I found this in trunk, but assume it&apos;s elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t have any test data showing it&apos;s affect on performance either way, I&apos;ve never enabled it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17042327" author="rustyrazorblade" created="Sat, 22 Feb 2020 01:41:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=benedict&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;benedict&quot;&gt;benedict&lt;/a&gt; I think we might be a bit late to remove the back pressure mechanism from 4.0.  I intend to fix the logging, and maybe we evaluate it for removal in the next release?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17042519" author="benedict" created="Sat, 22 Feb 2020 11:14:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s never too late: it&apos;s about 5m of work to remove, it has precisely two insertion points in the code, and it&apos;s never actually used.  If we are interested at all in doing it, I can do it right now.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17042673" author="dcapwell" created="Sat, 22 Feb 2020 18:36:57 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;My preference is to remove the back pressure feature entirely, since it&apos;s never really been tested at scale that I know of.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large chunk of the work for 4.0 is testing, so removing something because its not tested isn&apos;t really fair since this wouldn&apos;t be unique. Also, based off this JIRA, you can disable it; so don&apos;t see a reason to remove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 4.0 we have the capability of pushing the actual internode backpressure back to clients&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a jira for actually testing the different back pressures we have before 4.0 releases?  If not can we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would personally love to see &quot;this is how 4.0 doesn&apos;t crash under load&quot; and tests to back it up; if there is a test for this already do let me know =)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17042734" author="benedict" created="Sat, 22 Feb 2020 22:36:57 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;since it&apos;s never really been tested at scale that I know of&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^ This was a euphemism for &#8220;this feature has never been used, and is probably bad&#8221;.&#160; It was implemented some time ago by DataStax, never advertised in any way by OSS, and has never ben updated (making it either the first perfect feature, or broken).&#160; It has perhaps been used by DataStax in their own offerings, but never by OSS. &#160;It is unlikely (m?)any even know it exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the 4.0 networking changes, this feature no longer provides any utility for stability.  We now limit the amount of data inbound from any specific (and all) coordinators so that we cannot be overwhelmed, and vice-versa, and this happens instantly i.e. responsively*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature, however, makes some basic implementation errors, and appears to have several problematic semantics, particularly with vnodes, responsiveness and choppiness (imposing three arbitrary rates of LOW, HIGH, INFINITE for all unique combination of message recipient (probably really problematic with vnodes, and high RF), updated once every WriteRpcTimeout - assuming the system clock doesn&#8217;t get updated by e.g. NTP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only behaviour missing from internode is the ability to notify clients of back pressure, either by propagating to the client connection or by throwing overloaded exceptions.  However this is also implemented poorly here, &#8220;applying backpressure&#8221; by consuming a &lt;tt&gt;RequestPoolExecutor&lt;/tt&gt; thread until permitted to proceed.  Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-15013&quot; title=&quot;Prevent client requests from blocking on executor task queue&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-15013&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-15013&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this will only be suboptimal, but prior to 4.0 this would have lead to really problematic cluster behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s worth noting that the above was all perhaps a reasonable set of trade-offs when first implemented, though the original ticket lead to a great deal of debate about the reasonableness of the approach (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/CASSANDRA-9318&quot; title=&quot;Bound the number of in-flight requests at the coordinator&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;CASSANDRA-9318&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;CASSANDRA-9318&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).  However it also suggests to me we are better removing this unused, unmaintained feature that is no longer particularly needed, and if we have time implementing the version that makes sense in the current context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(*That all said, 4.0 stability at scale is part of the 4.0 testing plan, and determining reasonable numbers for the limits is a remaining exercise - they are almost certainly too high today to guarantee stability.)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17043342" author="benedict" created="Mon, 24 Feb 2020 10:00:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;For sake of discussion, &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/tree/15375&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a quick 10m patch (I guess I was a slight optimist) to remove this from the codebase&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17043844" author="dcapwell" created="Mon, 24 Feb 2020 20:40:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the detailed write up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only behaviour missing from internode is the ability to notify clients of back pressure&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&apos;t get that statement since I thought we had it, but Jordan than informed me that they are related just not connected (NodeA -&amp;gt; NodeB has support, coordinator  -&amp;gt; client has support; NodeA -&amp;gt; coordinator -&amp;gt; client does not have support).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17043926" author="benedict" created="Mon, 24 Feb 2020 22:29:32 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;NodeA -&amp;gt; coordinator -&amp;gt; client &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, so fortunately we&apos;re talking about (I expect) fairly limited scaffolding to link the two systems together, when we get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17050473" author="rustyrazorblade" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2020 18:40:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve worked on a few hundred clusters (from maybe 75 teams / companies) and I have never seen this feature used.  I have no objections to removing it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17050482" author="sbtourist" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2020 19:01:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As the original author of that implementation, I regard it as experimental and never proven to be widely used, so I agree with removing it. Dead code is bad code (regardless of its actual quality or past merits).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17050506" author="benedict" created="Tue, 3 Mar 2020 19:47:26 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;regardless of its actual quality or past merits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FWIW, I&apos;d like to disclaim any desire to discredit the original work - it was both a very different time, and nothing is ever perfect first time.  With maintenance it could no doubt have rapidly become a useful feature, but today it does not make sense.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17051099" author="sbtourist" created="Wed, 4 Mar 2020 10:41:34 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d like to disclaim any desire to discredit the original work&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, and as I said it was experimental and meant to evolve once widely used, which never happened. Do you want me to review your patch?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17051102" author="benedict" created="Wed, 4 Mar 2020 10:45:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That would be great, thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17068605" author="sbtourist" created="Fri, 27 Mar 2020 12:01:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=benedict&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;benedict&quot;&gt;benedict&lt;/a&gt;, apologies for this late review. I&apos;ve added some comments to your commit here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/commit/3584b4305ab87f836fdc94d4d5b28bd102642ccb&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/commit/3584b4305ab87f836fdc94d4d5b28bd102642ccb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17105672" author="jrwest" created="Tue, 12 May 2020 18:49:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry to come in late on this when there is already a patch but shouldn&apos;t we deprecate&#160;&lt;tt&gt;RateBasedBackPressure&lt;/tt&gt; before removing it? I understand folks here haven&apos;t seen it in the wild but that doesn&apos;t mean someone isn&apos;t using it. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17105768" author="benedict" created="Tue, 12 May 2020 21:45:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Not everything has to go through a deprecation process, no.  Since this feature was never advertised by any means, it cannot be taken to be supported.  Since we also don&apos;t think it&apos;s &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt;, ignoring the property will leave the database approximately as functional as it was before.  Such a user, if they exist, will still have a working database after upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="17105780" author="jrwest" created="Tue, 12 May 2020 22:06:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;While I don&apos;t totally agree with your bar for what constitutes an official public API, my biggest concern was that since we weren&apos;t deprecating it, if there was a user of it, there would be an exception when their configuration was read on startup. Looking closer at your patch, it does look like this has been accounted for by indeed marking the fields &lt;tt&gt;@Deprecated&lt;/tt&gt; in &lt;tt&gt;Config&lt;/tt&gt; (as an aside I also agree with the comment that we should note them as such in cassandra.yaml). So while they will take no effect, they won&apos;t harm anyone who had it set in their config either. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17105783" author="benedict" created="Tue, 12 May 2020 22:13:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;FWIW, we haven&apos;t actually always been great about deprecating old parameters in config files.  I&apos;m pretty sure every version has had some config parameter vanish without deprecation (which is not an endorsement of that, of course)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separately, I hadn&apos;t actually realised it was in the yaml, I had been searching for the wrong text string.  That could certainly be taken to be an advertisement of the feature.  I still don&apos;t think deprecation is warranted, given the earlier discussions about the feature itself, but my prior position was taken on faulty information.  I&apos;d be happy to defer to somebody with a stronger opinion.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17105791" author="jrwest" created="Tue, 12 May 2020 22:27:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d be +1 on this if we update cassandra.yaml with a deprecation notice &amp;#8211; continuing with code removal as it is in the patch now. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17159794" author="benedict" created="Fri, 17 Jul 2020 09:13:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry for dropping the ball on this, the ticket doesn&apos;t show up in my normal Jira query (will figure out why later).  I&apos;ve pushed an update to the branch addressing the review feedback; I think it&apos;s ready to commit with a quick +1 (CI is running &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.circleci.com/pipelines/github/belliottsmith/cassandra?branch=15375&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17159876" author="snazy" created="Fri, 17 Jul 2020 11:32:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;super nit: maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/belliottsmith/cassandra/commit/2ba8b4d162c20142c3d4c7a225432337b7bdbc36#diff-4805e34bd9553ede03778be66ddc06c7R262&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;change the wording here&lt;/a&gt; to &quot;removed&quot; instead of &quot;deprecated&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17159989" author="benedict" created="Fri, 17 Jul 2020 15:18:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks, committed with your suggestion&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313920" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Authors</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[benedict]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12313825" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:cascadingselect">
                        <customfieldname>Bug Category</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                                    <customfieldvalue key="13163" cascade-level=""><![CDATA[Code]]></customfieldvalue>
                                <customfieldvalue key="13164" cascade-level="1"><![CDATA[Bug - Unclear Impact]]></customfieldvalue>
            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313821" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Complexity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12964"><![CDATA[Low Hanging Fruit]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313822" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Discovered By</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12969"><![CDATA[User Report]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12313922" key="jira.plugin.projectspecificselectfield.jpssf:multicftype">
                        <customfieldname>Impacts</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="13100"><![CDATA[None]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            5 years, 17 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313921" key="jira.plugin.projectspecificselectfield.jpssf:multicftype">
                        <customfieldname>Platform</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="13076"><![CDATA[All]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z07yhc:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12313420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multiuserpicker">
                        <customfieldname>Reviewers</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                    <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[benedict]]></customfieldvalue>
        <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[snazy]]></customfieldvalue>
        <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[sbtourist]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12313820" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:select">
                        <customfieldname>Severity</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="12961"><![CDATA[Low]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311420" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:version">
                        <customfieldname>Since Version</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue id="12348284">4.0-alpha4</customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313924" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:textfield">
                        <customfieldname>Source Control Link</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/cassandra/commit/d8993934e976d8edb94cbfe2974688dac63c5db5&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;d8993934e976d8edb94cbfe2974688dac63c5db5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313823" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:textarea">
                        <customfieldname>Test and Documentation Plan</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>&lt;p&gt;n/a&lt;/p&gt;</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>