<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 22:17:19 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[WICKET-3433] Wicket parses HTML inside IE conditional comments</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3433</link>
                <project id="12310561" key="WICKET">Wicket</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;I cannot use the HTML5 Boilerplate HTML with wicket. Wicket appears to parse HTML inside IE conditional comments when they appear between the doctype declaration and the &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first lines of the boilerplate html look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;	&amp;lt;!doctype html&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
	&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if lt IE 7 ]&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;no-js ie6&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
	&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if IE 7 ]&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;no-js ie7&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
	&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if IE 8 ]&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;no-js ie8&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
	&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if IE 9 ]&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;no-js ie9&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
	&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;Unable to render embedded object: File (--[if (gt IE 9)) not found.&lt;/span&gt;(IE)]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html lang=&quot;en&quot; class=&quot;no-js&quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;/del&gt;&lt;del&gt;&amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...which causes a problem for wicket, as it thinks there are five opening &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; tags on the page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12497892">WICKET-3433</key>
            <summary>Wicket parses HTML inside IE conditional comments</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="2">Won&apos;t Fix</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="mgrigorov">Martin Tzvetanov Grigorov</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="_alanshaw">Alan Shaw</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>HTML5</label>
                            <label>boilerplate</label>
                            <label>doctype</label>
                            <label>html</label>
                            <label>parser</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Mon, 7 Feb 2011 19:35:30 +0000</created>
                <updated>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 11:28:56 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 11:28:56 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.5-M3</version>
                                                    <component>wicket</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>7</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12991537" author="_alanshaw" created="Mon, 7 Feb 2011 19:36:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This quickstart demonstrates the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12991763" author="pedrosans" created="Tue, 8 Feb 2011 01:22:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Close the html tag as below for now (as you suggested in the quickstart),  IMO MarkupParser needs to allow your usecase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if lt IE 7 ]&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if IE 7 ]&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if IE 8 ]&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;[if IE 9 ]&amp;gt;    &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;Unable to render embedded object: File (--[if (gt IE 9)) not found.&lt;/span&gt;(IE)]&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-&lt;del&gt;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!&lt;/del&gt;&lt;del&gt;&amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12991891" author="pedrosans" created="Tue, 8 Feb 2011 10:41:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Wicket chunks the conditional comment and parse only the markup inside it. Closing the html the as many times it was opened (as you suggested ), and wrapping then inside the correspondent conditional comments (as I&apos;m suggesting) generate valid html to browser, I just tested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://validator.w3.org/check&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://validator.w3.org/check&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12991935" author="pedrosans" created="Tue, 8 Feb 2011 11:05:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m sending back your quickstart working&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12991938" author="_alanshaw" created="Tue, 8 Feb 2011 11:12:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You are correct, apologies. The problem is slightly different to what I thought the problem was.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12993878" author="jdonnerstag" created="Sat, 12 Feb 2011 10:35:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I find it difficult to imagine how Wicket could handle possibilities. Pedro is right in how Wicket will see the markup once loaded. It&apos;ll be like&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
  &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
     &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
         &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
             &amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Wicket validates that for every open tag, there is a close tag as well, Wicket complains about the missing &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; tags in your original example. And for the browser to be happy you need add what Pedro has suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what would Wicket need to do in order to understand that use case: Wicket needs to validate that each body of the conditional leaves the very same open tag behind. In theory that could be done though a bit of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&apos;s not as simple as one my think. E.g. what is the rule that 2+ conditional tag belong to a group? I&apos;d guess only &quot;empty&quot; raw markup between &amp;lt;![endif]&amp;gt; and the next &amp;lt;!--[if...&amp;gt;.  But if the next conditional leaves different open tags behind, it should not be part of that group, right? =&amp;gt; increase in complexity&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;!--[if ..IE7...]&amp;gt; body AAAA &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;!--[if ..IE7...]&amp;gt; body BBBB by purpose &amp;lt;!&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;endif&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your conditional body for whatever reason gets a Component attached (either by the user or automatically by Wicket), than you&apos;ll need all the close tags. Otherwise the render process will fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be we can&apos;t handle all possible scenarios, but improve a bit. An additional IMarkupFilter would be needed. I&apos;m happy to review it if someone would provide the code.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12994253" author="mgrigorov" created="Mon, 14 Feb 2011 09:59:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think we should not do anything for this issue.&lt;br/&gt;
The solution/workaround is to use the same checks for the closing (&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;) elements, as in Pedro&apos;s comment from 08/Feb/11 1:22 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; HTML5 Boilerplate uses IE comments because it is more easy for them, but most of the JS libraries use onDomReady to assign the classes - see &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidwalsh.name/mootools-css&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://davidwalsh.name/mootools-css&lt;/a&gt; for the MooTools and Dojo approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a new markup filter will just make things more complex than needed for no big gain.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12994254" author="_alanshaw" created="Mon, 14 Feb 2011 10:06:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;HTML5 boilerplate uses IE conditional comments so that you can still apply IE specific styles to browsers that don&apos;t have JavaScript enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wicket has no business in IE conditional comments. Wicket is not IE. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12994264" author="pedrosans" created="Mon, 14 Feb 2011 10:42:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The big problem is that open some tag N times inside conditional comments an close it once gives us valid markup, I tested on w3c checker, and every browser understands it, I tested on Chrome, FireFox, Opera and Safari.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12994317" author="pedrosans" created="Mon, 14 Feb 2011 14:38:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch suporting the related usecase and Downlevel-revealed Conditional Comments as well&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12995192" author="ivaynberg" created="Wed, 16 Feb 2011 06:32:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;thanks for the patch Pedro, lets see if Juergen agrees.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12996747" author="jdonnerstag" created="Sat, 19 Feb 2011 10:39:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Pedro,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;few comments to your patch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;you &quot;fixed&quot; a test case by properly closing the &amp;lt;link&amp;gt; tag. Though it is proper XHTML now, HTML and most browsers did allow that inaccuracy, and we supported it as well. Introducing your patch means it no long works if markup contains conditional comments =&amp;gt; That will be a difficult to find problem for user I guess&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;since you are skipping all markup elements in HtmlHandler between the comment open and the close tag, no wicket components (manual or automatic ones) are allowed anymore in the markup embraced by the conditional. Something we used to support (see SimplePage_12.html). &amp;lt;link href=&quot;some.css&quot;&amp;gt; which are common in between conditional comment e.g. will be affected  =&amp;gt; if we want to go down that road, than we need to properly communicate that limitation to our users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Juergen&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12996750" author="jdonnerstag" created="Sat, 19 Feb 2011 10:47:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;my working file with additional test cases&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12996854" author="pedrosans" created="Sat, 19 Feb 2011 20:34:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Juergen thank for the review. The idea of skip repeated markup inside the conditional comments has those drawbacks you pointed, we would have to skip only repeated not closed or not opend tags inside different conditional comments to solve it. I think it can be done nicely, let me come back with another path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&apos;t fixed the MarkupParserTest by closing the link tag at MarkupParserTest_9.html because it wasn&apos;t failing, I just reverted it here to maintain it testing the tolerance of non close tags, thanks for noticed and test cases.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12997250" author="pedrosans" created="Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:58:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Juergen, the SimplePageTest#testRenderHomePage_12 is failing always, I&apos;m attaching what I think that we should expect.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12997610" author="pedrosans" created="Tue, 22 Feb 2011 00:10:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Juergen, I&apos;m attaching the patch with a new filter to skip tags inside conditional comments as you suggested. Below some explains about changed classes in the patch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;AbstractMarkupParser and WicketRemoveTagHandler: changed to support early test of tags on ConditionalCommentFilter&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;TagStack: html tags open close balance control moved out from HtmlHandler to be used by ConditionalCommentFilter also&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ConditionalComment: class created to enable parse filters to control this MarkupElement&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;XmlPullParser: changed to support the new markup element type - ConditionalComment&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ConditionalCommentFilter: new filter in the chain to skip mismatch tags inside conditional comments&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;RootMarkupFilter: changed to return the new comment type to chained filters&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;WicketTagIdentifier: simple change to avoid class cast exceptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13008835" author="pedrosans" created="Sat, 19 Mar 2011 21:57:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;same patch for the current trunk&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13008898" author="jdonnerstag" created="Sun, 20 Mar 2011 12:58:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Pedro,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not yet there, but I&apos;d like to forward every tag (including comments) to markup filters, so that conditional comments can be fully handled by a markup filter. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13008956" author="pedrosans" created="Sun, 20 Mar 2011 20:11:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Nice, I think I did that in the patch, the new filter fully handling conditional comment logic is the ConditionalCommentFilter&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13008997" author="pedrosans" created="Mon, 21 Mar 2011 01:03:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Juergen, in the last commit you broke the HtmlHandler validation by moving it to postProcess (bug exposed by MarkupParserTest#testErrorOnMismatchTag in the patch). The problem is that postProcess is not invoked for all filters in the chain since its first filter - StyleAndScriptIdentifier -  is not forwarding the call.&lt;br/&gt;
I understand your idea of moving the conditional comments handle code to a filter in the chain, I think it is OK and it is why I moved it to there in my second patch I guess. &lt;br/&gt;
In your last commit you also made a relatively big change in the parser by not considering the XmlTag as a MarkupElement. I also agree with the change, and merged it into my patch. But I ask you to hold on further changes in the parser until we close this ticket, because it&apos;s getting hard to follow you in the changes.&lt;br/&gt;
The Wicket parser is an hostile land for newcomers, I already saw a single innocent line invoking a method in the wrong sequence break more than 500 test cases.&lt;br/&gt;
The new attached patch fix this issue, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3500&quot; title=&quot;Method AbstractMarkupParser.removeComment() causes an endless loop&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;WICKET-3500&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;WICKET-3500&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and the on described before.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13009052" author="jdonnerstag" created="Mon, 21 Mar 2011 08:37:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Pedro,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&apos;t mean to give you a hard time. That&apos;s why I wrote my last comment. Though re-reading it, it says nothing about &quot;hold off until I&apos;m finished&quot;. Sorry for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look at you patch. I think a little bit more tweaking to the framework - compared to the dedicated comment handling code - is necessary to make the markup filters more versatile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juergen&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13025811" author="mgrigorov" created="Wed, 27 Apr 2011 14:36:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Please test the fix here with getMarkupSettings().setStripComments(true);&lt;br/&gt;
This setting has some issues with IE conditional comments - see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3648&quot; title=&quot;AbstractMarkupParser.removeComment() goes in endless loop when the comment is multi line&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;WICKET-3648&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;WICKET-3648&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13033608" author="ivaynberg" created="Sat, 14 May 2011 22:20:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;where are we on this?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13050390" author="clerch" created="Thu, 16 Jun 2011 12:56:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Martin, that&apos;s gracious.&lt;br/&gt;
Please find attached a very simple quickstart, that should demonstrate that setting the class attribute on the html tag via TransparentWebMarkupContainer  and AttributeAppender does not work, well, at least as I understand it. Please let me know what&apos;s wrong with it.&lt;br/&gt;
Thank you,&lt;br/&gt;
Chris&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13050405" author="mgrigorov" created="Thu, 16 Jun 2011 13:19:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attaching the fixed quickstart provided by Christian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@Christian: its your turn again. Please create a wiki page, describe the use case and paste the relevant snippets &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13063387" author="jdonnerstag" created="Mon, 11 Jul 2011 15:14:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Microsoft removed support for Conditional Comments in IE10. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ie/archive/2010/04/14/same-markup-writing-cross-browser-code.aspx&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ie/archive/2010/04/14/same-markup-writing-cross-browser-code.aspx&lt;/a&gt; on MS proposed ways to solve cross browser issues.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13562563" author="fstoerkle" created="Fri, 25 Jan 2013 09:55:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Any news here?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13564321" author="rniestroj" created="Mon, 28 Jan 2013 15:04:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Made a workaround today. This is attached to the body tag:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      WebMarkupContainer body = new WebMarkupContainer(&quot;bodyContainer&quot;){&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;         @Override&lt;br/&gt;
         protected void onConfigure() {&lt;br/&gt;
            super.onConfigure(); &lt;br/&gt;
            if (WebSession.get().getClientInfo().getProperties().isBrowserInternetExplorer())&lt;/p&gt;
{
               add(AttributeModifier.replace(&quot;class&quot;, &quot;ie ie&quot; + WebSession.get().getClientInfo().getProperties().getBrowserVersionMajor() ));
            }
&lt;p&gt;         }&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;      };&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13739534" author="mgrigorov" created="Wed, 14 Aug 2013 11:28:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Closing as &quot;Won&apos;t fix&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workaround in programmatic-way.tgz (simple version can be seen in Robert&apos;s comment) is better solution than what h5boilerplate provides. The Wicket way will work even in IE10+.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310000">
                    <name>Duplicate</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is duplicated by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12510487">WICKET-3801</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12505302">WICKET-3648</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12471537" name="SimplePageExpectedResult_12a.html" size="1138" author="pedrosans" created="Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:58:09 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12474141" name="WICKET-3433.patch" size="76756" author="pedrosans" created="Mon, 21 Mar 2011 01:03:51 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12470582" name="html5boilerplate.ui.wicket.parsefail-working.zip" size="33723" author="pedrosans" created="Tue, 8 Feb 2011 11:05:26 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12470490" name="html5boilerplate.ui.wicket.parsefail.zip" size="36658" author="_alanshaw" created="Mon, 7 Feb 2011 19:36:45 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12482794" name="programmatic-way.tgz" size="18561" author="mgrigorov" created="Thu, 16 Jun 2011 13:19:05 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12482791" name="quickstart.zip" size="4524190" author="clerch" created="Thu, 16 Jun 2011 12:56:15 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12471463" name="wicket-conditional-comments.patch" size="20556" author="jdonnerstag" created="Sat, 19 Feb 2011 10:47:44 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>7.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2595</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            12 years, 14 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i00wgv:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>3192</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>