<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 22:17:45 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[WICKET-3667] Once in a while we get random page expired on customers site </title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3667</link>
                <project id="12310561" key="WICKET">Wicket</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;To reproduce the error just run the attached quickstart, and run it. Open 2 browser instances with 8 tabs each pointing toward the server. Wait for page expired.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment>jetty,. tomcat, ff</environment>
        <key id="12506171">WICKET-3667</key>
            <summary>Once in a while we get random page expired on customers site </summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="8">Not A Problem</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="mgrigorov">Martin Tzvetanov Grigorov</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="nino">Nino Martinez</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 4 May 2011 14:03:29 +0000</created>
                <updated>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 08:48:47 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 27 May 2011 13:33:26 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.5-RC3</version>
                                                    <component>wicket</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>1</votes>
                                    <watches>3</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13028753" author="nino" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 14:05:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;quickstart&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13028754" author="nino" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 14:08:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I noticed that it only seemed to occur when the total and used memory consumption clashed like the below line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INFO  - DummyRequestLogger         - time=2609,event=null,response=null,sessionid=1hz2dq3mc1fxlrru26h4vn19k,sessionsize=662,sessionstart=Wed May 04 16:07:25 CEST 2011,requests=3,totaltime=3171,activerequests=0,maxmem=66M,total=2M,used=2M&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13028765" author="mgrigorov" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 14:49:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Not sure how your real application looks like but here is what I think happens in the quickstart:&lt;br/&gt;
There is just one page which is stored in the http session. Since Ajax requests don&apos;t change page version there are no more versions of that page to be stored. So there is no need to store this page instance in the disk. By creating more tabs you exhaust the free memory and at one point the page is cleaned from the memory because the pages are stored in SoftReferences - see org.apache.wicket.pageStore.DefaultPageStore.SerializedPagesCache.cache. Next Ajax call can&apos;t find the page anymore because it is no more in memory (http session) nor in disk (never got there). Thus the page expired exception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems my machine is more powerful than yours because I cannot make it close-to-out-of-memory. I have 4 instances of Firefox each with 10-12 tabs, the counter reached ~6000 and all is fine. I even set -Xms8m and -Xmx8m but the GC is so aggressive that &apos;used&apos; cannot get equal to &apos;total&apos; (8M).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may try to set org.apache.wicket.DefaultPageManagerProvider.getCacheSize() to 0. This way there wont be memory store and the page will be serialized immediately in the disk store. The drawback is that each ajax call will hit the disk. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13028780" author="mgrigorov" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 14:57:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I am not correct. The first version of the page is actually stored in the disk store: &lt;br/&gt;
org.apache.wicket.pageStore.DefaultPageStore.storePage(String, IManageablePage) does that.&lt;br/&gt;
Will investigate further...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13028785" author="nino" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 15:10:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;but how do one determine the total, if I can change that it would help..&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13028877" author="nino" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 18:25:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;ok so what you essentially are saying are that I can affect total, by changing jvm settings right? but why are totalt different from max then?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13028903" author="mgrigorov" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 19:20:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I just committed an improvement.&lt;br/&gt;
Can you try latest -SNAPSHOT and send feedback ?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13029210" author="nino" created="Thu, 5 May 2011 07:15:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In progress, inital testing on my pc went well. Now rolling out to customers site..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the improvement simple, so I could &quot;patch&quot; the RC3 or?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13029213" author="mgrigorov" created="Thu, 5 May 2011 07:20:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Check the &quot;Subversion commits&quot; tab here in the ticket and decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13029227" author="nino" created="Thu, 5 May 2011 08:18:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Our testing on customers site shows it is fixed &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; Thanks ALOT Martin for helping out..&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13029230" author="mgrigorov" created="Thu, 5 May 2011 08:23:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Cool!&lt;br/&gt;
Our QA also experienced similar problem but he didn&apos;t know how to reproduce it.&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks for the quickstart! Hopefully it will solve our problem too.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13030287" author="mgrigorov" created="Sat, 7 May 2011 07:13:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It seems I&apos;ll have to revert the &quot;improvement&quot; for your ticket (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3667&quot; title=&quot;Once in a while we get random page expired on customers site &quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;WICKET-3667&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;WICKET-3667&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3676&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-3676&lt;/a&gt; is broken because of&lt;br/&gt;
this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFAIK Wicket should not store the page for Ajax requests (this is what&lt;br/&gt;
I know from the other devs) but apparently this is not quite true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried the app in 3676 in latest 1.4.x and it works fine. So I&lt;br/&gt;
debugged it and it seems Wicket 1.4.x actually stores the page after&lt;br/&gt;
Ajax request.&lt;br/&gt;
So now I&apos;m a confused what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@Other devs: any advises ?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13030305" author="pedrosans" created="Sat, 7 May 2011 09:59:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I can&apos;t reproduce the problem here unless I decrease the DiskDataStore maxSizePerPageSession. The only potential problem I see are distinct threads storing distinct pages without the happens-before relationship. It can cause indexPointer variable getting incremented twice and read by those threads only after it get double incremented. In this scenario the PageWindowManager would map only one of those pages to the new index, and in the next call the not mapped page will cause the page expired exception.&lt;br/&gt;
PageAccessSynchronizer synchronize threads by page id, but different threads can use the same PageWindowManager to map different pages.&lt;br/&gt;
Is my concern valid? I&apos;m trying to imaging what generated the reported problem since I could not reproduce it here.&lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="13030312" author="nino" created="Sat, 7 May 2011 10:47:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Im not sure either. But I can reproduce it on my laptop using the quickstart... And our product are awaiting the fix to function properly.. Otherwise the customer can only have one or two open browser instances.. And that is very bad &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/sad.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you need from me? &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13031196" author="nino" created="Tue, 10 May 2011 13:58:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Have tried with the latest snapshot today, and are unable to reproduce with the quick start.. However as this is a pretty elusive bug, I&apos;d like to try our app at customers site before closing it..&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13032818" author="mlopezsoto" created="Fri, 13 May 2011 04:01:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;We have a problem which we believe is related to the same bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an application that after the user is authenticated shows a page with two iFrames, where each frame points to a different page, one is map and the other one contains a DataTable. The page has a timer (JavaScript) that refreshes some components of these two pages (AJAX), but not the pages themselves, every 5 seconds. After some time (kind of ramdom, could be one minute, could be 20) the app crashes because of a PageExpiredException.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps to pinpoint the problem. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13038010" author="mgrigorov" created="Mon, 23 May 2011 16:03:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Any news here ?&lt;br/&gt;
Do you experience this issue with RC4.2 ?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13038133" author="jimlars" created="Mon, 23 May 2011 18:56:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I have experienced PageExpiredExceptions in RC4.2 and still on 1.5-SNAPSHOT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been struggling to create a quickstart, with no success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is somehow related to mounted pages, as I can move my problems by changing the mounted pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a site that could be illustrated like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/homepage      (mounted page)&lt;br/&gt;
/admin/page1  (mounted as /admin and protected by AuthStrat)&lt;br/&gt;
/admin/page2  (protected by AuthStrat)&lt;br/&gt;
/login             &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I stats my site I end up on homepage, I then by hand enter the url /admin that should take me to page1, but its protected, and i get to the /login, successful login would normally send me to page1 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here is the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In jetty everything works perfect (I get to page 1)&lt;br/&gt;
In tomcat without apache in front everything works perfect ( I get to page 1)&lt;br/&gt;
But with apache in front of tomcat, I see problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow It messes with the session and I am logged in but there is no page to continue to, witch results in that i end up on homepage (but user is logged in on this session (i get links to my admin pages).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now i click on link to page1 and this is shown, but now it does not matter what i do. I will get an PageExpiredException from the page) &lt;br/&gt;
Using page2 will not result in PageExpired (that page is protected in the same way as page 1, but was not part of my login)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I change my mount from page1 to page2, I see same result, but all problems will come on page2 and page1 will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that if i clik on a link to my homepage, the user is by magic logged out !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect that the problem is related to session (cant say exactly why, but it appears as if there are 2 sessions involved)&lt;br/&gt;
Clicking on my homepage link should load my homepage, but it looks as if it is a cached version (but pages are not cached, to my knowledge, and I have checked to see if all headers are in my response (they are))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as I wrote, I only see the problems with PageExpired, when having Apache in front of tomcat.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sorry about this bad description, but as I am not able to create a quickstart, it means I&apos;m not understanding the problem my self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My problem is not random, as I can reproduce it, but I suspect that it is somehow related.&lt;/p&gt;






</comment>
                            <comment id="13038399" author="mgrigorov" created="Tue, 24 May 2011 05:50:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;JIm, your problem seems to be related to wrong Apache configuration. Better ask in the mailing lists of Tomcat.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13038926" author="mlopezsoto" created="Wed, 25 May 2011 02:11:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Martin,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have the problem and I managed to write a small application that can be used to reproduced the problem. First let me tell you what the real application does (not the small attached app):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a main page that is &apos;always&apos; visible. This main page shows &apos;real time&apos; data by refreshing a Wicket Datatable every 5 seconds using AJAX. If the user clicks on any of the links (usually CRUD operations), the application opens a new browser window with another table (sometimes it can be a couple of tabs, each tab holding a datatable) that allows the user to do the basic CRUD tasks. Every time the user clicks on one the links, we noticed that we get a new version of the page, for example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-First click -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/app/page1?5&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://localhost/app/page1?5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-Second click -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/app/page1?12&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://localhost/app/page1?12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-Third click -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/app/page1?19&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://localhost/app/page1?19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
 and so on..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few versions (we believe 50 versions) of page1 have been created, the main page expires (PageExpiredException). We have managed to delay this (we still get some PageExpiredException-s, but we don&apos;t know if the cause is the same) by changing the default values of the DefaultPageManagerProvider as you suggested in an earlier comment. We set the getCacheSize() and getMaxSizePerSession() to 0, but it does not seem rigth to us. Maybe we are doing something wrong and clicking the same link should not be creating new versions of the same page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reproduce this on the attached application (pageexpired.zip)&lt;br/&gt;
-Unzip&lt;br/&gt;
-run mvn eclipse:eclipse&lt;br/&gt;
-Run the application jetty:run&lt;br/&gt;
-open a browser: &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/pageexpired&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8080/pageexpired&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
-On the main page click the &apos;Pop Up Window&apos; link several times, until the pop-up page version reaches 51 or more. Do not refresh the main page or click on the &apos;click me&apos; link (maybe the ajax &apos;click me&apos; link can be clicked, haven&apos;t tried).&lt;br/&gt;
-When you see version 51 or higher on the pop up window (&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:8080/pageexpired/popup?53&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://localhost:8080/pageexpired/popup?53&lt;/a&gt;), click the  &apos;click me&apos; link on the main page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will get a Page Expired Error. We are using 1.5- RC4.2. It also happens in Tomcat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13039031" author="nino" created="Wed, 25 May 2011 08:38:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Martin, sorry for the delayed answer we are very busy (near the end of a development cycle). We should be able to retest again near the end of next week.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13040220" author="mgrigorov" created="Fri, 27 May 2011 13:33:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Mauricio,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is what happens in your quickstart:&lt;br/&gt;
DiskDataStore stores the pages in the file system, setMaxSizePerSession(someBytes) configures how big the file can be per session, in bytes. Initially you create the first page, it is stored at position 1 in the file, then you create N new pages which are stored at 2, 3, ..., N. When N*pageSize becomes bigger than someBytes DiskPageStore starts to write any new page from the beginning of the file, i.e. overrides the oldest one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve the problem either ping the main page from time to time as I told you in stackoverflow.com before, or make the disk store bigger. I think the first option is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In trunk I introduced IStoreSettings which can be used to tweak the settings for the default impls of IPageStore, IDataStore and IPageManager. You&apos;ll need to touch your app when upgrading to next version but I believe it is for good.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13040223" author="mgrigorov" created="Fri, 27 May 2011 13:33:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Closing as not a problem until proven otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13040402" author="mlopezsoto" created="Fri, 27 May 2011 19:27:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Martin,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of some requirements, we can&apos;t ping the main window so we will be making the disk store bigger. Looking forward to having IStoreSettings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers&lt;br/&gt;
Mauricio&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13040406" author="mgrigorov" created="Fri, 27 May 2011 19:39:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;What requirements if it is not secret ?&lt;br/&gt;
Because adding AjaxSelfUpdatingTimerBehavior that sends a request back to the page every N seconds should be very light and transparent.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13040996" author="mlopezsoto" created="Mon, 30 May 2011 04:13:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;We are using Google maps to show live data. We refresh the markers on the maps every 5 to 20 seconds, but we can&apos;t reload the maps very often (we were told to minimize reloading of the map as much as possible, and reloading the page reloads the map as well) because we have a limited number of map views. This is because we bought a Google Maps license that allows for certain number of map views, and going beyond that limit is going to cost us extra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe there is a way to using AjaxSelfUpdatingTimerBehavior to reload the page but not the maps?   &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13041007" author="mgrigorov" created="Mon, 30 May 2011 05:47:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It was good that I asked &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
You can use AbstractAjaxTimerBehavior (AjaxSelfUpdatingTimerBehavior) just to &quot;touch&quot; the page which will cause a storing of the current page version in the stores (IPageStore and IDataStore) but you&apos;ll not re-render anything, i.e. you wont do anything in onTimer().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;public MyPage(PageParameters params) {&lt;br/&gt;
  super(params);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;  add(new AbstractAjaxTimerBehavior(Duration.seconds(30) {&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     protected void onTimer(final AjaxRequestTarget target) {}&lt;br/&gt;
  });&lt;br/&gt;
}&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13041168" author="mlopezsoto" created="Mon, 30 May 2011 15:33:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Martin,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a much better way of solving this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13043007" author="mlopezsoto" created="Thu, 2 Jun 2011 19:30:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Martin, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using AbstractAjaxTimerBehavior as you suggested does not seem to be working, we are getting the page expired exception. I tried setting the page state to dirty (target.getPage().dirty()) but it did not work either. Maybe I am missing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;br/&gt;
Mauricio &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13043228" author="nino" created="Fri, 3 Jun 2011 06:33:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thats right in line with what I was experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13046013" author="mlopezsoto" created="Wed, 8 Jun 2011 15:36:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As I said in a previous comment, the workaround that we are using is changing the default values of the DefaultPageManagerProvider. We set the getCacheSize() and getMaxSizePerSession() to 0. What I noticed is that by having getMaxSizePerSession() always returning 0, the PageWindowManager index is always incremented, never goes back to zero. Event though it is working, I was wondering if this might be a problem for long running sessions (several days).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12839840">WICKET-5933</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310050">
                    <name>Regression</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="breaks">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12506413">WICKET-3676</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12478164" name="heartbeatProblem.zip" size="21086" author="nino" created="Wed, 4 May 2011 14:05:37 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12480358" name="pageexpired.zip" size="291863" author="mlopezsoto" created="Wed, 25 May 2011 02:13:44 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>71575</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            14 years, 24 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i1gghr:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>304265</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>