<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 22:18:20 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[WICKET-2650] Consistently create body for short tags.</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-2650</link>
                <project id="12310561" key="WICKET">Wicket</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Wicket HTML contains a tag such as &amp;lt;a wicket:id=&quot;foo&quot; /&amp;gt; and the component bound to that tag uses replaceComponentTagBody to write a string to the tag&apos;s body, currently nothing happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either a text node should be added to the component tag and the body written to it;&lt;br/&gt;
Or a warning/exception should occur if for some reason it is preferred to not let this method succeed when the component tag has no body yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t see the use of the latter, so I recommend the former be implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now it&apos;s just confusing and dangerous.  If I give my HTML to a web designed and he changes a few empty HTML tags to short tags, I&apos;ll never be warned, but my output WILL be broken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12444302">WICKET-2650</key>
            <summary>Consistently create body for short tags.</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="jdonnerstag">Juegen Donnerstag</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="lhunath">Maarten Billemont</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Tue, 29 Dec 2009 10:58:02 +0000</created>
                <updated>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 20:09:41 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 20:09:41 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.4.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.5-RC6</fixVersion>
                                    <component>wicket</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>1</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12795036" author="lhunath" created="Tue, 29 Dec 2009 11:03:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I believe the short tag is already expanded for certain components/tags, such as div/span?  Either way; this should be consistent across all of the tag handling and be taken out where it exists currently.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12795039" author="jdonnerstag" created="Tue, 29 Dec 2009 12:02:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It is not that simple. &lt;br/&gt;
1) Obviously open/close tags are perfectly valid. &lt;br/&gt;
2) We check the tag and if it is open than we render the body - whatever that body is and which ever way the user wants to do it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How shall Wicket know upfornt that you&apos;ll be rendering the body yourself? Without a better reason I&apos;m not in favor to switch to &quot;always render the body and than based on the text generate determine what to do...&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some Components require a body text and thus accept open/close tags which the Component itself manually changes via subclassing onComponentTagBody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want ALL your wicket tags to have a body, simply create a filter and add it to your application. You may copy and modify OpenCloseTagExpander for that purpose&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can imagine there are specific use cases (like &amp;lt;a wicket:id=  &amp;gt;/) currently not automatically covered by Wicket and I&apos;m more than open to adjust any of the existing filters or add a new one. But I&apos;m -1 on changing all &amp;lt;xxx wicket:id= ../&amp;gt; to open-body-close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be you can provide a filter implementation which implements these use cases and I&apos;m more than happy to take a look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, via the filter you can implement both: automatically change open-close to open-body-close, throw an exception or log a warning.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12795257" author="martin-g" created="Wed, 30 Dec 2009 08:49:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As far as I remember expanding of div and span was added to overcome a bug in Firefox (maybe version 2.x). So Wicket is trying to help the user here.&lt;br/&gt;
I don&apos;t agree that Wicket should fix developer/webdesigner errors, like &amp;lt;a href=&quot;&quot; ... /&amp;gt;. Especially I don&apos;t want to see any of my &amp;lt;img /&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;input /&amp;gt; expanded.&lt;br/&gt;
There are helper utils in Wicket like devutils&apos; Filter for &amp;lt;img src=&quot;&quot; /&amp;gt; (image empty source location) which are there to help me and extending them to warn me about my coding mistakes would be great.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12795266" author="lhunath" created="Wed, 30 Dec 2009 09:19:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hmm; I hadn&apos;t seen OpenCloseTagExpander yet.  Interesting approach; but appears to be lacking a few tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps we should just add all HTML elements which are designed to have a body to it, such as:&lt;br/&gt;
a, q, sub, sup, abbr, acronym, cite, code, del, dfn, em, ins, kbd, samp, var, label, textarea, tr, td, th, caption, thead, tbody, tfoot, dl, dt, dd, li, ol, ul, h1-6, pre, title&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For these elements, there is no advantage whatsoever to keeping them open/close rather than open/body/close, while there is advantage to converting them to open/body/close.  In that light I don&apos;t see why we should not do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, OpenCloseTagExpander seems like a nice but very incomplete filter.  The approach it takes is one to change a set of tags, but there is no logic or consistency behind what tags are in the set.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12795336" author="jdonnerstag" created="Wed, 30 Dec 2009 15:44:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Added ExtendedOpenCloseTagExpander to core which is NOT automatically added. Please see the javadocs for how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12836890" author="lhunath" created="Mon, 22 Feb 2010 20:43:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So; what is the reason to not add this one automatically?  I see a lot of benefit from it and not sure I can see any reason why it would be disadvantageous.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12837557" author="ivaynberg" created="Wed, 24 Feb 2010 01:03:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;we cannot change the behavior in wicket-1.4.x but in trunk i changed the default to work like extended&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13051740" author="lhunath" created="Sun, 19 Jun 2011 22:16:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Am I being daft or is ExtendedOpenCloseTagExpander&apos;s contains missing a &quot;super.contains(name) || &quot;?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13051810" author="lhunath" created="Mon, 20 Jun 2011 05:37:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I&apos;d like to propose the class be extended to include all new HTML5 elements that are defined to allow a content.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13052028" author="jdonnerstag" created="Mon, 20 Jun 2011 16:06:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;  missing a &quot;super.contains(name) || &quot;? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.4: since super.contains() is missing, only the &quot;new&quot; tags are opened =&amp;gt; add super.contains()&lt;br/&gt;
1.5: registers the old and the new one, but with a comment &quot;leave the old one&apos;s in for backwards compatibility reason&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t want to change all tags automatically (same as Martin), including new html5 elements. Please provide a list and an explanation why they should be considered. Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13052556" author="lhunath" created="Tue, 21 Jun 2011 13:30:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The list would include every single tag from the HTML5 specification that has a non-empty content model.  When the HTML specification specifies that a body on the element is legal, we can expand it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13053434" author="jdonnerstag" created="Wed, 22 Jun 2011 20:09:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;fixed&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>70233</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            14 years, 22 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i0kctb:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>116893</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>