<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Sat Nov 08 22:19:53 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[WICKET-2949] Select does not work properly in functional flows e.g. Wizards</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/WICKET-2949</link>
                <project id="12310561" key="WICKET">Wicket</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Select FormComponent for rendering drop-downs is used inside a WizardStep that has a form-submitting back-button with defaultFormProcessing=false, the following effect is possible: Say there are three WizardSteps in a row, and the one with the Select is the middle one. Now say that we first move through the first two steps successfully, with changes to the Model being applied since validation results are ok. Then say we go back to the first step (the Model remaining unchanged during this navigation because in fact all our back-buttons have defaultFormProcessing=false).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the problem. If we now from this point go back and forth between the first and the second step, without changing any selections or data, we may not get the result that we would like to see, i.e. that the selected values are kept (re-validated and reapplied to the model, but never changed to other values). But, for example, on going forward to the second step, we may observe the drop-down showing a default value rather than the expected unchanged value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this happens when the back-button is a form-submitting button with defaultFormProcessing=false that generates raw input on the form, which in case of the Select is a path including the current page version. Then, when we are in step one, we use the next-button to go forward. The Select is being re-rendered and during this phase it checks itself if there is raw input. Indeed, there is, but the path does not match any option, because the page version is now a newer one. Thus, the Select might think it has invalid input, but it does not complain. Instead, it assumes null or empty string as input which leads it to render with the default value being selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I cannot supply an example for this since we use a copyrighted wizard and i currently have no time to set up an example based on the original wicket-extensions wizard. But it would be great if someone could follow this report and check carefully whether this is really always a problem, and how to fix it. I am going to try a workaround in my case where the Select does &quot;ignore&quot; the page version in the paths. I am not sure yet if there are more problems on the road with this approach.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment>Java 5 Tomcat 5.5.28, Java 6 Tomcat 6.0</environment>
        <key id="12469471">WICKET-2949</key>
            <summary>Select does not work properly in functional flows e.g. Wizards</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="svenmeier">Sven Meier</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="sludwig">Sven Ludwig</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 17:09:39 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 16:30:43 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 16:30:42 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>1.4.9</version>
                                    <fixVersion>1.4.20</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>1.5.5</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>6.0.0-beta1</fixVersion>
                                    <component>wicket-extensions</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>1</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12889819" author="sludwig" created="Mon, 19 Jul 2010 11:14:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I have now created a fix of the central method Select.isSelected. In my version, if hasRawInput returns true but getInputAsArray (which only looks at the request itself) returns null, getRawInput is used to get the raw input from the form. Subsequently, the raw input is splitted by &apos;;&apos; and thus the paths are obtained. If there are one or more paths, the option(s) are selected that match these paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To account for an older page version in the paths in the raw input, I also changed the comparison of the paths so that the page version is effectively ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If getRawInput should return null for a nullable Select, the behavior of isSelected is the same as in the 1.4.9 version when hasRawInput returns true but getInputAsArray returns nothing and no option is selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please find the code attached.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12902240" author="ivaynberg" created="Wed, 25 Aug 2010 01:03:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;please create a quickstart that reproduces the problem and reopen the issue. your description is pretty hard to follow and would be hard to recreate. also please attach your changes in a form of a patch. thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13194847" author="svenmeier" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2012 15:26:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;quickstart showing the problem&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13194895" author="svenmeier" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2012 16:30:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;getRawInput() is now used, making sure no new request intervenes with its parameters&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12449845" name="alternative_isSelected_20100719_sludwig.txt" size="2410" author="sludwig" created="Mon, 19 Jul 2010 14:38:44 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12512179" name="wicket2949.zip" size="8924" author="svenmeier" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2012 15:26:31 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>203788</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            13 years, 43 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i0kc5z:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>116788</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>