<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 03:38:24 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-4679] HTML line breaks (&lt;br&gt;) are removed during indexing; causes wrong search results</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-4679</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;HTML line breaks (&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;BR&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;, ...) seem to be removed during extraction of content from HTML-Files. They need to be replaced with a empty space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test-File:&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Test mit HTML-Zeilenschaltungen&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
word1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;word2&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Some other words, a special name like linz&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;and another special name - vienna&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Solr-content-attribute contains the following text:&lt;br/&gt;
Test mit HTML-Zeilenschaltungen    &lt;br/&gt;
word1word2&lt;br/&gt;
Some other words, a special name like linzand another special name - vienna&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are not able to find the word &quot;linz&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use the ExtractingRequestHandler to put content into Solr. (wiki.apache.org/solr/ExtractingRequestHandler)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment>&lt;p&gt;Windows Server 2008 R2, Java 6, Tomcat 7&lt;/p&gt;</environment>
        <key id="12641032">SOLR-4679</key>
            <summary>HTML line breaks (&lt;br&gt;) are removed during indexing; causes wrong search results</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="uschindler">Uwe Schindler</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="christophs78">Christoph Stra&#223;er</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 5 Apr 2013 12:19:10 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 5 Oct 2013 10:19:09 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Fri, 9 Aug 2013 13:28:04 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>4.2</version>
                                    <fixVersion>4.5</fixVersion>
                                    <component>contrib - Solr Cell (Tika extraction)</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="13623575" author="christophs78" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 12:19:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;File to reproduce the issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13623578" author="christophs78" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 12:24:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Screenshots showing the issue within Solr-Console&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13625691" author="hossman" created="Mon, 8 Apr 2013 19:14:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;FYI, i&apos;ve confirmed this isn&apos;t a general problem with Tika 1.3 &amp;#8211; using the tika-app.jar with the &quot;--text&quot; option there is a newline generated in place of the &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; tag, so something about Solr&apos;s use of Tika is loosing this information...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;hossman@frisbee:~/tmp$ cat external.htm 
&amp;lt;html&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Test mit HTML-Zeilenschaltungen&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
word1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;word2&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;
Some other words, a special name like linz&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;and another special name - vienna
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;hossman@frisbee:~/tmp$ java -jar tika-app-1.3.jar --text external.htm 

word1
word2

Some other words, a special name like linz
and another special name - vienna


hossman@frisbee:~/tmp$ java -jar tika-app-1.3.jar --text external.htm | cat -vet
$
word1$
word2$
$
Some other words, a special name like linz$
and another special name - vienna$
$
$
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13626309" author="christophs78" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2013 06:52:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thank you for checking Tika.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as i understand &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/ExtractingRequestHandler&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://wiki.apache.org/solr/ExtractingRequestHandler&lt;/a&gt; extracts XHTML, not text. Tika XHTML-option-output looks okay too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Root issue - like you said - probably somewhere within Solr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;D:\temp\20130409&amp;gt;java -jar tika-app-1.3.jar --xml external.htm
&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&amp;gt;&amp;lt;html xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;Content-Length&quot; content=&quot;193&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;Content-Encoding&quot; content=&quot;windows-1252&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;Content-Type&quot; content=&quot;text/html; charset=windows-1252&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;resourceName&quot; content=&quot;external.htm&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;meta name=&quot;dc:title&quot; content=&quot;Test mit HTML-Zeilenschaltungen&quot;/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;title&amp;gt;Test mit HTML-Zeilenschaltungen&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
word1
word2

Some other words, a special name like linz
and another special name - vienna
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13626775" author="hossman" created="Tue, 9 Apr 2013 16:28:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Right ... i wonder if somewhere in the flow of SAX events these newline are being treated as &quot;ignorable whitespace&quot; ... i can&apos;t imagine why they would be, but that&apos;s the best guess i have at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13680538" author="hossman" created="Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:53:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;i did some experimenting and confirmed that the SolrContentHandler is getting ignorable whitespace SAX events for &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags in HTML &amp;#8211; which makes no sense to me, so i&apos;ve opened &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1134&quot; title=&quot;ContentHandler gets ignorable whitespace for &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags when parsing HTML&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-1134&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-1134&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to try and get to the bottom of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s possible that SolrContentHandler should be changed to &quot;fix&quot; this behavior, but not in any clear way i can see (if we start treating all ignorable whitespace as significant that would lead to other problems when there is in fact ignorable whitespace)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13680550" author="hossman" created="Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:59:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;patch includes a test demonstrating hte problem in Solr, and an example of how we could work around this in SolrContentHandler &#8211; but i don&apos;t think the workarround is a good idea ... not w/o a lot more careful thought about how all that extra ignorblae whitespace might affect people (not just from html docs, but from any other types of docs where Tika produces ignorable whitespace sax events)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13733328" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 8 Aug 2013 10:09:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;There is another occurence of this bug with PDF files (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-5124&quot; title=&quot;Solr glues word&#180;s when parsing PDFs under certan circumstances&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-5124&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-5124&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;). I think we should apply the workaround and make the ignoreable whitespace significant. In my opinion this is not a problem at all, because the Analyzer will remove this stuff in any case, so some additional whitespace would disappear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;i did some experimenting and confirmed that the SolrContentHandler is getting ignorable whitespace SAX events for &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags in HTML &#8211; which makes no sense to me, so i&apos;ve opened &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1134&quot; title=&quot;ContentHandler gets ignorable whitespace for &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags when parsing HTML&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-1134&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-1134&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to try and get to the bottom of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this bug and I was discussing about that since the early beginning in TIKA and I don&apos;t think it will change! TIKA uses ignorable whitespace for all text-only glue stuff, which was decided at the beginning of the project. I can find the mail from their lists; I was involved in that, too (because I applied some fixes for that to &quot;corectly produce&quot; ignorable whitespace in some parsers, which were missing to do this. I also added the XHTMLContentHandler stuff that makes &quot;block&quot; XHTML elements like &amp;lt;p/&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;div/&amp;gt; also emit a newline as ignoreable on the closing element, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-171&quot; title=&quot;New ContentHandler for plain text output that has no problem with missing white space after XHTML block tags&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-171&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-171&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FYI: &quot;ignoreable whitespace&quot; is XML semantics only, in (X)HTML this does not exist (it is handled differently, but is never reported by HTML parsers), so the idea in TIKA is to &quot;reuse&quot; (its a bit &quot;incorrect&quot;) the ignoreableWhitespace SAX event to report this &quot;added whitespace&quot;. The rule that was choosen in TIKA is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If you ignore all elements of HTML and only extract plain text, use the ignoreable whitespace. This is e.g. done by the TIKA&apos;s internal wrappers that produce plain text (TextOnlyContentHandler). They treat all ignoreable whitepsace as significant. Ignoreable whitespace is &lt;b&gt;only&lt;/b&gt; produced by TIKA so if it exists, you know that it is coming from TIKA.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If you want to keep the XHTML structure and you &quot;understand&quot; block tags and &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;, then you can ignore the ignorable whitespace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Regarding this guideline, your patch is correct and should be applied to solr.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13733337" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 8 Aug 2013 10:24:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The stuff with ignorableWhitespace was discussed between &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=jukkaz&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;jukkaz&quot;&gt;jukkaz&lt;/a&gt; and me in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-171&quot; title=&quot;New ContentHandler for plain text output that has no problem with missing white space after XHTML block tags&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-171&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-171&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I think this was the issue when we decided to emit ignorableWhitespace for all &quot;synthetic&quot; whitespace added to support text-only extraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=hossman&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;hossman&quot;&gt;hossman&lt;/a&gt;: I can take the issue if you like. I am +1 to committing your current patch, because it makes use of the stuff we decided in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-171&quot; title=&quot;New ContentHandler for plain text output that has no problem with missing white space after XHTML block tags&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-171&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-171&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In my opinion,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1134&quot; title=&quot;ContentHandler gets ignorable whitespace for &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags when parsing HTML&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-1134&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-1134&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is obsolete but you/I can add a comments there to explain &quot;one more time&quot; and document under which circumstances TIKA emits ignorableWhitepsace.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13733656" author="hossman" created="Thu, 8 Aug 2013 16:33:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Uwe: I defer to your judgement on this.  if you think the patch is hte right way to go, then +1 from me.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13733776" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 8 Aug 2013 18:02:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hoss: I just took this issue because it was unassigned and I was the one mandating to add ignorable whitespace at that time in TIKA. So Jukka and I decided this would be the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you are still not convinced with my argumentation, let me recapitulate TIKA&apos;s problems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;TIKA decided to use XHTML as its output format to report the parsed documents to the consumer. This is nice, because it allows to preserve some of the formatting (like bold fonts, paragraphs,...) originating from the original document. Of course most of this formatting is lost, but you can still &quot;detect&quot; things like emphasized text. By choosing XHTML as output format, of course TIKA must use XHTML formatting for new lines and similar. So whenever a line break is needed, the TIKA pasrer emits a &amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; tag or places the &quot;paragraph&quot; (in a PDF) inside a &amp;lt;p/&amp;gt; element. As we all know, HTML ignores formatting like newlines, tabs,... (all are treated as one single whitespace, so means like this regreplace: &lt;tt&gt;s/\s+/ /&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;On the other hand, TIKA wants to make it simple for people to extract the &lt;b&gt;plain text&lt;/b&gt; contents. With the XHTML-only approach this would be hard for the consumer. Because to add the correct newlines, the consumer has to fully understand XHTML and detect block elements and replace them by \n&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To support both usages of TIKA the idea was to embed this information which is unimportant to HTML (as HTML ignores whitespaces completely) as ignorableWhitespace as &quot;convenience&quot; for the user. A fully compliant XHTML consumer would not parse the ignoreable stuff. As it understands HTML it would detect a &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; element as a block element and format the output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solr unfortunately has some strange approach: It is mainly interested in the text only contents, so ideally when consuming the HTLL it could use &lt;tt&gt;WriteoutContentHandler(StringBuilder, BodyContentHandler(parserConmtentHandler)&lt;/tt&gt;. In that case TIKA would do the right thing automatically: It would extract only text from the body element and would use the &quot;convenience whitespace&quot; to format the text in ASCII-ART-like way (using tabs, newlines,...) &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Solr has a hybrid approach: It collects all into a content tag (which is similar to the above approcha), but the bug is that in contrast to TIKA&apos;s official WriteOutContentHandler it does not use the ignorable whitespace inserted for convenience. In addition TIKA also has a stack where it allows to process parts of the documents (like the title element or all &amp;lt;em&amp;gt; elements). In that case it has several StringBuilders in parallel that are populated with the contents. The problems are here too, but cannot be solved by using ignorable whitespace: e.g. one indexes only all &amp;lt;em&amp;gt; elements (which are inline HTML elements no block elements), there is no whitespace so all em elements would be glued together in the em field of your index... I just mention this, in my opinion the SolrContentHandler needs more work to &quot;correctly&quot; understand HTML and not just collect element names in a map!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to your complaint: You proposed to report the newlines as real &lt;tt&gt;character()&lt;/tt&gt; events - but this is not the right thing to do here. As I said, HTML does not know these characters, they are ignored. The &quot;formatting&quot; is done by the element names (like &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;div&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;table&amp;gt;). So the &quot;helper&quot; whitespace for text-only consumers should be inserted as ignorableWhitespace only, if we would add it to the real character data we would report things that every HTML parser (like nekohtml) would never report to the consumer. Nekohtml would also report this useless extra whitespace as ignorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The convenience here is that TIKA&apos;s XHTMLContentHandler used by all parsers is &quot;configured&quot; to help the text-only user, but don&apos;t hurt the HTML-only user. This differentiation is done by reporting the HTML element names (p, div, table, th, td, tr, abbr, em, strong,...) but also report the ASCII-ART-text-only content like TABs indide tables, newlines after block elements,... This is always done as ignorableWhitespace (for convenience), a real HTML parser must ignore it - and its correct to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="13733791" author="hossman" created="Thu, 8 Aug 2013 18:13:47 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because you are still not convinced with my argumentation, let me recapitulate TIKA&apos;s problems:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never said that ... you said &quot;I can take the issue if you like.&quot; and you explained why the existing patch should be committed &amp;#8211; i&apos;m totally willing to go along with that, so have at it.  it seems sketchy to me, but if that&apos;s the way Tika works that&apos;s the way tika works, you certainly understand it better then me, so i defer to your assesment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(as mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/TIKA-1134&quot; title=&quot;ContentHandler gets ignorable whitespace for &amp;lt;br&amp;gt; tags when parsing HTML&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;TIKA-1134&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;TIKA-1134&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; it would be nice if this type of behavior was better documented for people implementing their own ContentHandlers, but that&apos;s a Tika issue not a Solr issue.)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13733901" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 8 Aug 2013 19:50:30 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I never said that ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You somehow said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I defer to your judgement on this&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I assumed that you are still not 100% convinced. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case I will take the issue. In my opinion there is more work to be done with this crazy stack of StringBuilders to better handle the ignorableWhitepace when a new field begins/ends. Currently its insered after the block end tag, so it would go one up in the stack only. I have to think a little bit about it, but the fix in your patch is the easiest for now. And the maybe useless whitespace on some lower stacked StringBuilders is generally removed by text analysis.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13734469" author="christophs78" created="Fri, 9 Aug 2013 06:41:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@Uwe: Big thanks for taking care of this issue! &lt;br/&gt;
@Hoss Man: Thank you for your input!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13734759" author="jira-bot" created="Fri, 9 Aug 2013 13:26:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 1512296 from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=thetaphi&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;thetaphi&quot;&gt;thetaphi&lt;/a&gt; in branch &apos;dev/trunk&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://svn.apache.org/r1512296&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://svn.apache.org/r1512296&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-4679&quot; title=&quot;HTML line breaks (&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;) are removed during indexing; causes wrong search results&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-4679&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-4679&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-4908&quot; title=&quot;SolrContentHandler procuces glued words when extracting html&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-4908&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-4908&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-5124&quot; title=&quot;Solr glues word&#180;s when parsing PDFs under certan circumstances&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-5124&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-5124&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Text extracted from HTML or PDF files using Solr Cell was missing ignorable whitespace, which is inserted by TIKA for convenience to support plain text extraction without using the HTML elements. This bug resulted in glued words.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13734763" author="jira-bot" created="Fri, 9 Aug 2013 13:27:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 1512297 from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=thetaphi&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;thetaphi&quot;&gt;thetaphi&lt;/a&gt; in branch &apos;dev/branches/branch_4x&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://svn.apache.org/r1512297&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://svn.apache.org/r1512297&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Merged revision(s) 1512296 from lucene/dev/trunk:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-4679&quot; title=&quot;HTML line breaks (&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;) are removed during indexing; causes wrong search results&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-4679&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-4679&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-4908&quot; title=&quot;SolrContentHandler procuces glued words when extracting html&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-4908&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-4908&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-5124&quot; title=&quot;Solr glues word&#180;s when parsing PDFs under certan circumstances&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-5124&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-5124&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Text extracted from HTML or PDF files using Solr Cell was missing ignorable whitespace, which is inserted by TIKA for convenience to support plain text extraction without using the HTML elements. This bug resulted in glued words.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13787089" author="jpountz" created="Sat, 5 Oct 2013 10:19:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;4.5 release -&amp;gt; bulk close&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10032">
                    <name>Blocker</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is blocked by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12652243">TIKA-1134</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310000">
                    <name>Duplicate</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is duplicated by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12651642">SOLR-4908</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12662571">SOLR-5124</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12587277" name="SOLR-4679__weird_TIKA-1134.patch" size="2211" author="hossman" created="Tue, 11 Jun 2013 18:59:31 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12577207" name="Solr_HtmlLineBreak_Linz_NotFound.png" size="91460" author="christophs78" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 12:24:04 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12577208" name="Solr_HtmlLineBreak_Vienna.png" size="110771" author="christophs78" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 12:24:04 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12577206" name="external.htm" size="193" author="christophs78" created="Fri, 5 Apr 2013 12:19:56 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>4.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>321448</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            12 years, 7 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i1jgnj:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>321793</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>