<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:16:25 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-9524] SolrIndexSearcher.getIndexFingerprint uses dubious sunchronization</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9524</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9310&quot; title=&quot;PeerSync fails on a node restart due to IndexFingerPrint mismatch&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9310&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9310&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; we added more code that does some fingerprint caching in SolrIndexSearcher. However, the synchronization looks like it could be made more efficient and may have issues with correctness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/blob/branch_6x/solr/core/src/java/org/apache/solr/search/SolrIndexSearcher.java#L2371-L2385&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/blob/branch_6x/solr/core/src/java/org/apache/solr/search/SolrIndexSearcher.java#L2371-L2385&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the issues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Double checked locking needs use of volatile variables to ensure proper memory semantics.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;sync on a ConcurrentHashMap is usually a code smell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13005475">SOLR-9524</key>
            <summary>SolrIndexSearcher.getIndexFingerprint uses dubious sunchronization</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="noble.paul">Noble Paul</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="mdrob">Mike Drob</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:03:08 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 8 Jun 2019 15:31:36 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 06:05:48 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>6.3</version>
                                    <fixVersion>6.3</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>7.0</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>9</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="15496673" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:06:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Might not actually be DCL because we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; reload the value. I still think this method can be cleaned up though.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15496691" author="yseeley@gmail.com" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:11:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&apos;t be a DCL anti-pattern (i.e. not thread safe) in either case because the underlying cache is thread safe.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15496722" author="mbraun688" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:22:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;maxVersionFingerprintCache.computeIfAbsent seems a good replacement for this functionality but there is a comment about the operation being possibly expensive such that one may want to actually block on multiple threads calculating the same value, which computeIfAbsent will not do. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15496733" author="mbraun688" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:27:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The existing code actually seems to have a bug in a different way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;      fingerprint = maxVersionFingerprintCache.get(maxVersionFingerprintCache);
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s looking its own reference up instead of the maxVersion long, which it checks earlier (and puts as). &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15496737" author="yseeley@gmail.com" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 16:29:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Ha - nice catch!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497002" author="yseeley@gmail.com" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:21:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9310&quot; title=&quot;PeerSync fails on a node restart due to IndexFingerPrint mismatch&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9310&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9310&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has already been released (5.5.3?), we can&apos;t re-open it to fix.  Might as well just use this JIRA?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497213" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 19:53:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Chatted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=mbraun688&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;mbraun688&quot;&gt;mbraun688&lt;/a&gt; about this a bit...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think &lt;tt&gt;computeIfAbsent&lt;/tt&gt; is close to what we want, but it doesn&apos;t let us easily preserve the current behaviour to throw &lt;tt&gt;IOException&lt;/tt&gt; - we&apos;d have to wrap it as an RTE. I&apos;m also a little sceptical of the claim that multiple threads would be attempting to calculate the same fingerprint, since this is only called when we open a new searcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ll agree that it may be expensive, but I don&apos;t what code paths we are trying to protect against. And I think we&apos;d get much better gains by doing the optimizations at the lower level... There&apos;s a note in IndexFingerprint that &lt;tt&gt;// TODO: this could be parallelized, or even cached per-segment if performance becomes an issue&lt;/tt&gt;, which I think is where we should look instead of trying to ensure that a fingerprint is only calculated once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; need to ensure that each fingerprint is only calculated once for performance issues, then we should switch to a more granular locking mechanism. Possibly something like striped locking, or a parallel Map&amp;lt;Long, Lock&amp;gt;. This is a lot more complexity.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497247" author="mbraun688" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:14:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=mdrob&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;mdrob&quot;&gt;mdrob&lt;/a&gt; it&apos;s not as pretty as computeifAbsent but it probably make sense from an exception point of view to keep it as is and possibly change the synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497252" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:18:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;tt&gt;ConcurrentHashMap.computeIfAbsent&lt;/tt&gt; javadoc though, &quot;the entire method invocation is performed atomically, so the function is applied at most once per key.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we&apos;re willing to live with the clunky exception handling it requires, then I&apos;m back on board with that approach.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497259" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:21:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;And looking at the Oracle JDK 8 implementation, I&apos;m reasonably convinced that this is the correct way to go.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497260" author="mbraun688" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:21:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Whoops sorry &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=mdrob&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;mdrob&quot;&gt;mdrob&lt;/a&gt; I was looking at the wrong function! Ignore my previous comment re: not preferring computeIfAbsent.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497285" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:33:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attaching a patch for master branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=yonik%40apache.org&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;yonik@apache.org&quot;&gt;yonik@apache.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=noble.paul&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;noble.paul&quot;&gt;noble.paul&lt;/a&gt; - you&apos;ve been in this code most recently, what do you think?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497304" author="yseeley@gmail.com" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:41:41 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m also a little sceptical of the claim that multiple threads would be attempting to calculate the same fingerprint&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a new leader is elected, I think everyone peersyncs to that leader.&lt;br/&gt;
When I originally wrote the code it was just a single fingerprint value (no max rolled in), and so it made sense to cache (since the common case is multiple replicas asking for the same info around the same time).  After the code was modified to use maxversion, it&apos;s less clear what the overlap will be, but if everyone is already in sync, it should still be high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; There&apos;s a note in IndexFingerprint that // TODO: this could be parallelized, or even cached per-segment if performance becomes an issue, which I think is where we should look instead of trying to ensure that a fingerprint is only calculated once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t see those as exclusive... caching a top-level fingerprint is desirable until we have per-segment caching.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497337" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:54:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yea, that makes sense. I&apos;m much less worried about correctness and efficiency when we can delegate to the JDK and trust them to do it correctly.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497429" author="dsmiley" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 21:27:23 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;RE computeIfAbsent and IOException:   I recent reviewed some code and gave feedback on an issue pertaining to this (I can&apos;t seen to find right it now).  The code on whatever issue it was could have theoretically used computeIfAbsent and would thus have been much nicer were it not for the IOException.  So we couldn&apos;t use it; &lt;em&gt;what a pain, sigh...&lt;/em&gt;.  If we want to use it here too (were it not for IOException) we might want to add a utility to make this easy so that the semantics of what we&apos;re doing is clear.  computeIfAbsent is beautiful when you can use it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497474" author="praste" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 21:47:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The reason I didn&apos;t use computeIfAbsent is computing fingerprint could throw an exception. Code to account for exception looks pretty ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also seems like some changes to the original patch, I dont remember using ConcurrentHashmap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will double check though.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497481" author="praste" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 21:49:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;PS : We are planning to cache fingerprint per segment under Solr-9506&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497495" author="praste" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 21:54:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;May be we should hold off 6.2.1 release&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15497566" author="praste" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 22:19:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Nice catch. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May be we should right a test case, now that twice fingerprint caching got us in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15498410" author="noble.paul" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2016 07:13:17 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;fingerprint = maxVersionFingerprintCache.get(maxVersionFingerprintCache);&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LOL, nice bug.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;May be we should hold off 6.2.1 release&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=praste&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;praste&quot;&gt;praste&lt;/a&gt; I don&apos;t think it&apos;s a big deal. Essentially it&apos;s just made caching useless. We didn&apos;t have any caching till now. So, it is not going to be any worse than what it used to be &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15499113" author="yseeley@gmail.com" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2016 14:22:03 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We didn&apos;t have any caching till now. So, it is not going to be any worse than what it used to be&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was cached before &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9310&quot; title=&quot;PeerSync fails on a node restart due to IndexFingerPrint mismatch&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9310&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9310&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, so if everyone was in sync (say coming back up from a reboot, or after electing a new leader), it could certainly be more expensive than it was.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15499123" author="mdrob" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2016 14:28:09 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RE computeIfAbsent and IOException: I recent reviewed some code and gave feedback on an issue pertaining to this (I can&apos;t seen to find right it now). The code on whatever issue it was could have theoretically used computeIfAbsent and would thus have been much nicer were it not for the IOException. So we couldn&apos;t use it; what a pain, sigh.... If we want to use it here too (were it not for IOException) we might want to add a utility to make this easy so that the semantics of what we&apos;re doing is clear. computeIfAbsent is beautiful when you can use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been poking at this, but due to some quirks of java generics, it&apos;s harder to put in a generic utility than it would appear at first blush. Going down this route, we may have to limit ourselves strictly to IOException.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think it&apos;s a big deal. Essentially it&apos;s just made caching useless. We didn&apos;t have any caching till now. So, it is not going to be any worse than what it used to be&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It only made the second check useless. The first check and the put are still correct, so we will still have some amount of caching right now, but multiple threads asking at once could end up all doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15499190" author="praste" created="Sat, 17 Sep 2016 15:17:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I will look through logs of our collections (fortunately we have plenty of those) and see how expensive is fingerprint computation. There is already a ticket @noble opened for caching fingerprint per segment. I am going to get to it next week.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15507625" author="mdrob" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2016 19:57:42 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will look through logs of our collections (fortunately we have plenty of those) and see how expensive is fingerprint computation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=praste&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;praste&quot;&gt;praste&lt;/a&gt; - did you get a chance to verify this? I tried to check on our systems, but the first few deployments I looked at were all on versions before index fingerprinting.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15507812" author="praste" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2016 21:14:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I checked logs on one of our biggest collection with following stats&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;num docs: 1591412892&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;shards: 12&lt;/tt&gt; spread across two solr instances (each process hosts 6 shards and each instance runs on separate physical box).&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;auto soft commit : 1 secs&lt;/tt&gt; (not sure this matters as computing fingerprint opens a new NR searcher anyway)&lt;br/&gt;
There is replication too but I don&apos;t think that matters a lot here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is typically taking  ~2 seconds on avg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This definitely requires caching. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to take on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9506&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;SOLR-9506&lt;/a&gt; this week. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15508053" author="mdrob" created="Tue, 20 Sep 2016 22:52:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for looking. I agree that &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9506&quot; title=&quot;cache IndexFingerprint for each segment&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9506&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9506&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; would be a good improvement too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I didn&apos;t use computeIfAbsent is computing fingerprint could throw an exception. Code to account for exception looks pretty ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also seems like some changes to the original patch, I dont remember using ConcurrentHashmap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CHM was added in commit 37ae065 by Noble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the ugliness of the code around exception handling here is a fine tradeoff for the correctness issue that we&apos;ve already seen and the performance issue of locking on the whole map. If you have 5 fingerprints to calculate, then the current code will need 10 seconds total since each calculation can only happen serially. Letting computeIfAbsent manage the concurrent access for us seems much much better.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15508867" author="jira-bot" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2016 06:00:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit afc57347b47322290d6b0e6c00e4e3413ce2fbf0 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=noble.paul&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;noble.paul&quot;&gt;noble.paul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=afc5734&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=afc5734&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9524&quot; title=&quot;SolrIndexSearcher.getIndexFingerprint uses dubious sunchronization&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9524&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9524&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: SolrIndexSearcher.getIndexFingerprint uses dubious synchronization&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15508879" author="jira-bot" created="Wed, 21 Sep 2016 06:05:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 7a1e6efa9678f9cdfb3f59f61fba6e60e725f3a7 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_6x from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=noble.paul&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;noble.paul&quot;&gt;noble.paul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=7a1e6ef&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=7a1e6ef&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9524&quot; title=&quot;SolrIndexSearcher.getIndexFingerprint uses dubious sunchronization&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9524&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9524&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: SolrIndexSearcher.getIndexFingerprint uses dubious synchronization&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15547393" author="yseeley@gmail.com" created="Wed, 5 Oct 2016 02:21:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I wonder if we could use the same type of logic for UnInvertedField.getUnInvertedField().... perhaps by adding an additional method to SolrCache that takes a creator?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15650293" author="shalinmangar" created="Wed, 9 Nov 2016 08:38:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Closing after 6.3.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12989898">SOLR-9310</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12828894" name="SOLR-9524.patch" size="2412" author="mdrob" created="Fri, 16 Sep 2016 20:33:09 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>1.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            9 years, 1 week, 6 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i33py7:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>