<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:19:17 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-10031] ReplicationHandler path traversal vulnerability</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-10031</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Fra: Mark Thomas &amp;lt;markt@apache.org&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Emne: Fwd: Apache Solr - security vulnerability (path traversal attack)&lt;br/&gt;
Dato: 24. januar 2017 kl. 13.14.36 CET&lt;br/&gt;
Til: private@lucene.apache.org&lt;br/&gt;
Kopi: &quot;security@apache.org&quot; &amp;lt;security@apache.org&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Svar til: private@lucene.apache.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Apache Lucene PMC,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security vulnerability report has been received by the Apache&lt;br/&gt;
Security Team and is being passed to you for action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take careful note of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;This information is private and should be treated accordingly. The&lt;br/&gt;
issue must not be discussed on a public mailing list, it must not be&lt;br/&gt;
added to a public bug tracker, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Lucene PMC is responsible for resolving this issue. The security&lt;br/&gt;
team is here to provide help and advice but the responsibility to do the&lt;br/&gt;
work lies with the Lucene PMC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You may find the &quot;ASF Project Security for Committers&quot; &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;1&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; a useful&lt;br/&gt;
reference. This e-mail represents step three of that process. Step 4&lt;br/&gt;
should be completed asap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;1&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apache.org/security/committers.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://www.apache.org/security/committers.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;-------- Forwarded Message --------&lt;br/&gt;
Subject: 	Apache Solr - security vulnerability (path traversal attack)&lt;br/&gt;
Date: 	Mon, 23 Jan 2017 11:27:19 -0800&lt;br/&gt;
From: 	Hrishikesh Gadre &amp;lt;gadre.solr@gmail.com&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To: 	security@apache.org&lt;br/&gt;
CC: 	Hrishikesh Gadre &amp;lt;gadre.solr@gmail.com&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a path manipulation security vulnerability in Apache Solr after&lt;br/&gt;
running HPE Fortify static code analyzer on the Solr codebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a brief description of this issue,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Apache Solr provides a &quot;replication&quot; handler which supports operations&lt;br/&gt;
related to querying the state of an index as well as copying files&lt;br/&gt;
associated with the index.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/solr/Index+Replication&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/solr/Index+Replication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/solr/Index+Replication&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/solr/Index+Replication&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This handler supports an HTTP API&lt;br/&gt;
(/replication?command=filecontent&amp;amp;file=&amp;lt;file_name&amp;gt;) which is vulnerable&lt;br/&gt;
to path traversal attack. Specifically, this API does not perform any&lt;br/&gt;
validation of the user specified file_name parameter. This can allow an&lt;br/&gt;
attacker to download &lt;b&gt;any&lt;/b&gt; file readable to Solr server process even if&lt;br/&gt;
it is not related to the actual Solr index state.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Path_Traversal&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Path_Traversal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have verified this with the Solr version 6.3. But I believe this&lt;br/&gt;
vulnerability to be present for much longer (going back to v 4.10.x) . I&lt;br/&gt;
am currently working on the fix. Please let me know the process to&lt;br/&gt;
submit a patch for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;br/&gt;
Hrishikesh&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13037696">SOLR-10031</key>
            <summary>ReplicationHandler path traversal vulnerability</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="janhoy">Jan H&#248;ydahl</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="janhoy">Jan H&#248;ydahl</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:27:30 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 8 Jun 2019 15:29:58 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 22:55:08 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>6.4</version>
                                    <fixVersion>5.5.4</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>6.4.1</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>7.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>replication (java)</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>6</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="15837749" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:39:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch with test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not tested explicitly that you can actually get files from parent folders with an unpatched system, is that necessary? The fix throws an HTTP 403 if file name is absolute or contains &quot;..&quot;, or if it is not a legal file name. Should we add other checks?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837755" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:45:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Just saw that the reporter also prepared a similar patch (attached path_traversal_fix.patch).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837762" author="thetaphi" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:49:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I like your patch more, especially the whole &quot;legacy&quot; Stack class looks not good. This one uses Path class, which would allow to implement the whole thing much easier.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837781" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:05:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I see that my patch will throw an error for file names validly containing the string sequence &lt;tt&gt;..&lt;/tt&gt;. It would be nicer to detect only if the whole path segment is exactly &quot;..&quot;. I&apos;ll post a patch which uses &lt;tt&gt;Path.forEach( action )&lt;/tt&gt; for this&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837786" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:11:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;New patch which loops path components.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837806" author="thetaphi" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:25:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only difference to the bug reporter&apos;s patch is that he uses a stack to look if it &quot;really escapes&quot;. But I think we should simply forbid all &quot;..&quot; anywhere in patch. If somebody tries to use this it is always some break-in attack.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837812" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:31:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Another difference is that Hrishikesh&apos;s test only tests the FILE param, while the same vulnerability is in &lt;tt&gt;cf&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;tlogFile&lt;/tt&gt; too. And I also disallow absolute paths, though I&apos;m not sure if that is allowed in &lt;tt&gt;new File(path, file)&lt;/tt&gt; anyway. His checks are in the calling code while mine is in the &lt;tt&gt;DirectoryFileStream&lt;/tt&gt; constructor, guess as low as possible is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837822" author="thetaphi" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:36:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Absolute paths should definitely be disallowed!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837847" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:48:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;New patch that does not reveal the vulnerability in the CHANGES entry&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837877" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 15:10:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;For the record, the vulnerability is ACK&apos;ed and we have requested a CVE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could be argued whether it is a real vulnerability since we recommend a firewalled setup, and the user running Solr should have limited privileges.. But there are enough installs where IT employees may have HTTP access to a Solr instance but are not allowed file-system access to the same box, so this one is a bit special.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15837909" author="thetaphi" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 15:28:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;FYI, I just made the following proposal for the future on the private@lao list, which should also prevent issues like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this issue should be seen as a first request for running Apache Solr in a security manager with a suitable prolicy file (like we do in tests). Elasticsearch has gone this route and I like that very much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solr should install the security manager and policy in its main() methods before Jetty is starting. There it should restrict access to the installation folder, maybe we can even go further. It should also prevent stuff like calling System.exit() from plugins. This is especially important for all stuff that may execute java code (like Javascript in DIH or similar).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839392" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 07:53:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;CVE received from Mark Cox:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, please use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVE-2017-3163&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839395" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 07:57:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Trying to understand the next step in the process. The policy says the commit message should not reveal the security breach until after release. But can we mention it in CHANGES.txt? How else&apos;s will people be aware of the importance of the fix?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839414" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 08:30:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Have a more generic message including a reference to this issue. But don&apos;t say &lt;b&gt;what&lt;/b&gt; exactly was wrong. Don&apos;t mention the CVE number.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839555" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 10:54:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So if we don&apos;t mention that a security issue was fixed anywhere in the released artifacts, then we do the release and rewrite the commit message, fine. But how do we communicate to the users/downloaders that this release actually fixes the given CVE? We can do it in the release announcement of course, and perhaps in the refGuide which is (currently) released after the binaries (although later on the refGuide will be released together).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see that ES has a separate security fixes webpage, perhaps that is a solution, so that people monitoring whether they should upgrade Solr due to CVEs could have one place to look it up?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839593" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 11:37:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;When doing the same with the issues about remote code injection (XXE attachs) in OpenOffice/MS-Office documents (it was SVN times), I did the following (was mainly on project POI, but also affected TIKA and Solr):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;alternate&quot; type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I committed stuff using the issue ID, not mentioning the security issue. I just said: &quot;Issue XXX. Restricted external entity resolving.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In the announcement on the web page I added the CVE numbers, the same in the announcement mail (you can still see those in the Solr News page, POI News page): &lt;a href=&quot;https://lucene.apache.org/solr/news.html#18-august-2014-recommendation-to-update-apache-poi-in-apache-solr-480-481-and-490-installations&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://lucene.apache.org/solr/news.html#18-august-2014-recommendation-to-update-apache-poi-in-apache-solr-480-481-and-490-installations&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://poi.apache.org/changes.html#Summary-N11D34&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://poi.apache.org/changes.html#Summary-N11D34&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;After the release, I changed the SVN commit messages (not sure if you can do this in Git, without breaking checkouts).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The CVE numbers were added to the issue (which were public) afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think the most important thing is to have the release notes especially mention the  issue and CVE numbers and tell user: &quot;hey upgrade, there is an issue&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839842" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 15:16:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Ok, I have not run full tests and precommit with this yet. Have to go now, feel free to take over for a while so we can get it in 6.4.1 in time (without revealing that this JIRA contains a CVE on the public dev-list)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15839851" author="thetaphi" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 15:19:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;OK, if you have some time you can commit the stuff, otherwise I will do this before Adrien spins 6.4.1.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15840610" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 26 Jan 2017 22:57:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Passing precommit. Cannot get test suite to ever pass 100% but the failures are not related, and running only &lt;tt&gt;TestReplicationHandler&lt;/tt&gt; succeeds.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15843325" author="cpoerschke" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2017 18:55:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The replication handler is one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/blob/master/solr/core/src/resources/ImplicitPlugins.json#L38-L41&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;implicit plugins&lt;/a&gt; now, previously presumably it always needed to be configured in solrconfig.xml (and some of the test files still do that e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/blob/master/solr/core/src/test-files/solr/collection1/conf/solrconfig-master.xml#L35-L43&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might it be worth mentioning somehow somewhere (afterwards) that the replication handler &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; configurable and that configuring a (custom) ReplicationHandler class with the fix would be an interim way of getting the fix without the upgrade?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would be sending a mixed message then though, whereas &quot;upgrade recommended&quot; is a clear message and anyone wishing to build and deploy a custom patched replication handler would probably have that idea by themselves anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15843458" author="janhoy" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2017 20:35:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hmm, are you thinking about people using 5.5.3, which is also a &quot;supported&quot; version. I think perhaps that once we acknowledge it as a security risk we should consider plugging the hole in 5.x with a 5.5.4 bugfix release. It&apos;s a small patch which should be easy enough to backport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this should be coordinated so 5.x people have a true quick upgrade path once the announcement is made?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could also create a Wiki page for the CVE explaining what the risk is, how to exploit it and how to work around it if you cannot upgrade, such as turning off replication  if you don&apos;t use it, making sure no untrusted clients have access to the /replication endpoint etc.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15843545" author="janhoy" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2017 21:55:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Attaching patch backport to 5_5.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15843688" author="janhoy" created="Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:14:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;New patch crediting Hrishikesh Gadre and removing unnecessary positive test. Think this is ready to go in&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15844677" author="janhoy" created="Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:31:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed&lt;br/&gt;
master: 6f598d24692a89da9b5b671be6cf4b947aa39266&lt;br/&gt;
branch_6x: 7088137d52256354a52ed86547b9faa0e7042934&lt;br/&gt;
branch_6_4: 3a4f885b18bc963a8326c752bd229497908f1dbc&lt;br/&gt;
branch_5_5: ae789c252687dc8a18bfdb677f2e6cd14570e4db&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15846161" author="janhoy" created="Mon, 30 Jan 2017 23:44:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Resolving since all code has landed in the branches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reminder: Post release we need to make a security announcement, make this JIRA public and rewrite the GIT commit log. msg.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15868755" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 15 Feb 2017 22:53:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Reopening to make public&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15868759" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 15 Feb 2017 22:54:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Issue made public now that ANNOUNCEMENT is made and 5.5.4 includes the fix.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12849782" name="SOLR-10031.patch" size="4160" author="janhoy" created="Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:14:42 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12849300" name="SOLR-10031.patch" size="4413" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:48:00 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12849294" name="SOLR-10031.patch" size="4531" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 14:11:03 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12849292" name="SOLR-10031.patch" size="4376" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:39:53 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12849758" name="SOLR-10031_branch5_5.patch" size="4916" author="janhoy" created="Fri, 27 Jan 2017 21:55:11 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12849293" name="path_traversal_fix.patch" size="4842" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:45:30 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>6.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            8 years, 39 weeks, 6 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i396qn:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>