<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:24:12 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-10915] Make SolrClient classes extendable without code duplication</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-10915</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;SolrClient used to be easily extendable but our move to Builder pattern has made it impossible to extend those classes without code duplication. &lt;br/&gt;
As an example, if we wanted to extend HttpSolrClient we would also want to extend the Builder. The problem is that the constructor of the main class, does not accept the builder object but explicit parameters, and the inherited class doesn&apos;t have access to any of those values from the Builder object as they are all private. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, we&apos;d want to have the client object constructor accept the Builder, instead of explicit values, and also make the Builder values protected so the inherited classes could use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m marking this as a blocker for 7.0 as this is an important piece that needs to be fixed before the major release, specially now that we know that this problem exists.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13080882">SOLR-10915</key>
            <summary>Make SolrClient classes extendable without code duplication</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/blocker.svg">Blocker</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="anshum">Anshum Gupta</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="anshum">Anshum Gupta</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 16:53:41 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 8 Jun 2019 15:23:00 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Sat, 24 Jun 2017 20:38:49 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>7.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>clients - java</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>5</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16054373" author="gerlowskija" created="Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:13:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is true.  Most (see below) of the SolrClient implementations have their constructors at protected visibility, so this is less of a problem with extending the SolrClients and more of a problem of being able to re-use the Builder code/pattern when you do so?  (I ask this not in an attempt to minimize the issue, but purely for clarification).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Related to this issue in my mind is the fact that CloudSolrClient &lt;b&gt;doesn&apos;t&lt;/b&gt; have a protected constructor.  This was raised on the mailing list, and a patch was put forward in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9535&quot; title=&quot;SolrClients should have protected constructors&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9535&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9535&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; .  Might be a good time to give that a little attention too, though it&apos;s not as important as the concerns you raise in this JIRA)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting back to this issue, I plan to push a patch for this tonight, unless you&apos;ve already started on it &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=anshumg&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;anshumg&quot;&gt;anshumg&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16054432" author="anshumg" created="Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:40:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=gerlowskija&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;gerlowskija&quot;&gt;gerlowskija&lt;/a&gt;, ideally I&apos;d want to build my extended client with something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;MyClient client = &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; MyBuilder().withBaseSolrUrl(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//myBaseUrl/solr&quot;&lt;/span&gt;).build();&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but MyBuilder wouldn&apos;t have access to anything from the parent Builder class. The constructor for the client would need the object and so we&apos;d have a deadlock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could just add a setter and get things taken care of there but I wouldn&apos;t be able to do anything at construction time. &lt;br/&gt;
Also, adding everything to the client itself instead of through the builder breaks how it should be extended in my opinion and shouldn&apos;t be recommended. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&apos;t started working on this but I know what to do. If you want to take a shot at it, go for it and I can review it and get this in.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16054443" author="anshumg" created="Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:43:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9535&quot; title=&quot;SolrClients should have protected constructors&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9535&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9535&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; seems to overlap with this to a reasonable extent. We could either commit this together as we&apos;re trying to solve the common problem of being able to extend the clients in a meaningful manner without duplicating code.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16054452" author="gerlowskija" created="Mon, 19 Jun 2017 17:46:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;That all makes sense; I&apos;ll do this later today (folding in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9535&quot; title=&quot;SolrClients should have protected constructors&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9535&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9535&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; changes as you suggested above).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16055711" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 13:01:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I made the changes pretty much exactly as you requested above Anshum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One question I had when making the changes was whether we also wanted to deprecate the existing constructors and remove any uses of them.  You didn&apos;t explicitly call for that in the issue description, but since one of the main goals of the builders was to cut down on constructor duplication/sprawl, it would make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&apos;ve uploaded two patches, one that leaves the existing constructors as-is, and another that deprecates the existing ctors and changes any calls to go to the builder-based constructor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both pass tests on &lt;tt&gt;master&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16055713" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 13:02:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;(Both patches contain the CloudSolrClient visibility change from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-9535&quot; title=&quot;SolrClients should have protected constructors&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-9535&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-9535&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that we said we&apos;d fold into this JIRA)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056009" author="elyograg" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 16:00:29 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;If I&apos;m understanding what&apos;s going on here, I really like it.  I hadn&apos;t thought of using the builder in the constructor ... that&apos;s a really good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds like this would make both the client itself and its builder user-extendable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did notice a couple of things in the patch, not sure if these are actual problems or a lack of understanding on my part:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Where a Builder class has been added, it doesn&apos;t have any explicit visibility, while the existing Builder classes are explicitly marked public.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The new Builder classes do not have any fluent &quot;with*&quot; methods, only a multiple-argument constructor.  The existing ones have simple constructors (no-arg and in some cases one-arg) and fluent methods for configuration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As for how to handle removal and deprecation ... are we at a point where we can simply remove the other constructors in master/branch_7x?  They should have already been deprecated when the Builder pattern was implemented.  The remaining non-deprecated constructor (before this patch) is likely private or protected, and I don&apos;t think we have any reason to worry about deprecating it before we change it to one that accepts a Builder.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056053" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 16:38:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;A few responses:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where a Builder class has been added, it doesn&apos;t have any explicit visibility, while the existing Builder classes are explicitly marked public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&apos;s a good point/question.  Most of the builders added in this patch were for trivial SolrClient subclasses that were only used in that same Java file. Because of that I didn&apos;t give visibility a ton of thought- I just left them as package-scoped.  But we could probably do something more thoughtful on a case-by-case basis here if it&apos;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new Builder classes do not have any fluent &quot;with*&quot; methods, only a multiple-argument constructor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The convention I&apos;ve been trying to follow is that truly required arguments should go in the &lt;tt&gt;Builder()&lt;/tt&gt; ctor, to force users to provide them.  Optional ones I&apos;ve been creating fluent &lt;tt&gt;withFoo&lt;/tt&gt; methods for.  The lack of added &lt;tt&gt;withFoo&lt;/tt&gt; methods in this patch is (I think) just a coincidence related to the sort of SolrClient subclasses I ran into with this patch (created with a very directed purpose, with limited visibility, for 1 or 2 Java files).  If I made any mistakes following that convention, or you would prefer deviating from the convention for other reasons, I&apos;d be fine with that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The remaining non-deprecated constructor (before this patch) is likely private or protected, and I don&apos;t think we have any reason to worry about deprecating it before we change it to one that accepts a Builder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That seems reasonable to me, but I also see an argument that methods marked as protected are a part of our API and we&apos;d need to give more warning.  Either way would be fine with me.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056177" author="anshumg" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 17:57:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Jason. The patch looks good overall but I think we should only have client constructors that accept the builder, and nothing else - even private constructors. Everything that is needed is a part of the builder object, and so can be extracted. That certainly means more work, but I think it is worth it. e.g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;// L209 in the patch
&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;protected&lt;/span&gt; CloudSolrClient(Builder builder) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;(builder.zkHosts, builder.zkChroot, builder.solrUrls, builder.httpClient, builder.loadBalancedSolrClient,
        builder.lbClientBuilder, builder.shardLeadersOnly, builder.directUpdatesToLeadersOnly, builder.stateProvider);
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should just move the implementation of that private constructor in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t personally have a strong opinion around &lt;tt&gt;withFoo&lt;/tt&gt; methods Vs those being a part of the constructor. As long as that list is restricted to &amp;lt; 3 params (almost an arbitrary number that&apos;s not too high), I don&apos;t have a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;That seems reasonable to me, but I also see an argument that methods marked as protected are a part of our API and we&apos;d need to give more warning. Either way would be fine with me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We aren&apos;t &apos;removing&apos; anything here but just deprecating so we should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056201" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 18:08:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think I&apos;m reading you wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;we should only have client constructors that accept the builder, and nothing else - even private constructors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We aren&apos;t &apos;removing&apos; anything here but just deprecating so we should be fine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;seem to conflict a little bit.  The first implies removing all constructors except the ones created by this patch.  The second (as I read it) says that we should be deprecating but not removing any constructors here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m fine with either approach, just wanted to clarify before updating the patch.  Sorry for the confusion on my part.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056210" author="anshumg" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 18:12:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Sorry about that confusion, should&apos;ve read what I wrote &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do intend to have only constructors that accept a builder object. Everything else that has never been released i.e. was added after the last release OR is private can be completely removed, and constructors that are protected/public should be marked as deprecated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this make sense?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056496" author="anshumg" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 21:28:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=gerlowskija&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;gerlowskija&quot;&gt;gerlowskija&lt;/a&gt; one more thing, can you have the extension of the patch be &lt;tt&gt;.patch&lt;/tt&gt; so my browser doesn&apos;t auto-download the file? &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16056564" author="anshumg" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 22:16:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s existing constructors that were released in 6.6, which need to be handled and either removed, or deprecated with our move to the single format constructor for SolrClients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=gerlowskija&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;gerlowskija&quot;&gt;gerlowskija&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=elyograg&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;elyograg&quot;&gt;elyograg&lt;/a&gt;, and I had a discussion on irc and decided that we shouldn&apos;t be going crazy with the code removal, and instead should just happily deprecate stuff. It does mean working around with the current code and leaving it unclean but considering this is publicly released code, it doesn&apos;t make sense to just remove it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s the approach that Jason suggested, which I think makes sense to handle existing constructors. This routes everything through the new Builder implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; HttpSolrClient(&lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt; url, ResponseParser parser, Foo foo, Bar bar) {
    &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;final&lt;/span&gt; HttpSolrClient.Builder builder = &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; HttpSolrClient.Builder(url).withResponseParser(parser).withFoo(foo)...;
    &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;(builder);
}

&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; HttpSolrClient(Builder builder) {
  &lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;/* actual constructor implementation/logic */&lt;/span&gt;
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16057321" author="gerlowskija" created="Wed, 21 Jun 2017 10:47:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Updated patch.  The only constructor I was able to remove outright was a private one in CloudSolrClient.  The others have been deprecated, with their implementations changed to call out to the Builder-based ctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tests pass.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16060113" author="anshumg" created="Thu, 22 Jun 2017 22:25:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Jason. Patch looks good. I&apos;ve fixed a typo here and there and removed &lt;tt&gt;SolrExampleTests.java&lt;/tt&gt; as it didn&apos;t really have any changes but just import reordering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s the updated patch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m running the tests and I&apos;ll commit once the tests pass.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16061165" author="anshumg" created="Fri, 23 Jun 2017 16:17:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m seeing some pre-commit failures. I&apos;ve fixed a couple of them, but there are more. Will commit once I fix them.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16061355" author="jira-bot" created="Fri, 23 Jun 2017 18:31:05 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit e46d39bd5a571522bb2b9ffe97e7e0bca5d9836c in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=anshumg&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;anshumg&quot;&gt;anshumg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=e46d39b&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=e46d39b&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-10915&quot; title=&quot;Make SolrClient classes extendable without code duplication&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-10915&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-10915&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Make builder based SolrClient constructors to be the only valid way to construct client objects and increase the visibility of builder elements to be protected so extending the builder, and the clients is possible.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16062048" author="mkhludnev" created="Sat, 24 Jun 2017 16:21:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I want to commit on top of &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;commit e43253312f965ba838d80c2000dee761df1f25f5
Author: Uwe Schindler &amp;lt;uschindler@apache.org&amp;gt;
Date:   Sat Jun 24 15:35:00 2017 +0200
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and having precommit errors &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;common.compile-test:&lt;br/&gt;
    [javac] Compiling 3 source files to /lucene-solr/solr/build/solr-solrj/classes/test&lt;br/&gt;
    [javac] /lucene-solr/solr/solrj/src/test/org/apache/solr/client/solrj/embedded/SolrExampleStreamingTest.java:143: error: non-static variable this cannot be referenced from a static context&lt;br/&gt;
    [javac]         return new ErrorTrackingConcurrentUpdateSolrClient(this);&lt;br/&gt;
    [javac]                ^&lt;/p&gt;
{qoute}
&lt;p&gt;is ok to push anyway? &lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16062058" author="anshumg" created="Sat, 24 Jun 2017 16:47:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=mkhludnev&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;mkhludnev&quot;&gt;mkhludnev&lt;/a&gt; did you intend to comment on this JIRA?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, if you are seeing pre-commit errors, you shouldn&apos;t be committing as it would break the build. Is this something you changed?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16062125" author="mkhludnev" created="Sat, 24 Jun 2017 20:52:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;ok. Sorry for buzz, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=anshumg&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;anshumg&quot;&gt;anshumg&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;tt&gt;ant clean&lt;/tt&gt; fixed it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310060">
                    <name>Container</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="contains">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13005994">SOLR-9535</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12874147" name="SOLR-10915.patch" size="37778" author="anshum" created="Thu, 22 Jun 2017 22:24:46 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12873848" name="SOLR-10915.patch" size="40785" author="gerlowskija" created="Wed, 21 Jun 2017 10:46:26 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12873676" name="SOLR-10915.patch.with-deprecations" size="32721" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:57:12 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12873675" name="SOLR-10915.patch.without-deprecations" size="10807" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 20 Jun 2017 12:57:17 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>4.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            8 years, 21 weeks, 3 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i3ggcn:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>