<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:29:46 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-11412] Documentation changes for SOLR-11003: Bi-directional CDCR support</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11412</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11003&quot; title=&quot;Enabling bi-directional CDCR on cluster for better failover&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11003&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11003&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Bi-directional CDCR scenario support, is reaching its conclusion. The relevant changes in documentation needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13105633">SOLR-11412</key>
            <summary>Documentation changes for SOLR-11003: Bi-directional CDCR support</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="ctargett">Cassandra Targett</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com">Amrit Sarkar</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 02:44:34 +0000</created>
                <updated>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 00:42:13 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 4 Dec 2017 20:32:27 +0000</resolved>
                                                    <fixVersion>7.2</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>8.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>CDCR</component>
                    <component>documentation</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>3</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16183595" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Thu, 28 Sep 2017 02:56:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;First draft uploaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three important bits left are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. CDCR architecture needs to be updated or a new one needs to be added.&lt;br/&gt;
2. The description below the architecture needs or needs not to be updated ??&lt;br/&gt;
3. The Initial Startup part: it is specifically written for uni-directional scenario, not sure whether a section for bi-directional scenario is required or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The buffer element portion is somewhat confusing too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the changes, I made sure user doesn&apos;t confuse much. Though a thorough review is must.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16183596" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Thu, 28 Sep 2017 03:00:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The most important: forget to mention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to specify or which places repeatedly that &lt;b&gt;one must and must not index in both cluster simultaneously.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16185252" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Fri, 29 Sep 2017 02:00:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch updated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Cdcr bidirectional architecture png and description: DONE&lt;br/&gt;
2. &lt;em&gt;one must and must not index in both cluster simultaneously.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Included in initial introduction and whenever deem necessary. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16185254" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Fri, 29 Sep 2017 02:03:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The CDCR page is getting larger and larger. If we can break the CDCR components in different pages, I guess that will be really helpful. Too much information in one page.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16257702" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Fri, 17 Nov 2017 22:43:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Fixed the patch and added Erick&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11635&quot; title=&quot;CDCR Source configuration example in the ref guide leaves out important settings&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11635&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11635&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to bi-dir CDCR configurations. Also updated Cdcr-bidir.png.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=varun&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;varun&quot;&gt;varun&lt;/a&gt; this is ready to go, and awaiting your review and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16261563" author="ctargett" created="Tue, 21 Nov 2017 21:59:02 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m taking a review of the new docs, and looking at splitting the page up at the same time. Splitting CDCR API into its own page is obvious, but thinking about how to split the rest, I came up with this possible structure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;cross-data-center-replication.adoc&lt;/tt&gt;: parent page with &quot;What is CDCR?&quot; and &quot;CDCR Glossary&quot; sections, and links to other pages (would live in same place under SolrCloud top-level section)
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;cdcr-architecture.adoc&lt;/tt&gt;: new page with the current &quot;CDCR Architecture&quot; and &quot;Major Components of CDCR&quot; sections&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;cdcr-config.adoc&lt;/tt&gt;: new page with current &quot;CDCR Configuration&quot;, &quot;Initial Startup&quot;, and &quot;ZooKeeper Settings&quot; sections&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;cdcr-operations.adoc&lt;/tt&gt;: new page with current &quot;Monitoring&quot; and &quot;Upgrading and Patching Production&quot; sections&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;cdcr-api.adoc&lt;/tt&gt;: new page with current &quot;CDCR API&quot; section&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=varun&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;varun&quot;&gt;varun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sarkaramrit2%40gmail.com&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sarkaramrit2@gmail.com&quot;&gt;sarkaramrit2@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=erickerickson&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;erickerickson&quot;&gt;erickerickson&lt;/a&gt; - any thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16262486" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Wed, 22 Nov 2017 13:01:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;+1. It is lot of scrolling up and down right now. Happy with the 4 seb-sections too.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16262778" author="ctargett" created="Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:18:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s a patch that has Amrit&apos;s edits + splitting the CDCR page into multiple child pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s a bit more to do (mostly links between pages), so it&apos;s not ready to commit - just thought I&apos;d share in case anyone wanted to take a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16269411" author="ctargett" created="Tue, 28 Nov 2017 20:28:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve attached an updated patch (&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11412&quot; title=&quot;Documentation changes for SOLR-11003: Bi-directional CDCR support&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11412&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11412&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.patch) that has the CDCR page split into 4 new pages (for a total of 5 CDCR-related pages) along the lines I outlined the other day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the liberty of updating the terminology a bit - there were frequent instances of &quot;uni-directional scenario&quot; and &quot;bi-directional scenario&quot;, which made the word &quot;scenario&quot; seem over- and improperly used. I changed many of these to &quot;updates&quot; (with other sentence context changes to make it work). If this is also misleading, please let me know so we can fix before I commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suspect the &quot;CDCR Glossary&quot; is, at this point, a bit redundant and out of place. I&apos;d like to remove it, but for now left a comment that we should consider doing so in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I think this is good to commit if others agree with the patch as it is.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16275082" author="ctargett" created="Fri, 1 Dec 2017 22:19:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=sarkaramrit2%40gmail.com&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;sarkaramrit2@gmail.com&quot;&gt;sarkaramrit2@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=varun&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;varun&quot;&gt;varun&lt;/a&gt; - Do either of you have any comments about the latest patch?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16275103" author="varunthacker" created="Fri, 1 Dec 2017 22:33:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Cassandra,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going through the patch right now&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16275194" author="varunthacker" created="Fri, 1 Dec 2017 23:40:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;cdcr-api.adoc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we can remove &quot;Enable Buffer Response&quot;, &quot;Disable Buffer Response&quot;, &quot;CDCR Start Response&quot;, &quot;CDCR Stop Response&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
The one line explaination doesn&apos;t add any value in my opinion. &lt;br/&gt;
For &quot;OPS Response&quot; maybe all we should say is : &quot;Provides the average number of operations as a sum and broken down by adds/deletes&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
For &quot;ERRORS Response&quot; we should say &quot;Provides the number of consecutive errors encountered by the replicator thread, the number of bad requests or internal errors since the start of the replication process, and a list of the last errors encountered ordered by timestamp.&quot;  The first part of the description seems unecessary to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also both OPS and ERROR&apos;s should really be exposed via the metrics API. I&apos;ll file a separate Jira for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CDCR Architecture Page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The data changes can be replicated in near real-time (with a small delay) or could be scheduled to be sent at longer intervals to the Target data center&quot; : &quot;The data changes can be replicated at a configurable amount of time&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should Source and Target should start with a capital letter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Since this is a full copy of the entire index, network bandwidth should be considered.&quot; : What value does this line add to the user? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;CDCR can &quot;bootstrap&quot; the collection to the Target data center. Since this is a full copy of the entire index, network bandwidth should be considered. Of course both Source and Target collections may be empty to start.&quot; - Remove this part?  &lt;br/&gt;
The fifth paragraph ( &quot;Replication supports both...&quot; ) basically explains this in a better fashion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;The directional nature of the implementation implies a &quot;push&quot; model from the Source collection to the Target collection. Therefore, the Source configuration must be able to &quot;see&quot; the ZooKeeper ensemble in the Target cluster. The ZooKeeper ensemble is provided configured in the Source&#8217;s solrconfig.xml file.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel we can remove this entire para and just add a line to the 3rd para where we mention it&apos;s pushed based. Here&apos;s a stab at an updated 3rd para&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Each shard leader in the Source data center is responsible for replicating its updates to the corresponding leader in the Target data center. This is a push model and the source data center must be able to connect to the target ZooKeeper. Shard leaders in the Target data center will replicate the changes to their own replicas as normal SolrCloud updates.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;CDCR can be configured to replicate from one collection to a second collection within the same cluster. That is a specialized scenario not covered in this Guide.&quot; : Does this point have any value? I&apos;m +0 in removing it &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &quot;Figure 1. Uni-Directional Data Flow&quot; :  &quot;Since leaders may ... Firewalls, ACL rules, etc., must be configured to allow this.&quot; I feel like we have the ACL part could be mentioned in the architecture overview and removed from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;With bi-directional updates, indexing and querying &quot; : I guess the only hard requirement is indexing. Querying doesn&apos;t have any impact in this design i.e it&apos;s the same as uni directional&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Updates sent from Source data center to Target is not propagated back to Source when bi-directional updates are configured&quot; : This is what point 7 talks about so maybe remove this&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;CDCR Configuration : &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &quot;&amp;lt;!-- optional --&amp;gt;&quot; : We recommend everyone to disable buffering. Let&apos;s remove this comment&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt; From the &quot;Initial Startup&quot; section &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &quot;Sync the index directories from the Source collection to Target collection across to the corresponding shard nodes. rsync works well for this&quot; till the end of the section : Seems like a lot of info or notes which are already known?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &quot;ZooKeeper Settings&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;800 is a typo? We say we want to set 200 but use &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Cross Data Center Replication Operations&quot; : Should talk about how to update a schema. I&apos;ll add some docs after this commit&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16275196" author="varunthacker" created="Fri, 1 Dec 2017 23:41:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In general I think we could do with some more cleaning of the docs. No user is going to read so much of info before setting up CDCR. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1 to commit this with or without the changes I suggested. If it&apos;s committed without my changes then I can create a patch with everything that I felt can be folded it to make reviewing easier ?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16277355" author="ctargett" created="Mon, 4 Dec 2017 19:40:09 +0000"  >&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;tt&gt;cdcr-api.adoc&lt;/tt&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;I made all the recommended changes you suggested here.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;CDCR Architecture Page:
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;The data changes can be replicated in near real-time (with a small delay) or could be scheduled to be sent at longer intervals to the Target data center&quot; : &quot;The data changes can be replicated at a configurable amount of time&quot; Should Source and Target should start with a capital letter?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was like that before so isn&apos;t really related to the new content. I would normally remove the capitalization, but Erick wrote/contributed the page, and it&apos;s not so egregious that I thought it had to be changed. I think an argument can be made that in &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; case, the capitalization works as shorthand for the two clusters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Since this is a full copy of the entire index, network bandwidth should be considered.&quot; : What value does this line add to the user?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That he/she should be aware that an entire index is going over the wire and they shouldn&apos;t expect it to be done in nanoseconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of your comments for this page are judgement calls, again mostly not-related to the patch. If you want to make the changes at a later time, go ahead, I can&apos;t figure out what does &amp;amp; doesn&apos;t add value at the same level that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;CDCR Configuration :
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;!-- optional --&amp;gt;&quot; : We recommend everyone to disable buffering. Let&apos;s remove this comment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Sync the index directories from the Source collection to Target collection across to the corresponding shard nodes. rsync works well for this&quot; till the end of the section : Seems like a lot of info or notes which are already known?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known by who? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;ZooKeeper Settings&quot; 800 is a typo? We say we want to set 200 but use&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was already there, I&apos;ll assume you know it should be set to 800 in the comment.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16277443" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 4 Dec 2017 20:29:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 52cefbe742095daf8a31b8bc34ade5c809226c7d in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ctargett&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ctargett&quot;&gt;ctargett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=52cefbe&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=52cefbe&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11412&quot; title=&quot;Documentation changes for SOLR-11003: Bi-directional CDCR support&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11412&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11412&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Add docs for bi-directional CDCR; split CDCR pages into multiple child pages&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16277444" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 4 Dec 2017 20:30:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 89b02c430a6a42d4687afce647b030580fc46af6 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_7x from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ctargett&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ctargett&quot;&gt;ctargett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=89b02c4&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=89b02c4&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11412&quot; title=&quot;Documentation changes for SOLR-11003: Bi-directional CDCR support&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11412&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11412&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Add docs for bi-directional CDCR; split CDCR pages into multiple child pages&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16278528" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Tue, 5 Dec 2017 13:24:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thank you &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ctargett&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ctargett&quot;&gt;ctargett&lt;/a&gt; for curating and commiting.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310010">
                    <name>Incorporates</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is part of">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13084511">SOLR-11003</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12898296" name="CDCR_bidir.png" size="70828" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Fri, 17 Nov 2017 22:44:08 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12898876" name="SOLR-11412-split.patch" size="162348" author="ctargett" created="Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:16:51 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12899678" name="SOLR-11412.patch" size="168539" author="ctargett" created="Tue, 28 Nov 2017 20:24:28 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12898295" name="SOLR-11412.patch" size="12878" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Fri, 17 Nov 2017 22:44:15 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12889628" name="SOLR-11412.patch" size="12760" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Fri, 29 Sep 2017 02:01:39 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12889469" name="SOLR-11412.patch" size="12096" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Thu, 28 Sep 2017 09:24:56 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12889410" name="SOLR-11412.patch" size="11599" author="sarkaramrit2@gmail.com" created="Thu, 28 Sep 2017 02:46:38 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>7.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            7 years, 50 weeks ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i3kn7j:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>