<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:30:16 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-11624] collection creation should not also overwrite/delete any configset but it can!</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Looks like a problem that crept in when we changed the _default configset stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;setup:&lt;br/&gt;
upload a configset named &quot;wiki&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
collections?action=CREATE&amp;amp;name=wiki&amp;amp;.....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My custom configset &quot;wiki&quot; gets overwritten by _default and then used by the &quot;wiki&quot; collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assigning to myself only because it really needs to be fixed IMO and I don&apos;t want to lose track of it. Anyone else please feel free to take it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13117159">SOLR-11624</key>
            <summary>collection creation should not also overwrite/delete any configset but it can!</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="ichattopadhyaya">Ishan Chattopadhyaya</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="erickerickson">Erick Erickson</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 9 Nov 2017 01:29:35 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 8 Jun 2019 15:15:03 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 23:59:48 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>7.2</version>
                                    <fixVersion>7.3</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>8.0</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>12</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16245121" author="erickerickson" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 02:18:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This is apparently explicitly intended behavior, see: CreateCollectionCmd.copyDefaultConfigSetTo that has the comment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;// if a configset named coll exists, delete the configset so that _default can be copied over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this patch changes this behavior, I&apos;ll test it in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this is very explicit behavior and not just an oversight, I&apos;d like to reach some consensus before committing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m a strong -1 for the current behavior for the record.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16245181" author="erickerickson" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 04:22:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m having some really wonky behavior with that patch, so it&apos;s probably wrong. To whit: I try to create a collection without collection.configName and the process hangs. I can&apos;t imagine why given how trivial the change is but that just shows a lack of imagination I think.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16245209" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 05:07:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This was indeed intended, and discussed here:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-10272?focusedCommentId=15985654&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:comment-tabpanel#comment-15985654&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-10272?focusedCommentId=15985654&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:comment-tabpanel#comment-15985654&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m a strong -1 for the current behavior for the record.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you suggest we revert this behavior? I can work on such a patch, if there&apos;s consensus.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16245627" author="dsmiley" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 13:23:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I overlooked that detail &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; did in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-10272&quot; title=&quot;Use a default configset and make the configName parameter optional.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-10272&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-10272&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  +1 to your proposal here Erick (thus revert to the old behavior).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16245749" author="erickerickson" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 14:42:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Ishan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, reverting overwriting the named configuration set would be my preference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW, the wonkiness I was getting with my patch was due to it being late and having a massive elevate.xml left over from chasing a totally unrelated issue so it might be viable after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to grab this JIRA if you want, I only assigned it to myself to make sure I didn&apos;t lose track of it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16245844" author="elyograg" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 15:33:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I agree with Erick.  If a configset already exists, Solr should &lt;b&gt;not&lt;/b&gt; be changing it just because a collection creation with the same name was requested.  What if there were a hundred existing collections all using that configset?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an option on the create command to force a config overwrite wouldn&apos;t be a bad idea, but that shouldn&apos;t be the default behavior.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16246454" author="erickerickson" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 20:23:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;bq: Having an option on the create command to force a config overwrite...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d prefer that remain &apos;bin/solr zk upconfig.....&apos;, but that&apos;s not a strong preference.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16248351" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Sat, 11 Nov 2017 06:07:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s the reason behind putting in that change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of that whole exercise (default configset) was to not need the user to be aware of the concept of configsets. In that situation, here&apos;s a typical situation that a user (who isn&apos;t aware of the concept of configsets) would be faced with, if the current behavior were not to be there: a) user creates a collection without specifying a configset, b) makes some changes to schema/configs using APIs, c) he&apos;s unhappy with how things turned out and deleted that collection and re-created it, d) instead of starting from scratch (default configset), as he was hoping, he is at the same place where he left off before deleting the collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overwriting any existing configset results in a climate of least surprises for a new user. However, those who understand concepts of configsets can always specify a configset name while creating his collections. IMHO, we should keep the current behavior. But, as I mentioned before, if there&apos;s consensus on switching back to previous behavior, I can work on bringing it back.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16248591" author="erickerickson" created="Sat, 11 Nov 2017 16:53:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hmm, problem is we can&apos;t satisfy both a new user in the scenario you outline &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; someone taking control of their configsets. The situation we&apos;re in now is &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt; user tunes their configuration set like we want them to. We even tell them that _default isn&apos;t recommended for production!&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; user creates a collection without specifying configName&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; user loses their changes &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; gets schemaless to boot. Yes, they can start with the &quot;don&apos;t add new fields&quot; parameter....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I imagine it from the perspective of a brand-new user, then this becomes one of those little &quot;learning experiences&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I imagine this from the perspective of a veteran user then the behavior is a real head-scratcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And _much_worse IMO. &lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; user &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt;  understand configsets&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; user creates collection1 and gets configset collection1 copied from _default and makes modifications.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; user creates 10 more collections all using collection1 configset&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; user drops and recreates collection1. Now all 10 collections are back to _default&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So really we&apos;ve made it very easy for veteran users to mess up in order to make it easy for a new user to start from a known state when dropping and recreating a collection. It can take considerable time and effort to get your configs the way you want them, and all that work is potentially lost. Additionally it&apos;s very common to recommend that users drop and recreate collections to re-index from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two I&apos;d rather add the need to delete the configset when a user wants to start over to the learning curve rather than mess up veteran&apos;s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&apos;m +1 for reverting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think about this: We already have a warning when using the _default schema about how schemaless isn&apos;t recommended for production. To cover the situation Ishan outlined, we return a message like &quot;Using existing configuration set XXX&quot; if a configset already exists? And do this even if they specify configName.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually I kind of like that idea anyway as an additional confirmation that the user did what they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And another suggestion re: the message returned. The current message will still come back if a configset with the same name as the collection does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; exist. Rather than say &quot;Using _default configset...&quot; how about something telling them that the configset has been copied? the current wording is easy to interpret as the collection is actually using _default rather than a copy of it.  &quot;Copied the _default configset to &amp;lt;collection_name&amp;gt; which will be used by this collection...&quot; or something.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16249450" author="noble.paul" created="Mon, 13 Nov 2017 12:01:47 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Had a discussion with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt;. We really need to nail down the behavior for the default configsets. These were the take aways. Please comment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If Solr creates a configset implicitly, Solr must delete it implicitly when the collection is deleted (if it&apos;s not referenced by another collection, of course)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The current naming of the configset can lead to conflict can lead to the current, unpleasant behavior. The implicit configset created for a collection called &lt;tt&gt;mycollection&lt;/tt&gt; should be something like &lt;tt&gt;SOLR_CONFSET.mycollection&lt;/tt&gt; (other name suggestions are welcome).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16249798" author="erickerickson" created="Mon, 13 Nov 2017 16:37:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m -1 on both of these. Just because Solr created the configset does not mean Solr controls its entire lifecycle, we even provide tools for changing the configset! The naming is irrelevant. I&apos;m assuming the SOLR_CONFSET bit indicates that Solr created it. That does not mean it hasn&apos;t been modified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not address the root problem: the current behavior &lt;em&gt;overwrites&lt;/em&gt; an existing configset that I may have modified. I don&apos;t care how it was created, this is the root problem that I&apos;m -Integer.MAX_VALUE on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenario&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; I create collection EOE, SOLR_CONFIGSET.EOE is created by Solr&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; I customize the configset.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; I create 3 more collections pointing to it.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; I drop and recreate collection EOE.&lt;br/&gt;
&amp;gt; my other three collections now use the default configset with who knows what consequences?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s reasonable for users to drop and recreate a collection. It is also quite common for users to have multiple collections point to the same config set. Deleting (or overwriting) a configset &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; them when they didn&apos;t direct Solr to is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really don&apos;t see what the value is in making this so complex, the fix is simple. Just stop overwriting the configset if it already exists. Let the user delete configsets she doesn&apos;t want any more, it&apos;s easy with the configsets api.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The principle of least surprise comes in to play here. Once a configset exists in ZooKeeper, don&apos;t change it unless I tell you to. End of story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d be OK if the guarantee is that the configset hasn&apos;t been changed since Solr created it, in that case Solr can go ahead delete it with my blessing since it&apos;ll be recreated just as it was if I recreate the collection. I.e. there is no surprise in store for me. But otherwise -1 to both deleting it and overwriting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems llike the tail wagging the dog. We have a situation where we want to make it easy for the beginning user to get up and running. Solr does that by copying the _default configset. This is good, it removes a barrier to entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then users can spend quite a bit of time and effort modifying the configset to satisfy their needs. We should not risk them losing those changes just to tidy things up, which is all deleting configsets would really do. We should not risk them losing those changes by overwriting an existing configset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than having clean configs Znode, nobody has provided any compelling reason that Solr controlling the lifecycle of a configset is valuable. There are substantial risks do doing anything more than creating it if it doesn&apos;t exist that we should avoid.&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16249850" author="ctargett" created="Mon, 13 Nov 2017 17:24:24 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principle of least surprise comes in to play here. Once a configset exists in ZooKeeper, don&apos;t change it unless I tell you to. End of story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m +1 on this idea. I too don&apos;t understand the confusion and complication around just not overwriting an existing configset when one already exists that matches the name of the collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea of that whole exercise (default configset) was to not need the user to be aware of the concept of configsets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind, the goal was not to remove the need for new users to ever learn of the concept of configsets. It was to reduce the barrier of having to learn &lt;b&gt;everything&lt;/b&gt; about configsets before you can even remotely start with Solr. (Actually, to be more precise, it was to fix the scenario where a new user fires up the Admin UI and clicks a button to create a collection that 100% of the time fails with a cryptic-to-them error message.) What we&apos;ve done here is make something that should be a convenience into a poor experience for anyone who knows what they are doing. We must find the balance between these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way this currently works has not, in fact, simplified the whole story at all, just changed where surprising and annoying behavior occurs. Further, I don&apos;t find where this behavior is described in the Ref Guide, so there isn&apos;t even any explanation for users to understand what new implicit rules they&apos;re expected to know before trying to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16250666" author="noble.paul" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 02:03:29 +0000"  >
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;
&amp;gt; I create collection EOE, SOLR_CONFIGSET.EOE is created by Solr
&amp;gt; I customize the configset.
&amp;gt; I create 3 more collections pointing to it.
&amp;gt; I drop and recreate collection EOE.
&amp;gt; my other three collections now use the &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt; configset with who knows what consequences?
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case &lt;tt&gt;SOLR_CONFIGSET.EOE&lt;/tt&gt; is referenced by another live collection. So, it does not get deleted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This does not address the root problem: the current behavior overwrites an existing configset that I may have modified. I don&apos;t care how it was created, this is the root problem that I&apos;m -Integer.MAX_VALUE on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think we are talking against each other. We don&apos;t need to delete an existing confgset. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principle of least surprise comes in to play here. Once a configset exists in ZooKeeper, don&apos;t change it unless I tell you to. End of story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the use case of a casual user creating and deleting collections. very soon, we will end up a lot of unused configsets in zookeeper. The user did not create the configset, so he is not aware of its existence. Imagine he screwed up the configset while he was using the collection and he wanted to start with a clean slate. In order to do so, he would delete a collection and recreate another (most likely with the same name). He will see the screwed up behavior again because the old configset gets reused. So, my proposal was&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use a special name for auto-created configsets (such as &lt;tt&gt;SOLR_CONFIGSET.&amp;lt;collection-name&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;)  This eliminates the problem of us screwing up our current user base who creates configsets with the same name as the collection&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;As you said, DO NOT delete/overwrite a configset at the time of collection creation&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;When deleting a collection, that has an auto created configset, drop it. Because, the user did not ask us to create the configset and most likely he is unaware of it. If that configset is referenced by another collection, do not delete it.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;We can also provide a flag in DELETE-COLLECTION to omit dropping of configset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16250884" author="erickerickson" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 05:21:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I think I see how you&apos;re thinking about this. I think it&apos;s too much effort, unnecessarily complex and there&apos;s too many ways it can fail. Not to mention startling to veteran users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Failure case&lt;/b&gt;: User creates a collection and we copy &lt;tt&gt;_default&lt;/tt&gt; with our prefix. User uses the config API or schema API to modify. User drops collection. The user&apos;s work disappears. Hair tearing ensues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Failure case&lt;/b&gt;: User creates a collection and  we copy &lt;tt&gt;_default&lt;/tt&gt;. User is learning about configsets and uploads customized configs manually to the same place &apos;cause &quot;Hey! that&apos;s where my configset is!&quot;. User deletes collection and work disappears. Remaining hair is torn out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Failure case&lt;/b&gt;: User manually creates a configset prefixed by &lt;tt&gt;SOLR_CONFIGSET&lt;/tt&gt; &apos;cause &quot;Hey, that&apos;s the convention apparently&quot; then drops the associated collection. We remove the configset, again losing his work. User is now bald and head explodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Failure case N+1&lt;/b&gt;: I&apos;m sure we&apos;ll find more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, each failure case can be fixed with enough coding, but why bother just to keep configsets from proliferating? As I see it, the only thing this mechanism is really helping with is: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{Take the use case of a casual user creating and deleting collections. very soon, we will end up a lot of unused configsets in zookeeper. }}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, if the user is dropping and recreating the same collection there&apos;s no problem, they&apos;ll just continue to use the same configset that was copied the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, after that bit of hand-holding users will soon have to be aware of configsets. Especially since every time they create a collection with the &lt;tt&gt;_default&lt;/tt&gt; configset (or a copy) there&apos;s a warning in the response &lt;b&gt;telling the user that this isn&apos;t a good idea&lt;/b&gt; (that should stay  BTW)! I don&apos;t think it&apos;s too much to ask for them to use the configsets API to delete old configsets if they create/drop a bunch of different collections and we copy &lt;tt&gt;_defalut&lt;/tt&gt; around. Until then having configsets proliferate isn&apos;t a big deal IMO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t think your argument below is germane. Maybe I&apos;m stringing two sentences together that weren&apos;t intended...&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;The user did not create the configset, so he is not aware of its existence. Imagine he screwed up the configset while he was using the collection and he wanted to start with a clean slate.&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did the user screw up a configset if she was unaware of it in the first place? I guess you can argue that she messed it up by using the config API or the managed schema API. IMO it&apos;s totally reasonable to expect anyone at that level to use the configs API to delete the configset if they need to start over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I claim a user will have to eventually be aware of configsets and the added burden of using the configs API to delete unwanted ones after they figure configsets out is preferable to adding to the complexity and potential errors by trying to fix the one use case I see this addressing. If we go this route it won&apos;t need any new flags for the collections DELETE command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What other use-cases do you see that need supporting besides proliferating configsets?&lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="16250959" author="noble.paul" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 06:27:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;chatted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=erickerickson&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;erickerickson&quot;&gt;erickerickson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
following are the takeaways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do not delete/overwrite a configset when a collection is created&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use a special prefix for auto created configsets&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;When the collection which uses an autocreated configset is deleted, give a WARNING message that the configset is not deleted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16251575" author="erickerickson" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 15:43:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Noble:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for &amp;lt;3&amp;gt; can we include just a statement in the return to the request that the configset is still there, similar to what we do when we create a collection using the _default configset? Perhaps even give the configset API command to delete it or direct the user to the ref guide for the configset API?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in either case this would be when the configset was &quot;dangling&quot;, i.e. no collections use it any more, right?&lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="16251589" author="dsmiley" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 15:50:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;If the request to create a collection does not specify collection.configName, and if we see a config already exists with the name we want to use (e.g. &lt;tt&gt;SOLR_CONFIGSET.myColName&lt;/tt&gt;), then it might be helpful to log an informative message that we are using an existing config and what its name is.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16251619" author="steve_rowe" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 16:09:51 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;User manually creates a configset prefixed by &lt;tt&gt;SOLR_CONFIGSET&lt;/tt&gt; &apos;cause &quot;Hey, that&apos;s the convention apparently&quot; then drops the associated collection&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably better to use something like &lt;tt&gt;collection.AUTOMATIC_COPY_OF_DEFAULT_CONFIGSET&lt;/tt&gt; (suffix probably better than prefix imho), or less wordily-ish: &lt;tt&gt;collection.AUTO_DEFAULT_COPY&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16251785" author="noble.paul" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 17:29:50 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;suffix probably better than prefix imho&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;agreed . suffix is better. &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;collection&amp;gt;.AUTOCREATED_CONFIGSET&lt;/tt&gt; ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the request to create a collection does not specify collection.configName, and if we see a config already exists with the name we want to use (e.g. SOLR_CONFIGSET.myColName), then it might be helpful to log an informative message that we are using an existing config and what its name is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;And in either case this would be when the configset was &quot;dangling&quot;, i.e. no collections use it any more, right?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;right.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16251905" author="erickerickson" created="Tue, 14 Nov 2017 18:30:31 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;OK, so it looks like consensus has been reached as far as I&apos;m concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably won&apos;t be able to work on it for a while, anyone who wants should reassign it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16278796" author="erickerickson" created="Tue, 5 Dec 2017 16:07:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=noble.paul&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;noble.paul&quot;&gt;noble.paul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=steve_rowe&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;steve_rowe&quot;&gt;steve_rowe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adrien mentioned this JIRA as something he might include in the 7.2 release. Is this worth trying to push into 7.2 or would it be better to bake it for 7.3? I won&apos;t be able to devote significant time to it this week, too late for 7.2.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16279038" author="dsmiley" created="Tue, 5 Dec 2017 18:55:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The most immediate change we could do now is prevent overwriting the configset, i.e. throw an error.  I&apos;m already shepherding various issues so I don&apos;t have time to do this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16279754" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 06:54:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I was a bit under the weather and couldn&apos;t get to this sooner. &lt;del&gt;I&apos;ll try to put in this immediate measure, i.e. throw an error on overwrite.&lt;/del&gt; &lt;br/&gt;
EDIT: Error on overwrite seems a bit tricky: the collection creation would fail on this error which is an unfriendly behaviour and I&apos;m not sure if this is what we should do as a temporary/stopgap behaviour. I&apos;m thinking through this a bit more, will update as soon as possible. I&apos;ll try not to hold up the release for this.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16280121" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 12:40:36 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Here&apos;s what we agreed to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Do not delete/overwrite a configset when a collection is created&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Use a special prefix for auto created configsets&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;When the collection which uses an autocreated configset is deleted, give a WARNING message that the configset is not deleted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried a patch with first two items (attached); problem is that there are failures in some tests that would need some digging into (i.e. TimeRoutedAliasUpdateProcessor#test()). I can do only step 1, for now (7.2 release) and fix all other cases later; however, it would mean a break in user facing behaviour twice. I&apos;m going to skip doing so (and do nothing for 7.2), unless someone wants me to do otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16280183" author="dsmiley" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 13:39:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;BTW RE TimeRoutedAliasUpdateProcessorTest, as it&apos;s comments indicate, it creates a collection for the sole purpose of creating a named configset that it can then modify.  So it deletes it when done and intends for the config to still exist so that it can be referenced when other collections are created.  If we are to auto-delete configsets when collections get destroyed (sometimes, e.g. when config name matches the auto-created name), we then need an option to prevent this from happening if the user desires.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16280206" author="dsmiley" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 13:54:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Come to think of it, given that we now have a &quot;_default&quot; config set that already exists, I guess I could use the configset API to copy it first.  Assuming I choose a name that won&apos;t be the auto-created name, it shouldn&apos;t get auto-deleted when the collection is deleted.  Yeah, that works.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16280288" author="elyograg" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 15:09:29 +0000"  >&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use a special prefix for auto created configsets&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not going to tell you what to do here, but I think that the overall consensus was that a suffix was better than a prefix.  The choices I saw that looked good were .AUTO_DEFAULT_COPY and .AUTOCREATED_CONFIGSET.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16280346" author="erickerickson" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 15:49:08 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; This behavior has been around since 7.0, right? I see no compelling reason to rush this in to 7.2, I&apos;d rather have it change once rather than twice, not to mention that the possibility of having something get overlooked in the rush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So unless we&apos;re very confident, I&apos;m fine with pushing it off to 7.3.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16286385" author="asingh2411" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2017 18:30:50 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Please find the updated patch here -&amp;gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nobr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12901538/12901538_SOLR-11624.3.patch&quot; title=&quot;SOLR-11624.3.patch attached to SOLR-11624&quot;&gt;SOLR-11624.3.patch&lt;sup&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rendericon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/link_attachment_7.gif&quot; height=&quot;7&quot; width=&quot;7&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changes made:-&lt;br/&gt;
1. Modified the test case &lt;tt&gt;TimeRoutedAliasUpdateProcessorTest#test&lt;/tt&gt; to create/update and use the correct &lt;tt&gt;modifiedConfigSet&lt;/tt&gt; name.&lt;br/&gt;
2. Refactored the &lt;tt&gt;configName&lt;/tt&gt; , added suffix to the name of &lt;em&gt;auto-generated configSet&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dsmiley&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dsmiley&quot;&gt;dsmiley&lt;/a&gt; Please review the patch.  &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16288240" author="asingh2411" created="Tue, 12 Dec 2017 20:41:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Updated the patch with documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dsmiley&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dsmiley&quot;&gt;dsmiley&lt;/a&gt; Kindly review the same. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16306533" author="dsmiley" created="Fri, 29 Dec 2017 20:49:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Abhishek, when adding updated attachments to JIRA, use the same name and JIRA will keep track of it (clearly showing which is the latest yet allowing access to earlier ones if desired). Do not keep incrementing a counter at the suffix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FWIW I don&apos;t think the auto created suffix name needs &quot;CONFIGSET&quot; as a part of it&apos;s name, as that is the namespace in which it exists &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;  (and it&apos;s verbose).  I think a suffix of &quot;.AUTOCREATED&quot; is fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I briefly looked at two aspects of your patch; it wasn&apos;t thorough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RE TimeRoutedAliasUpdateProcessorTest: it seems that your changes resulted in the creation of an auto-generated configset, but I definitely do not want autogenerated configsets in the test.  I believe this is easily avoided by having the collection creation explicitly refer to the desired configset when it&apos;s created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the updated docs you added to the collection.configName parameter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defines the name of the configurations (which &lt;b&gt;must already be stored in ZooKeeper&lt;/b&gt;) to use for this collection. If not provided, Solr will use the configurations of `_default` configSet &lt;b&gt;OR&lt;/b&gt; `the only configSet present` (if there is only 1 config set in Zookeeper) to create the collection. The new configSet created for the collection will be  named `&amp;lt;collectionName&amp;gt;.AUTOCREATED_CONFIGSET`&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it needs to be clear that Solr will create a new (mutable) configSet that is a copy of _default, and that this new configSet will be deleted when the collection is.  The &amp;#42;OR&amp;#42; part has my attention.  I assume this rule is for legacy?  Any way, so if we have one configSet in ZooKeeper named &quot;myconfig&quot; and the user creates a collection &quot;mycoll&quot; (without specifying which config), then presumably we&apos;ll have two configSets: &quot;myconfig&quot; and &quot;mycoll.AUTOCREATED_CONFIGSET&quot;.  And this point there is no longer one configSet in ZooKeeper, nor is there &quot;_default&quot; for that matter.  Does this mean if the user goes to create another collection similarly that it will fail?  Presumably you didn&apos;t introduce this behavior but you are documenting it?  Can someone vouch for the usefulness of this behavior; I find it problematic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nippick: &quot;configurations&quot; should be in singular form in both places. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16306661" author="githubbot" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2017 05:18:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;GitHub user abhidemon opened a pull request:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/297&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    fix: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You can merge this pull request into a Git repository by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    $ git pull &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/abhidemon/lucene-solr&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/abhidemon/lucene-solr&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&quot; title=&quot;collection creation should not also overwrite/delete any configset but it can!&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11624&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11624&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively you can review and apply these changes as the patch at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/297.patch&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/297.patch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To close this pull request, make a commit to your master/trunk branch&lt;br/&gt;
with (at least) the following in the commit message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    This closes #297&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;commit 01eac2e19d0badf095816fa8f8a546653c0e4556&lt;br/&gt;
Author: abhidemon &amp;lt;abhishek.singh@...&amp;gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Date:   2017-12-12T20:44:56Z&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    fix: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16306785" author="abhidemon" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2017 14:28:24 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dsmiley&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dsmiley&quot;&gt;dsmiley&lt;/a&gt; , Thanks for the suggestions.&lt;br/&gt;
Uploading the updated patch with following changes:-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Changed the suffix name to   &quot;.AUTOCREATED&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Explicitly setting the name of the created ConfigSet in TimeRoutedAliasUpdateProcessorTest&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Modified the documentation to read..
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#654982&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;collection.configName&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt; : Defines the name of the configuration (which &lt;b&gt;must already be stored in ZooKeeper&lt;/b&gt;) to use for this collection. If not provided, Solr will use the configuration of &lt;tt&gt;_default&lt;/tt&gt; configSet &lt;b&gt;OR&lt;/b&gt; the &lt;tt&gt;only configSet present&lt;/tt&gt; (if there is only 1 config set in Zookeeper) to create a new (and mutable) configSet named &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;collectionName&amp;gt;.AUTOCREATED&lt;/tt&gt; and will use it for the new collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="16306797" author="abhidemon" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2017 14:37:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Also, Thanks for pointing this consistency out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;so if we have one configSet in ZooKeeper named &quot;myconfig&quot; and the user creates a collection &quot;mycoll&quot; (without specifying which config), then presumably we&apos;ll have two configSets: &quot;myconfig&quot; and &quot;mycoll.AUTOCREATED_CONFIGSET&quot;. And this point there is no longer one configSet in ZooKeeper, nor is there &quot;_default&quot; for that matter. Does this mean if the user goes to create another collection similarly that it will fail?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think yes, it will fail.&lt;br/&gt;
Looks like with the new ConfigName being added, this feature in particular will break. &lt;br/&gt;
We can get rid of this proble by &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Either depricating this feature of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/blob/master/solr/core/src/java/org/apache/solr/cloud/CreateCollectionCmd.java#L362&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;using the only configset present&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Or making a new configSet named &lt;tt&gt;_default&lt;/tt&gt; , whenever such a case arises.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dsmiley&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dsmiley&quot;&gt;dsmiley&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="16315645" author="erickerickson" created="Mon, 8 Jan 2018 04:06:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; Meant this JIRA, what&apos;s the status here?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16321260" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Wed, 10 Jan 2018 22:34:48 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=erickerickson&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;erickerickson&quot;&gt;erickerickson&lt;/a&gt;, I&apos;ll review the test and the documentation change and try to wrap this up this week.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16325318" author="githubbot" created="Sat, 13 Jan 2018 20:17:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Github user abhidemon closed the pull request at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/297&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/297&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16325341" author="abhidemon" created="Sat, 13 Jan 2018 21:34:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Uploading the updated patch with corrected documentation. &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ichattopadhyaya&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ichattopadhyaya&quot;&gt;ichattopadhyaya&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=dsmiley&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;dsmiley&quot;&gt;dsmiley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16334125" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2018 10:42:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Updated the patch for master. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16334302" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2018 14:18:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 183835ed2485915006746e456d7124cb5d5d4abb in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ishan1604&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ishan1604&quot;&gt;ishan1604&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=183835e&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=183835e&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&quot; title=&quot;collection creation should not also overwrite/delete any configset but it can!&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11624&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11624&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Autocreated configsets will not use .AUTOCREATED suffix&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16334308" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2018 14:21:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 6ef838663bd0a006109e427ae2995192f38f2453 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_7x from &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ishan1604&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ishan1604&quot;&gt;ishan1604&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=6ef8386&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://git-wip-us.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=6ef8386&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-11624&quot; title=&quot;collection creation should not also overwrite/delete any configset but it can!&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-11624&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-11624&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Autocreated configsets will not use .AUTOCREATED suffix&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16334378" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2018 15:09:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=abhidemon&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;abhidemon&quot;&gt;abhidemon&lt;/a&gt; for the patch (test+documentation) and thanks to Erick, David &amp;amp; Shawn for reviewing the approaches / patches.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12900857" name="SOLR-11624-2.patch" size="3134" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Wed, 6 Dec 2017 12:39:43 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12901538" name="SOLR-11624.3.patch" size="9833" author="asingh2411" created="Mon, 11 Dec 2017 18:33:24 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12901760" name="SOLR-11624.4.patch" size="11147" author="asingh2411" created="Tue, 12 Dec 2017 20:39:50 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12907081" name="SOLR-11624.patch" size="9866" author="ichattopadhyaya" created="Mon, 22 Jan 2018 10:40:53 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12906004" name="SOLR-11624.patch" size="10181" author="abhidemon" created="Sat, 13 Jan 2018 21:33:59 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12904067" name="SOLR-11624.patch" size="10390" author="abhidemon" created="Sat, 30 Dec 2017 14:27:38 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12896792" name="SOLR-11624.patch" size="1086" author="erickerickson" created="Thu, 9 Nov 2017 02:16:00 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>7.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            7 years, 43 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i3mkof:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>