<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:36:21 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-13116] Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-13116</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Spinoff from&#160;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-7896&quot; title=&quot;Add a login page for Solr Administrative Interface&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-7896&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-7896&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Kerberos auth plugin should get&#160;Admin UI Login support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13207564">SOLR-13116</key>
            <summary>Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="janhoy">Jan H&#248;ydahl</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="janhoy">Jan H&#248;ydahl</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 3 Jan 2019 22:57:39 +0000</created>
                <updated>Sat, 8 Jun 2019 15:03:14 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:30:38 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>7.7</version>
                    <version>8.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>7.7</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>8.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Admin UI</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>5</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16734215" author="ctargett" created="Fri, 4 Jan 2019 14:51:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;The description for this issue isn&apos;t exactly incorrect, but it possibly understates the need here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using Kerberos one does not &quot;login&quot; anywhere. One either has a valid ticket or one doesn&apos;t and access to the Admin UI is granted based on the validity of the ticket without any user input. The need is that the login page not be presented when a user has a valid ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the current login page implementation, it seems that a Kerberos-secured Solr will present a user with an error instead of properly granting access according to whatever authz rules have been put in place.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16734286" author="janhoy" created="Fri, 4 Jan 2019 16:03:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I have not used Kerberos with Solr. How does this work today? Is it so that whenever user is logged in, the users Web Browser will present the ticket to Admin UI and thus avoid HTTP 401? If so, then we can close this right away, since the Login screen of the Admin UI will never be triggered. That is, unless some feature in the Admin UI requires more permission than the current user&apos;s Kerberos ticket allows, then I guess there might be some situation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can someone with a Kerberized Solr please test and report?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16735833" author="gerlowskija" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 13:52:27 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hey Jan,  I just tested your login screen with Kerberos (this includes the changes you made an hour or so ago, to clarify)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the behavior I&apos;m seeing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. With a Kerberos ticket in my local ticket cache, I can get to the admin UI and perform operations without ever seeing a login screen.  The admin UI is definitely usable.&lt;br/&gt;
2. If I destroy my Kerberos ticket or it expires, subsequent navigation or operations will produce a username/password login page.&lt;br/&gt;
3. If my machine acquires a valid ticket, I can then click on the &apos;Dashboard&apos; menu item to get away from the login page and back to the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in summary, the Admin UI is definitely usable when Kerberos auth is being used.  But that said the login/auth page still seems a little BasicAuth-specific, and inappropriate for other auth schemes.  Some specific issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. We probably shouldn&apos;t be displaying &lt;tt&gt;username&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;password&lt;/tt&gt; dialog boxes unless we&apos;re sure the user is using a auth scheme where those values make sense (they don&apos;t in Kerberos, for example).&lt;br/&gt;
2. Some other terms on the page also seem a little too Basic Auth specific to be useful for other auth schemes.  &quot;Login/Logout&quot; might be examples of this - those terms are rarely used when discussing Kerberos authentication.  Not entirely sure on this though.&lt;br/&gt;
3. It looks like when Kerberos is used, several templated values needed for the auth page are missing, causing UI errors.  Not familiar with how the UI works, so I may be off on the cause here.  I&apos;ve attached a screenshot below of the UI errors for the auth page on &lt;tt&gt;master&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
 &lt;span class=&quot;image-wrap&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12954006/12954006_eventual_auth.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px solid black&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for Kerberos/Solr testing, I recently came across a writeup/helper-repo that Ishan put together a year or two ago.  If you&apos;ve got docker installed, it makes setting up and testing Kerberos refreshingly straightforward.  Give it a shot if you get a chance: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chatman/solr-kerberos-docker&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/chatman/solr-kerberos-docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16735840" author="janhoy" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 13:57:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Your screenshot indicates that AngularJS is not able to fill the template. Do you see any errors in solr log or in browser console? When should happen is that you should only see the bottom part &quot;Authentication scheme not supported&quot; along with the actual response from your Kerberos plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will try the docker thingy..&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16735847" author="janhoy" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 14:00:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;So what we could do for this Jira is to provide an explicit text for &lt;tt&gt;login.html&lt;/tt&gt; for Kerberos that says something like &quot;Solr could not discover a valid Kerberos ticket&#160;from your browser. The response from the server is &amp;lt;....&amp;gt; Please re-login and re-try. Consult the Reference Guide chapter on Kerberos for more information&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16735903" author="gerlowskija" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 14:46:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Ok, that makes sense.  The page would be much more appropriate if only the bottom section appeared, as you indicate is &quot;expected&apos;.  I&apos;ll retry this afternoon when I get a few spare minutes and see if there&apos;s any particularly helpful errors in the browser console.  I didn&apos;t see anything interesting in solr.log previously, fwiw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, improving the message for Kerberos to be close to what you suggested would be a big improvement IMO.  I&apos;d suggest a slight rewording...there&apos;s two main things that can go wrong with Kerberos in the browser, and it&apos;d be helpful to mention both of them a bit more explicitly.  I&apos;d suggest something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Your browser did not provide the required information to authenticate using Kerberos.  Please check that your computer has a valid ticket for communicating with Solr, and that your browser is properly configured to provide that ticket when required.  For more information consult Solr&apos;s Kerberos documentation&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;link&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;.  The response from the server was: &amp;lt;..&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16735928" author="janhoy" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 15:06:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Excellent!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fired up the docker image on my MacBook and managed to get the solr1 container authenticating with the kdc container. But I did not manage to use kinit locally on my mac, it just hangs and cannot contact the kdc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you find some error msgs that could point us to a bug in the AdminUI code, and then we could add your wording, all before 7.7 or 8.0 is released, which would be a benefit!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16735937" author="risdenk" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 15:11:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I haven&apos;t played with this too much lately but &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/risdenk/knox_solr_testing/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/risdenk/knox_solr_testing/&lt;/a&gt; has Solr with KDC support. It was for testing Knox but should work standalone. I don&apos;t remember if KDC ports are exposed for kiniting locally though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another good blog for testing with Kerberos is here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bryanbende.com/development/2016/08/31/apache-nifi-1.0.0-kerberos-authentication&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://bryanbende.com/development/2016/08/31/apache-nifi-1.0.0-kerberos-authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16737238" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 8 Jan 2019 15:35:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the pointers Kevin; will check them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=janhoy&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;janhoy&quot;&gt;janhoy&lt;/a&gt;  I reproduced again this morning and saw the following error in my browser&apos;s web console.  I&apos;m not familiar enough with how the login page is implemented to tell if it&apos;s helpful.  But hopefully you find it enlightening:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;
Error: wwwHeader is &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;
@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/js/angular/controllers/login.js:31:11
&lt;/span&gt;invoke@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:4205:14
&lt;/span&gt;instantiate@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:4213:27
&lt;/span&gt;$ControllerProvider/&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;.$get&amp;lt;/&amp;lt;@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:8472:18
&lt;/span&gt;link@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular-route.min.js:30:268
&lt;/span&gt;invokeLinkFn@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:8236:9
&lt;/span&gt;nodeLinkFn@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:7745:11
&lt;/span&gt;compositeLinkFn@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:7098:13
&lt;/span&gt;publicLinkFn@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:6977:30
&lt;/span&gt;boundTranscludeFn@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:7116:16
&lt;/span&gt;controllersBoundTransclude@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:7772:18
&lt;/span&gt;x@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular-route.min.js:29:364
&lt;/span&gt;$broadcast@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:14725:15
&lt;/span&gt;m/&amp;lt;@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular-route.min.js:34:426
&lt;/span&gt;processQueue@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:13193:27
&lt;/span&gt;scheduleProcessQueue/&amp;lt;@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:13209:27
&lt;/span&gt;$eval@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:14406:16
&lt;/span&gt;$digest@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:14222:15
&lt;/span&gt;$apply@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:14511:13
&lt;/span&gt;done@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:9669:36
&lt;/span&gt;completeRequest@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:9859:7
&lt;/span&gt;requestLoaded@http:&lt;span class=&quot;code-comment&quot;&gt;//solr1:8983/solr/libs/angular.js:9800:9
&lt;/span&gt; &amp;lt;div ng-view=&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot; id=&quot;&lt;/span&gt;content&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot; class=&quot;&lt;/span&gt;ng-scope&quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&apos;s nothing that appears relevant in &lt;tt&gt;solr.log&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for why your kinit command just hung, I&apos;ve got a guess.  Docker on Linux allows the host machine to reach docker containers by IP address.  But docker on Mac &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/docker-for-mac/networking/#per-container-ip-addressing-is-not-possible&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;doesnt&lt;/a&gt;.  Since running &lt;tt&gt;kinit&lt;/tt&gt; on the host machine (your macbook) has it try to talk to the Kerberos KDC server by IP address, &lt;tt&gt;kinit&lt;/tt&gt; just hangs because it can&apos;t route to the docker container hosting the KDC.  That&apos;s my theory at least.  If you give it a shot on a Linux box, I bet it&apos;ll work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, hopefully you can reproduce it on your own.  But if you still can&apos;t reproduce, or want a double check that a fix works, happy to run the reproduction again.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16737558" author="janhoy" created="Tue, 8 Jan 2019 21:50:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;From the stack trace it is evident that the response from Kerberos auth plugin does contain a &lt;tt&gt;WWW-Authenticate&lt;/tt&gt;&#160;but when trying to split this in a schema and parameters with regex &lt;tt&gt;/(\w+)\s+(.*)/&lt;/tt&gt; then there is not match, so probably the header&#160;has some other format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you perhaps check the WWW-Authenticate header in the browser&apos;s debug panel under the Network tab? Then we can either change the parsing of the pattern or we can change the header sent by Kerberos plugin to carry information about the scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to&#160;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4559#section-4)&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4559#section-4&lt;/a&gt;&#160;the plain&#160;string &quot;Negotiate&quot; is returned in the first phase of Kerberos, so the regex fails.&#160;Working on a better&#160;parsing code.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16737679" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 9 Jan 2019 00:20:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Uploaded an (untested) patch that aims to solve the UI bug and add the login text agreed upon. To test it, it should be enough to re-build the webapp and reload the browser&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;
pushd webapp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; ant dist &amp;amp;&amp;amp; popd&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16740479" author="gerlowskija" created="Fri, 11 Jan 2019 15:22:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Just got a chance to test your patch.  Things look better (for Kerberos at least).  I&apos;ve attached a screenshot showing the result:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;image-wrap&quot; style=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/12954598/12954598_improved_login_page.png&quot; style=&quot;border: 0px solid black&quot; /&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16741356" author="janhoy" created="Sat, 12 Jan 2019 18:23:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Looks great &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Was there no link to the Refguide on that page?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16742928" author="janhoy" created="Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:12:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Uploaded new patch with CSS changes for the refguide link. I still wonder why I don&apos;t see the link with text &quot;Solr&apos;s Kerberos documentation&quot; in your screenshot above &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=gerlowskija&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;gerlowskija&quot;&gt;gerlowskija&lt;/a&gt;. I don&apos;t have a Kerberos environment but it shows if I fake it.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16743048" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 15 Jan 2019 13:22:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Oh shoot, I missed your last comment, sorry.  I don&apos;t remember if there was a refguide link or not.  Maybe there was a link there but my browser had issues with it for some reason?  I&apos;ll take a look again today with your latest patch and let you know.  Hopefully we can get this cleared up.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16744888" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 17 Jan 2019 10:53:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ll commit this today, it is a plain static HTML &lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt; tag link so I cannot see why it would not work?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16745039" author="jira-bot" created="Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:25:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit e515a9140677d76d4d74a32f6c8ca03a2b2f72c5 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from Jan H&#248;ydahl&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=e515a91&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=e515a91&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-13116&quot; title=&quot;Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-13116&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-13116&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16745040" author="jira-bot" created="Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:26:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 2be452d4730cc4d16773b98aa46ff50b3df7c10a in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_8x from Jan H&#248;ydahl&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=2be452d&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=2be452d&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-13116&quot; title=&quot;Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-13116&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-13116&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(cherry picked from commit e515a9140677d76d4d74a32f6c8ca03a2b2f72c5)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16745043" author="jira-bot" created="Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:30:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit c028bd7bae65df736877e3eeaf1b373add83309a in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_7x from Jan H&#248;ydahl&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=c028bd7&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=c028bd7&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-13116&quot; title=&quot;Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-13116&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-13116&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Add Admin UI login support for Kerberos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(cherry picked from commit e515a9140677d76d4d74a32f6c8ca03a2b2f72c5)&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16745044" author="janhoy" created="Thu, 17 Jan 2019 13:35:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Committed. I do not see any need for RefGuide updates, since the Kerberos page&#160;already says that users with a valid ticket can use the Admin UI. Wdyt?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16748812" author="gerlowskija" created="Tue, 22 Jan 2019 15:07:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I guess I&apos;m fine with that.  I&apos;m not sure what information we&apos;d add that wouldn&apos;t be a restatement of the instructions already on the login page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably worth double checking that this is given a good description in CHANGES.txt though, since it&apos;s such a visible change for anyone using auth.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310040">
                    <name>Required</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="requires">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12852874">SOLR-7896</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12954954" name="SOLR-13116.patch" size="3335" author="janhoy" created="Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:09:03 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12954242" name="SOLR-13116.patch" size="2809" author="janhoy" created="Wed, 9 Jan 2019 00:16:40 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12954006" name="eventual_auth.png" size="49162" author="gerlowskija" created="Mon, 7 Jan 2019 13:48:42 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12954598" name="improved_login_page.png" size="23545" author="gerlowskija" created="Fri, 11 Jan 2019 15:20:13 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>4.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            6 years, 43 weeks ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|u00hzk:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>