<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 04:44:59 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF JIRA</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SOLR-14462] Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462</link>
                <project id="12310230" key="SOLR">Solr</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;Under concurrent collection creation, wrong Autoscaling placement decisions can lead to severely unbalanced clusters.&lt;br/&gt;
 Sequential creation of the same collections is handled correctly and the cluster is balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;TL;DR;&lt;/b&gt; under high load, the way sessions that cache future changes to Zookeeper are managed cause placement decisions of multiple concurrent Collection API calls to ignore each other, be based on identical &#8220;initial&#8221; cluster state, possibly leading to identical placement decisions and as a consequence cluster imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Some context first&lt;/b&gt; for those less familiar with how Autoscaling deals with cluster state change: a PolicyHelper.Session is created with a snapshot of the Zookeeper cluster state and is used to track already decided but not yet persisted to Zookeeper cluster state changes so that Collection API commands can make the right placement decisions.&lt;br/&gt;
 A Collection API command either uses an existing cached Session (that includes changes computed by previous command(s)) or creates a new Session initialized from the Zookeeper cluster state (i.e. with only state changes already persisted).&lt;br/&gt;
 When a Collection API command requires a Session - and one is needed for any cluster state update computation - if one exists but is currently in use, the command can wait up to 10 seconds. If the session becomes available, it is reused. Otherwise, a new one is created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Session lifecycle is as follows: it is created in COMPUTING state by a Collection API command and is initialized with a snapshot of cluster state from Zookeeper (does not require a Zookeeper read, this is running on Overseer that maintains a cache of cluster state). The command has exclusive access to the Session and can change the state of the Session. When the command is done changing the Session, the Session is &#8220;returned&#8221; and its state changes to EXECUTING while the command continues to run to persist the state to Zookeeper and interact with the nodes, but no longer interacts with the Session. Another command can then grab a Session in EXECUTING state, change its state to COMPUTING to compute new changes taking into account previous changes. When all commands having used the session have completed their work, the session is &#8220;released&#8221; and destroyed (at this stage, Zookeeper contains all the state changes that were computed using that Session).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue arises when multiple Collection API commands are executed at once. A first Session is created and commands start using it one by one. In a simple 1 shard 1 replica collection creation test run with 100 parallel Collection API requests (see debug logs from PolicyHelper in file policy.logs), this Session update phase (Session in COMPUTING status in SessionWrapper) takes about 250-300ms (MacBook Pro).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that about 40 commands can run by using in turn the same Session (45 in the sample run). The commands that have been waiting for too long time out after 10 seconds, more or less all at the same time (at the rate at which they have been received by the OverseerCollectionMessageHandler, approx one per 100ms in the sample run) and most/all independently decide to create a new Session. These new Sessions are based on Zookeeper state, they might or might not include some of the changes from the first 40 commands (depending on if these commands got their changes written to Zookeeper by the time of the 10 seconds timeout, a few might have made it, see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These new Sessions (54 sessions in addition to the initial one) are based on more or less the same state, so all remaining commands are making placement decisions that do not take into account each other (and likely not much of the first 44 placement decisions either).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sample run whose relevant logs are attached led for the 100 single shard single replica collection creations to 82 collections on the Overseer node, and 5 and 13 collections on the two other nodes of a 3 nodes cluster. Given that the initial session was used 45 times (once initially then reused 44 times), one would have expected at least the first 45 collections to be evenly distributed, i.e. 15 replicas on each node. This was not the case, possibly a sign of other issues (other runs even ended up placing 0 replicas out of the 100 on one of the nodes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the client perspective, http admin collection CREATE requests averaged 19.5 seconds each and lasted between 7 and 28 seconds (100 parallel threads). This is likely an indication that the last 55 collection creations didn&#8217;t see much of the state updates done by the first 45 creations (client delay is longer though than actual Overseer command execution time by http time + Collections API Zookeeper queue time) .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A possible fix&lt;/b&gt; is to not observe any delay before creating a new Session when the currently cached session is busy (i.e. COMPUTING). It will be somewhat less optimal in low load cases (this is likely not an issue, future creations will compensate for slight unbalance and under optimal placement) but will speed up Collection API calls (no waiting) and will prevent multiple waiting commands from all creating new Sessions based on an identical Zookeeper state in cases such as the one described here. For long (minutes and more) autoscaling computations it will likely not make a big difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we had more than a single Session being cached (and reused), then less ongoing updates would be lost.&lt;br/&gt;
 Maybe, rather than caching the new updated cluster state after each change, the changes themselves (the deltas) should be tracked. This might allow to propagate changes between sessions or to reconcile cluster state read from Zookeeper with the stream of changes stored in a Session by identifying which deltas made it to Zookeeper, which ones are new from Zookeeper (originating from an update in another session) and which are still pending.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13303412">SOLR-14462</key>
            <summary>Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="ilan">Ilan Ginzburg</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="ilan">Ilan Ginzburg</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 7 May 2020 14:15:06 +0000</created>
                <updated>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 14:11:44 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:21:32 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>8.6</version>
                    <version>9.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>8.6</fixVersion>
                                    <component>AutoScaling</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>1</votes>
                                    <watches>7</watches>
                                                    <progress percentage="100">
                                    <originalProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#89afd7"/>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="transparent"/>
                                            </originalProgress>
                                                    <currentProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#51a825"/>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#ec8e00"/>
                                            </currentProgress>
                            </progress>
                                    <aggregateprogress percentage="100">
                                    <originalProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#89afd7"/>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="transparent"/>
                                            </originalProgress>
                                                    <currentProgress>
                                                    <row percentage="100" backgroundColor="#51a825"/>
                                                    <row percentage="0" backgroundColor="#ec8e00"/>
                                            </currentProgress>
                            </aggregateprogress>
                                            <timeestimate seconds="0">0h</timeestimate>
                            <timespent seconds="13800">3h 50m</timespent>
                                <comments>
                            <comment id="17101830" author="murblanc" created="Thu, 7 May 2020 16:02:18 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Did a test with no wait before creating a new Session if current cached session is COMPUTING. Doesn&apos;t work (creates a new Session every time more or less, saw 99 sessions for 100 collection creations) because the way the cache can only hold a single session make them non reusable.&lt;br/&gt;
Not waiting before creating a session implies being able to cache more than one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note the run was faster with better throughput of creations per second. Max time was significantly lower, cluster imbalance was similar. Measures below are http request times seen from JMeter for creation of 1 shard 1 replica collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait 10 seconds to see if session becomes available:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avg 17879ms, min 7794, max 26063, 3.8/sec, 81/16/3 collections per node, 57 Sessions created total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not wait, create new session if cached one not available:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avg 17721ms, min 7097, max 20951, 4.7/sec, 80/11/9 collections per node, 99 Sessions created total.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17104433" author="murblanc" created="Mon, 11 May 2020 13:06:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ab&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ab&quot;&gt;ab&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=noble&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;noble&quot;&gt;noble&lt;/a&gt; I have created a PR for fixing the caching of a single Session and cache instead multiple sessions. Also randomized the wait time a bit (from 10 seconds to 1-10 seconds) so that in case of multiple concurrent requests not all wake up together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1504&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1504&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the same parallel 100 simple collection (1 replica 1 shard, 3 nodes) creation run between before and after the change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before:&#160;Avg 17879ms, min 7794, max 26063, 3.8/sec, 81/16/3 collections per node, 57 Sessions created total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After:&#160;Avg 17328ms, min 4743, max 25176, 3.9/sec, 95/5/0 collections per node, 32 Sessions created total.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better session reuse but still very high (even higher) imbalance, due as stated above to something else. Will keep investigating.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17104435" author="noble.paul" created="Mon, 11 May 2020 13:09:44 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=murblanc&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;murblanc&quot;&gt;murblanc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall review this soon&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17104448" author="murblanc" created="Mon, 11 May 2020 13:20:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Gradle precommit (that I did not run) reports 2 violations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;cause: &apos;hasParens true prevLineNotIf true pernicketyLevel true&apos; Suspicious logging call, Parameterize and possibly surround with &apos;if (log.is*Enabled) {..}&apos;. Help at: &apos;gradlew helpValidateLogCalls&apos;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;/home/runner/work/lucene-solr/lucene-solr/solr/solrj/src/java/org/apache/solr/client/solrj/cloud/autoscaling/PolicyHelper.java:433,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is wrongly detected, there is a surrounding &quot;if (log.isDebugEnabled())&quot; around the log, but the if bloc also gets the TimeSource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;cause: &apos;hasPlus: true&apos; Suspicious logging call, Parameterize and possibly surround with &apos;if (log.is*Enabled) {..}&apos;. Help at: &apos;gradlew helpValidateLogCalls&apos;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&#160;&lt;em&gt;/home/runner/work/lucene-solr/lucene-solr/solr/solrj/src/java/org/apache/solr/client/solrj/cloud/autoscaling/PolicyHelper.java:555).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likely because the log is written as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;log.debug(&quot;New session created, &quot; + sessionWrapper.getCreateTime());&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and not:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;log.debug(&quot;New session created, {}&quot;, sessionWrapper.getCreateTime());&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The direct concatenation is more efficient in Java. If Solr coding standards impose the &quot;format&quot; style for logs, I&apos;ll change it (format style make sense when there&apos;s not surrounding if for debug level, as they&apos;re cheaper to not execute than the concatenation that would have to be executed even if the log is not output).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17104452" author="murblanc" created="Mon, 11 May 2020 13:27:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;PolicyHelper logs for 100 collection creation with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1504&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;PR 1504&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nobr&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/attachment/13002633/13002633_PolicyHelperNewLogs.txt&quot; title=&quot;PolicyHelperNewLogs.txt attached to SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;PolicyHelperNewLogs.txt&lt;sup&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rendericon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/link_attachment_7.gif&quot; height=&quot;7&quot; width=&quot;7&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17107302" author="murblanc" created="Thu, 14 May 2020 13:37:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In existing (9.0 master) code as well as in the PR, when a new Session is required, it is created in PolicyHelper.createSession() called from PolicyHelper.get().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session is therefore created while holding the&#160;lockObj lock!&lt;br/&gt;
When SolrCloud has a large number of collections/shards/replicas, session creation can take a few seconds. Parallel session creation is therefore significantly delayed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be better to not hold the lock while creating the session. That lock should only be used to protect changes to SessionRef (and should be acquired after a Session got created to register that session with the SessionRef).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17112435" author="murblanc" created="Wed, 20 May 2020 16:45:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I took into account the comments and updated the PR (+ rebase).&#160;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1504&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1504&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This includes now changes to the way new Sessions are created when needed, by &lt;ins&gt;taking the actual creation outside of the critical section&lt;/ins&gt;. Performance tests run elsewhere showed that with a large number of collections in a cluster creating the session could take quite some time, and because it is serialized with existing implementation, these times add up when multiple commands are run (and running 100 commands concurrently is supported in Overseer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the proposal here, creations can happen concurrently. There&apos;s a random wait delay used to wait for sessions to be returned if there already exists cached sessions OR if sessions are in the process of being created. This avoid the thundering herd effect of all waiting threads making the same decision at the same time and ending up creating a large number of sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17120524" author="murblanc" created="Sun, 31 May 2020 12:44:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=noble.paul&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;noble.paul&quot;&gt;noble.paul&lt;/a&gt;&#160;do you think you&apos;ll be able to have a look at this?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17144258" author="jira-bot" created="Wed, 24 Jun 2020 20:02:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 25428013fb0ed8f8fdbebdef3f1d65dea77129c2 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from Ilan Ginzburg&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=2542801&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=2542801&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: cache more than one autoscaling session (#1504)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: cache more than one autoscaling session&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17144259" author="jira-bot" created="Wed, 24 Jun 2020 20:02:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 25428013fb0ed8f8fdbebdef3f1d65dea77129c2 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from Ilan Ginzburg&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=2542801&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=2542801&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: cache more than one autoscaling session (#1504)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: cache more than one autoscaling session&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17147685" author="ab" created="Mon, 29 Jun 2020 11:04:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This should be back-ported to 8.6, it&apos;s an important bugfix.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17147697" author="murblanc" created="Mon, 29 Jun 2020 11:22:51 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Reopening to backport for 8.6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FYI &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=broustant&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;broustant&quot;&gt;broustant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17147788" author="murblanc" created="Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:37:46 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;PR for backport to branch_8x for inclusion in 8.6 at&#160;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1630&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://github.com/apache/lucene-solr/pull/1630&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t know if I&apos;ll have more luck now for a review than with the original version in master, otherwise I&apos;ll merge that later today...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17148059" author="jira-bot" created="Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:20:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 78152876fda92c61d1c6bcdf5e8953042a592b4f in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_8x from Ilan Ginzburg&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=7815287&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=7815287&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: cache more than one autoscaling session (#1630)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cherry picked from 25428013fb0ed8f8fdbebdef3f1d65dea77129c2&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17148061" author="murblanc" created="Mon, 29 Jun 2020 18:21:32 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Merged into branch_8x for inclusion in 8.6 release.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17152812" author="jira-bot" created="Tue, 7 Jul 2020 15:13:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit 06b1f3e86694b35365fd569a0581b1f6fc2cadb3 in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/master from Ilan Ginzburg&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=06b1f3e&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=06b1f3e&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: adjust test so less sessions are used even if test runs slowly. fix synchronization issue. (#1656)&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="17152822" author="jira-bot" created="Tue, 7 Jul 2020 15:30:58 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Commit e65631e026c5bb5c8eeb6fd1351bf798c0c6985c in lucene-solr&apos;s branch refs/heads/branch_8x from Ilan Ginzburg&lt;br/&gt;
[ &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=e65631e&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=lucene-solr.git;h=e65631e&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SOLR-14462&quot; title=&quot;Autoscaling placement wrong with concurrent collection creations&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SOLR-14462&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SOLR-14462&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: adjust test so less sessions are used even if test runs slowly. fix synchronization issue. (#1657)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cherry picked from 06b1f3e86694b35365fd569a0581b1f6fc2cadb3&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17158322" author="broustant" created="Wed, 15 Jul 2020 15:09:55 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Closing after the 8.6.0 release&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="13002633" name="PolicyHelperNewLogs.txt" size="85118" author="ilan" created="Mon, 11 May 2020 13:26:43 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="13002302" name="policylogs.txt" size="113121" author="ilan" created="Thu, 7 May 2020 14:13:03 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            5 years, 17 weeks, 6 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z0eh74:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313321" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:message">
                        <customfieldname>Solr Mailing List Info</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>