<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 05:55:15 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[AMQ-2656] ActiveMQInitialConnectionFactory cannot return an XAConnectionFactory</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/AMQ-2656</link>
                <project id="12311210" key="AMQ">ActiveMQ Classic</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;ActiveMQInitialContextFactory cannot resolve the name &quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot;  a la:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INFO: JNDI API lookup failed: javax.naming.NameNotFoundException: XAConnectionFactory&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This prevents using the builtin JNDI service in an XA transaction context.  I&apos;ve created a simple patch to workaround this and discussed it on the mailing list:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://old.nabble.com/ActiveMQ%27s-JNDI-does-not-resolve-XAConnectionFactory-td27936255.html&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://old.nabble.com/ActiveMQ%27s-JNDI-does-not-resolve-XAConnectionFactory-td27936255.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12483476">AMQ-2656</key>
            <summary>ActiveMQInitialConnectionFactory cannot return an XAConnectionFactory</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="gtully">Gary Tully</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="edan">Edan idzerda</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 19:51:56 +0000</created>
                <updated>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 11:41:21 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 11:41:21 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>5.3.0</version>
                                    <fixVersion>5.4.0</fixVersion>
                    <fixVersion>5.7.0</fixVersion>
                                    <component>JMS client</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>3</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="12936918" author="gtully" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 20:05:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;added support for a boolean xa property in the environment which will cause an xa connection factory to be created. r924972&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;xa=&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or on a lookup name basis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;connection.&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;.xa=&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;will result in an XAConnectionFactory being created.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12937601" author="edan" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 20:20:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This is my patched version that allows me to jndiContext.lookup(&quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot;) and get a working XAConnectionFactory.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12939050" author="edan" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 20:24:00 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Gary, will your patch (I can&apos;t see it yet) allow me to JNDI lookup &quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot;  ?  That may be all I have available in webMethods &quot;JNDI Provider Alias&quot; settings.  I guess I can try to lookup connection.MyConnection or something along those lines.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12939391" author="gtully" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 20:45:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;check out the subversion commits tag to see the changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may not be enough for you if you cannot augment the environment to add the xa=true property.&lt;br/&gt;
there is also a property for the connectionFactoryNames where you can provide the list of names you will expect. This overrides the DEFAULT_CONNECTION_FACTORY_NAMES&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12941940" author="edan" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 01:31:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;At least from work, it took a while for the source code to show up in Crucible.  I saw it before I left work, but I wasn&apos;t able to get it to work.  I&apos;ll try again tomorrow, but I get ClassCastException trying to cast ActiveMQConnectionFactory to ActiveMQXAConnectionFactory.  Maybe that should work since it&apos;s a subclass, but that error makes me doubtful &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;  So far I&apos;ve only been successful with my patch which returns an ActiveMQXAConnectionFactory specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From within webMethods, I can set &quot;other properties&quot; which seem to be &quot;jndi.properties.&quot;   I tried adding &quot;MyConnection&quot; to my custom list of connectionFactoryNames, but I was unsuccessful performing a context.lookup() on &quot;MyConnection.xa=true&quot; or &quot;connection.MyConnection.xa=true&quot; ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I can get your patch working, I still want to modify the DEFAULT_CONNECTION_FACTORY_NAMES to include &quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot; to make it available as easily as the other standard JMS types.  Thanks for your help on this &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12941992" author="edan" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 03:05:04 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This version is based on the latest svn but adds an XAConnectionFactory to the default list of factories, and sets the &quot;xa&quot; environment value manually for that factory during creation.  I was able to test the original patch successfully, and this patch lets me lookup &quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot; via the JNDI context which I believe will be required to easily integrate with webMethods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it should be a regexp so any custom connection name with &quot;XA&quot; will get the treatment?  &lt;b&gt;shrug&lt;/b&gt;  I guess I think that at a minimum, a default connection factory name like &quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot; should work without setting environment variables.  But I what do I know, seriously...   &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/wink.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12942038" author="gtully" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 11:19:11 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;If you can specify in other properties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;connectionFactoryNames=XAConnectionFactory
xa=&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;context.lookup(&lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot;&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; will be an instanceof XAConnectionFactory&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12941998" author="edan" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 15:46:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the pointers on the properties.  I was able to just have a line with &quot;xa=true&quot; in both my jndi.properties for my standalone java client test and the &quot;Other Properties&quot; in webMethods and create an &quot;XA&quot; transaction by just looking up &quot;ConnectionFactory.&quot;  It seems to apply to all ConnectionFactory lookups, though, so my standalone java client gets an exception when sending a message:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;javax.jms.JMSException: Session&apos;s XAResource has not been enlisted in a distributed transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assume there is no way to limit the xa=true property to a particular connection factory lookup with this method.  (If I use your snippet above a lookup of &quot;ConnectionFactory&quot; fails, for instance.)  It seems less desirable to me to be forced into creating separate processes or JNDI Providers in webMethods to do XA or not.  But I can work with the patch you have submitted for 5.4.0, as opposed to current.  Once we&apos;ve had a chance to test out the current patch in webMethods more, perhaps we will see if it is a big of a pain or not.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m tempted to keep my patch locally, as it strikes me as much easier to remember &quot;just look up XAConnectionFactory if that&apos;s what you need&quot; as opposed to configuring the environment.  OTOH, it may be harder to remember to keep my local patch when we upgrade someday &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;  Thanks again.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12941988" author="gtully" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 15:53:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;you are nearly there, try&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;connectionFactoryNames=XAConnectionFactory,ConnectionFactory
connection.XAConnectionFactory.xa=&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you can lookup both an xa and non xa connectonfactory by their respective names.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12942125" author="edan" created="Tue, 23 Mar 2010 20:14:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Why didn&apos;t you mention that in the first place!?!?!   Oh... Because you did... DOH!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, that is working fine for both my Java client test and our webMethods environment, even as far as verifying a transaction can be rolled back.    I still think XAConnectionFactory should be available without additional configuration, for instance, just yesterday I had to remind a coworker to copy the properties configuration after setting up a new system &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is working and I don&apos;t want to be too pushy with my first reported issue &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;  Thanks a lot for the help.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12942816" author="sapunce" created="Wed, 1 Sep 2010 14:37:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hello Gary and Edan, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the same problem using the XAConnectionFactory with ActiveMQ. &lt;br/&gt;
Could please tell me is this patch released and how can I use it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;br/&gt;
Nace&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12942803" author="gtully" created="Wed, 1 Sep 2010 15:25:14 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;it is in 5.4.0, see the fix version above and the comment: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/activemq/browse/AMQ-2656?focusedCommentId=58336&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels%3Acomment-tabpanel#action_58336&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/activemq/browse/AMQ-2656?focusedCommentId=58336&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels%3Acomment-tabpanel#action_58336&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that has details of the properties.&lt;br/&gt;
There is also a test you can browse: &lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://fisheye6.cenqua.com/browse/activemq/trunk/activemq-core/src/test/java/org/apache/activemq/jndi/XAConnectionFactoryTest.java&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://fisheye6.cenqua.com/browse/activemq/trunk/activemq-core/src/test/java/org/apache/activemq/jndi/XAConnectionFactoryTest.java&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12942794" author="sapunce" created="Thu, 2 Sep 2010 10:32:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your fast response Gary. Yes it works for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again, &lt;br/&gt;
Nace&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12986410" author="hindsbeans" created="Tue, 25 Jan 2011 14:52:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Gary, thanks for your help on this. In the end I had to use the version of ActiveMQInitialContextFactory.java as attached by Edan idzerda at 2010-03-18 11:05 PM. I had a search through the ActiveMQ issue tracker and couldn&apos;t find if Edan&apos;s suggested code was ever added to core - do you know if it was? It would be very useful if it was for cases like the one I have outlined below where the setting up of the jndi environment is abstracted up out of the code. (i.e. in websphere you cannot define the &apos;xa=true&apos; property anywhere - hence Edan&apos;s &apos;XAConnection&apos; jndi name is invaluable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anybody else trying to get a connection to ActiveMQ within a WebSphere7.0.0-managed XA transaction and getting an error of &quot;An illegal attempt to commit a one phase capable resource with existing two phase capable resources has occured&quot; in the WebSphere SystemOut.log. This error was thrown when a Message Driven Bean was fired from a WebSphere default jms queue and it tried to write a message to an ActiveMQ queue all within an XA transaction. There was an Oracle db write in the same transaction also. Here are the steps to get around it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Use the attached file kindly attached by Edan at 2010-03-18 11:05 PM to compile activemq-5.4.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) In WebSphere Admin Console, create a new JMS provider:&lt;br/&gt;
i) Resources &amp;gt; JMS &amp;gt; JMS providers &amp;gt; New&lt;br/&gt;
ii) Use the following:&lt;br/&gt;
    Name: use a name like &apos;ActiveMQ 5.4.0&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
    Classpath: add the paths to the following jar files (each path needs to be on a new line in the text box) activemq-all-5.4.0.jar, commons-logging-1.1.jar, geronimo-j2ee-management_1.1_spec-1.0.1.jar&lt;br/&gt;
    External Initial Context Factory: org.apache.activemq.jndi.ActiveMQWASInitialContextFactory&lt;br/&gt;
    External Provider URL: tcp://localhost:61616&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) In WebSphere Admin Console, create a new ConnectionFactory&lt;br/&gt;
i) Resources &amp;gt; JMS &amp;gt; Connection factories &amp;gt; New&lt;br/&gt;
ii) Use the following:&lt;br/&gt;
    Name: use a name like &apos;ActiveMQ 5.4.0 Connection Factory&apos;&lt;br/&gt;
    JNDI name: jmsfactory/activemq540connfactory (this will be the name that any WebSphere-run apps will lookup using jndi)&lt;br/&gt;
    External JNDI name: XAConnectionFactory (this is the new name added by Edan&apos;s code in step 1 above - basically, when you&apos;re code running in WebSphere calls &apos;jmsfactory/activemq540connfactory&apos;, WebSphere does a call to activemq using this jndi name, i.e. XAConnectionFactory )&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="12986433" author="gtully" created="Tue, 25 Jan 2011 15:29:43 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;@peter, thanks for closing the loop on this with the feeback.&lt;br/&gt;
So in 2.ii or 3.i - there is no possibility to specify an additional property for the jndi environment?&lt;br/&gt;
not good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So either we have a hardcoded xaconnection factory, Edan&apos;s fix, or the &apos;xa=true&apos; jndi env property needs to be embedded in the 2.ii external provider url, like tcp://localhost:61616?jndi.xa=true&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="12986512" author="hindsbeans" created="Tue, 25 Jan 2011 16:56:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;In websphere there are options in 2.ii and 3.i to add what are called &apos;custom properties&apos; but these do not get translated into jndi environment properties unfortulately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of which route to take I would say that the provider url should be left intact. To me it would be more intuitive if the name you supply to a jndi lookup call determines if an ActiveMQXAConnectionFactory or an ActiveMQConnectionFactory is returned as opposed to the provider url used to create the InitialContext. I guess setting it in the provider url abstracts it away from where it is relevant, which is in the jndi lookup call. As in all things though, this is just my opinion - and I&apos;m more than wiling to be corrected!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the &apos;XAConnectionFactory&apos; jndi name also has the additional benefit of leaving the well recognised url of &apos;tcp://localhost:61616&apos; untouched as well as being tried and tested - thanks to Edan!!&lt;/p&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="12988215" author="gtully" created="Fri, 28 Jan 2011 20:21:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;opening so we don&apos;t forget to add a hard coded xa factory name.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="13411422" author="gtully" created="Wed, 11 Jul 2012 11:41:21 +0000"  >
&lt;p&gt;URL: &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?rev=1360125&amp;amp;view=rev&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?rev=1360125&amp;amp;view=rev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Log:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/AMQ-2656&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/AMQ-2656&lt;/a&gt; - add wellknown xa factory name, XAConnectionFactory so that context.lookup(&quot;XAConnectionFactory&quot;) will work as expected out of the box&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="10001">
                    <name>dependent</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is depended upon by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12483181">AMQ-2670</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12461576" name="ActiveMQInitialContextFactory.java" size="8422" author="edan" created="Fri, 19 Mar 2010 03:05:04 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12461439" name="ActiveMQInitialContextFactory.java" size="9409" author="edan" created="Thu, 18 Mar 2010 20:20:33 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>74857</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            13 years, 19 weeks, 6 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i0akiv:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>59598</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>