<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 07:27:11 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[MJAVADOC-452] Several fixes for comment corruption in fix goal</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-452</link>
                <project id="12317529" key="MJAVADOC">Maven Javadoc Plugin (Moved to GitHub Issues)</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve attached a patch to this issue that fixes several problems in javadoc:fix, including issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-420&quot; title=&quot;javadoc:fix duplicates lines&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-420&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-420&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-434&quot; title=&quot;Running javadoc:fix corrupts files&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-434&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-434&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-451&quot; title=&quot;Add &amp;quot;skip&amp;quot; option to javadoc:fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-451&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-451&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and adds some improvements to the fix goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Done&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; added a new config parameter &quot;removeUnknownThrows&quot;, to tell the plugin to remove a @throws tag if the exception class is not actually thrown. Previously it only warned. I set the default value to &quot;false&quot; to preserve existing behavior&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Done&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; in &quot;processFix&quot;, I added a check to see if the content had actually been changed before writing to disk. This preserves file timestamps and provides a clear indication if any changes were actually made&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Superceded&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; a problem in &quot;updateJavadocTags&quot; for method comments specifically, where, if a throws tag was unknown, it would be written at the bottom of the comments e.g. after @return, @since etc. I fixed updateJavadocTags so that method tags are always output in the prescribed order&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Done&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; I fixed issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-420&quot; title=&quot;javadoc:fix duplicates lines&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-420&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-420&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where if two method parameters existed with overlapping names (e.g. @param thing @param thing2), then the second parameter would be added twice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Done&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; there was an issue if a comment erroneously contained the same parameter twice (.e.g @param thing, @param thing), where both tags would be duplicated, and all instances would have the description of the first. this was fixed in &quot;updateJavadocTags&quot; and &quot;addMissingJavadocTags&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6) &lt;b&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;Superceded&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Includes the same fix as attached to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-451&quot; title=&quot;Add &amp;quot;skip&amp;quot; option to javadoc:fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-451&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-451&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which adds a &quot;skip&quot; parameter, which is useful when used in conjunction with &quot;force&quot;. Also this parameter prevents &quot;clirr&quot; from causing javadoc:fix from being re-invoked when clirr is kicked off, which would cause an infinite loop of fix-&lt;del&gt;&amp;gt;clirr&lt;/del&gt;&lt;del&gt;&amp;gt;fix&lt;/del&gt;-&amp;gt;clirr. This scenario is prevented by internally passing the &quot;skip&quot; parameter into the invocation of clirr&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the patch will also resolve &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-434&quot; title=&quot;Running javadoc:fix corrupts files&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-434&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-434&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, corrupted files (basically the end-comment tag was left in the middle of the comment block causing syntax errors) because I also observed this behavior and I don&apos;t now after the patch, but I didn&apos;t actually trace down the root cause of 434 to be certain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly I updated some of the log messages to be more descriptive and indicative of the actual activity (e.g. changed &quot;fixing&quot; to &quot;analyzing&quot;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the tags are output in the prescribed order, two of the JUnit test &quot;expected&quot; java output files needed to be updated to put the @return tag below their @param tags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attached patch file updates AbstractFixJavadocMojo.jar, and two test resources. All JUnit tests pass successfully. The patch was generated against the 2.10.3 tag in SVN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="12970989">MJAVADOC-452</key>
            <summary>Several fixes for comment corruption in fix goal</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="11">Done</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="rfscholte">Robert Scholte</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="rsand">Richard Sand</reporter>
                        <labels>
                            <label>patch</label>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 19 May 2016 02:55:25 +0000</created>
                <updated>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 04:13:13 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 13:15:25 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>2.10.3</version>
                                                    <component>fix</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>5</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="15303727" author="rfscholte" created="Fri, 27 May 2016 07:59:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s go through the list:&lt;br/&gt;
1. Nice fix&lt;br/&gt;
2. Interesting enhancement&lt;br/&gt;
3. Nice improvement&lt;br/&gt;
4. Let&apos;s fix it as part of  &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-420&quot; title=&quot;javadoc:fix duplicates lines&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-420&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-420&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I asume this can be a separate patch&lt;br/&gt;
5. Related to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-420&quot; title=&quot;javadoc:fix duplicates lines&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-420&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-420&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;? Let&apos;s try to fix it there.&lt;br/&gt;
6. I don&apos;t like the skip-parameter for this fix-goal, there must be a better solution. But let&apos;s discuss that at &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-451&quot; title=&quot;Add &amp;quot;skip&amp;quot; option to javadoc:fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-451&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-451&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. There must be a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m missing the junittest which confirm these issues. Before applying the patches to &lt;tt&gt;src/main/java&lt;/tt&gt; I&apos;d like to see failing tests which will succeed after applying the &lt;tt&gt;src/test/java&lt;/tt&gt; patches.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15304830" author="rsand" created="Fri, 27 May 2016 21:32:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Robert - thanks for replying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fixes for 3,4, and 5 all involve changes to the same method updateJavadocTags so its going to be difficult to create separate patches for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The patch I uploaded to the case also included the patches for the 2 JUnit test sample pages. Understand that I did not change the actual tests, I only changed the sample pages it compares the output with, so that the sample page now has the tags in the proper order as created by the goal. The two failures were simply due to fix #3 - because the old behavior added missing tags at the bottom of the javadoc, instead of preserving order, so those two JUnit tests were comparing to an output file that had the tags in the wrong order. I will doublecheck the patch file to make sure the JUnit test pages are in there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding #6, I&apos;ll reply in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-451&quot; title=&quot;Add &amp;quot;skip&amp;quot; option to javadoc:fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-451&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-451&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; thread. Thanks again!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15305093" author="rsand" created="Sat, 28 May 2016 01:42:39 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Yes take a look at the very bottom of the patch file, you&apos;ll see the fixes to the test output pages where I simply switched the location of two tags to be consistent with fix #3&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15305540" author="rfscholte" created="Sat, 28 May 2016 18:50:52 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Current patch is just too big for me to evaluate all changes. So split it up a bit, please.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15306998" author="rsand" created="Mon, 30 May 2016 23:06:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Robert, its a pain to split it up, is it ok if I walk through the changes in the patch file? Here is a description of every change by line # (the line # in the patch file that is):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17: added boolean config param &quot;removeUnknownThrows&quot; for removing unknown throws, default is false&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;30: added boolean config param &quot;maven.javadoc.fix.skip&quot; for skipping the fix goal, default is false&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;43: inside execute() method, added check for skip=true&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;57: in properties passed into CLIRR invocation, added &quot;maven.javadoc.fix.skip=true&quot; to prevent CLIRR from invoking fix and looping &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;I understand you don&amp;#39;t like that, but it&amp;#39;s simple and straightforward&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;68: added capability to detect if any actual changes have been made to the contents of the file before saving - line 68 initializes a new BufferedReader for holding the contents for comparison&lt;br/&gt;
75: reads the output file into our BufferedReader&lt;br/&gt;
86: closes the new BufferedReader&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;101: changed the log message from &quot;fixing&quot; to &quot;analyzing&quot;, since here we are only looking for fixes, later we will log if any fixes were performed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;112: moved &quot;String line&quot; variable declaration into the loop itself&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;121: added a missing &quot;close&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;130: does a line-by-line comparison of the original content to the new content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;136: added a log statement saying that we were saving changes to this file because changes were made&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;148: no code change here, just changed the formatting so each method was on its own line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;169: moved &quot;addMissingJavadocTags&quot; above &quot;updateJavadocTags&quot; - this is because we added a new method &quot;writeJavadocTags&quot; which does the actual output, so addMissingJavadocTags doesn&apos;t actually output anything, it just adds the missing tags to the list&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;177: added writeJavadocTags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;185: we are inside parseJavadocTags - we are now passing the javaEntityTags object into getJavadocComment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;198: here instead of directly putting the throws tag into the javaEntityTags, we call fixThrowsTag&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;207-312: the method updateJavadocTags has been modified a fair amount. First, it has been renamed to writeJavadocTags - this method writes all of the tags provided, and uniformly ensures that every tag ends in an EOL with no extra whitespaces trailing. The main change is its handling specifically of methods comments. Here, it uses the javaEntityTags to find all of the tags it needs to write, since we have ensured that the javaEntityTags are populated with everything that the comment should have&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;314: the method writeParamTag is now passed in the 1 specific tag it is supposed to be writing, instead of the array of all parameters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;318: removed call to fixQdox because that was called outside of writeParamTag&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;329: changed log message from &quot;fixed unknown param&quot; to &quot;removed unknown param&quot; to provide a clearer message&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;338: we renamed the method &quot;writeThrowsTag&quot; to &quot;fixThrowsTag&quot; because this method no longer writes any output, but just fixes the tag within the javaEntityTags. we added a new &quot;writeThrowsTag&quot; later to do the actual output writing&lt;br/&gt;
354: instead of writing the tag, put it into javaEntityTags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;360-371: no code changes, just formatting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;381-386: we don&apos;t output the tag, just update the String and put it back into the javaEntityTags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;392: add check for &quot;removeUnknownThrows&quot;&lt;br/&gt;
394-396: updated log message to explicitly state that the throws is being ignored (removed)&lt;br/&gt;
399-405: updated log message to explicitly state that an unknown throws was found but is being included&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;409-441: new method &quot;writeThrowsTag&quot; which does the actual output&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;455-456: addMissingJavadocTags no longer needs a StringBuffer since it no longer does any output writing. Instead any changes it makes are added to the javaEntityTags&lt;br/&gt;
464-467: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;java parameter&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
475-478: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;type parameter&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
486-489: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;return tag&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
497-500: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;throws tag&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
508-511: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;author tag&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
515-518: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;version tag&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
526-529: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;since tag, new class&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
534-538: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;since tag, existing class&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
546-549: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;since tag, new method&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
557-560: instead of writing to the output, we create a new javaEntityTags entry &lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;since tag, existing&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;568: added missing close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;578: added missing close&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;587-592: because we modified &quot;getJavadocComment&quot; to add the javaEntityTags parameter, specifically for dealing with method comments, we add this invocation with null for javaEntityTags to preserve existing invocations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;600,605-606: here we add javaEntityTags to getJavadocComment, which allows us to make sure that the same parameter isn&apos;t output multiple times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;614-624: here we make sure that the tag currently being processed hasn&apos;t already been added to the javaEntityTags&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;630-666: here we add the logic to make sure that two parameters with overlapping names don&apos;t conflict, e.g. &quot;@param something&quot; and @param &quot;somethingelse&quot;, and if the same tag exists twice, e.g. &quot;@param something&quot;, &quot;@param something&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

</comment>
                            <comment id="15368919" author="rsand" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 03:42:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;this patch is for the improvement that a file is not saved if no changes are made&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15368922" author="rsand" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 03:48:15 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I uploaded a fix for item #2 in my list above (only saving the file if its been changed). If you add this into the trunk, I&apos;ll check out the latest and create another patch for item #1 (new config option for removing unknown throws), which is also self-contained. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, item #6 (skipJavaDoc) is also self-contained, although I know you don&apos;t like that fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then items 3-5 I hope we can tackle as one patch since they all involve updates to the same method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15369038" author="rfscholte" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 09:41:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch for #2 applied in &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?rev=1751993&amp;amp;view=rev&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;r.1751993&lt;/a&gt; with small adjustments, i.e. never pass the changeDetected flag. Instead every method simply returns &lt;tt&gt;true&lt;/tt&gt; if they did an update,otherwise &lt;tt&gt;false&lt;/tt&gt;. The &lt;tt&gt;processFix&lt;/tt&gt;-method will keep track if there are any changes.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15369044" author="hudson" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 09:57:59 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;SUCCESS: Integrated in maven-plugins #6858 (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://builds.apache.org/job/maven-plugins/6858/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://builds.apache.org/job/maven-plugins/6858/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-452&quot; title=&quot;Several fixes for comment corruption in fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-452&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-452&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Several fixes for comment corruption in fix goal&lt;br/&gt;
Only write file if there&apos;s actually an updateEntityComment&lt;br/&gt;
Patch contributed by Richard Sand; reviewed and applied with small adjustments by Robert Scholte (rfscholte: &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc/?view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1751993&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc/?view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1751993&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;maven-javadoc-plugin/pom.xml&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;maven-javadoc-plugin/src/main/java/org/apache/maven/plugin/javadoc/AbstractFixJavadocMojo.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;maven-javadoc-plugin/src/test/java/org/apache/maven/plugin/javadoc/FixJavadocMojoTest.java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="15369310" author="rsand" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 21:57:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Robert. You saw what I was going for with passing the state into each method, just to save doing the string compares to detect changes if we know there are changes already. Not a big deal either way, code is cleaner and makes more sense the way you structured it. I&apos;ll work on the next patch now&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15369316" author="rsand" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 22:11:10 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This simple patch adds the option to remove unknown throws&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15369535" author="rfscholte" created="Sun, 10 Jul 2016 10:07:45 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Patch for #1 applied in &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc?rev=1752069&amp;amp;view=rev&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;r1752069&lt;/a&gt; and which also exposes why it is important to add unittests, because the line was still added. I&apos;ve decide to rewrite the logic a bit. The new parameter will only kick in if the the class can&apos;t be found on the classpath, probably caused by a typo. The unittest should explain all cases.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15369550" author="hudson" created="Sun, 10 Jul 2016 10:24:33 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;SUCCESS: Integrated in maven-plugins #6895 (See &lt;a href=&quot;https://builds.apache.org/job/maven-plugins/6895/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://builds.apache.org/job/maven-plugins/6895/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-452&quot; title=&quot;Several fixes for comment corruption in fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-452&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-452&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Several fixes for comment corruption in fix goal&lt;br/&gt;
Add parameter removeUnknownThrows&lt;br/&gt;
Patch contributed by Richard Sand; reviewed and applied with adjustments by Robert Scholte (rfscholte: &lt;a href=&quot;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc/?view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1752069&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;http://svn.apache.org/viewvc/?view=rev&amp;amp;rev=1752069&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;maven-javadoc-plugin/src/main/java/org/apache/maven/plugin/javadoc/AbstractFixJavadocMojo.java&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;maven-javadoc-plugin/src/test/java/org/apache/maven/plugin/javadoc/FixJavadocMojoTest.java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="15373729" author="rsand" created="Tue, 12 Jul 2016 21:26:17 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Robert. I uploaded the patch to #6 to &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/MJAVADOC-451&quot; title=&quot;Add &amp;quot;skip&amp;quot; option to javadoc:fix goal&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;MJAVADOC-451&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;MJAVADOC-451&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16730645" author="hudson" created="Sat, 29 Dec 2018 11:20:12 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Build failed in Jenkins: Maven TLP &#187; maven-javadoc-plugin &#187; master #113&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://builds.apache.org/job/maven-box/job/maven-javadoc-plugin/job/master/113/&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://builds.apache.org/job/maven-box/job/maven-javadoc-plugin/job/master/113/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16730690" author="rfscholte" created="Sat, 29 Dec 2018 13:15:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;All 6 issues have an answer. Some are implemented some time ago, some will be part of 3.1.0.&lt;br/&gt;
With that I&apos;ll close this issue. If there are any issues left, create a new Jira entry to keep focus on 1 issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17957810" author="olamy" created="Tue, 10 Jun 2025 04:13:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This project has moved from Jira to GitHub Issues. This issue was migrated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/maven-javadoc-plugin/issues/744&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;apache/maven-javadoc-plugin#744&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310051">
                    <name>Supercedes</name>
                                                                <inwardlinks description="is superceded by">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13206957">MJAVADOC-559</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12969724">MJAVADOC-451</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </inwardlinks>
                                    </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12805122" name="maven-javadoc-plugin-MJAVADOC452.patch" size="29688" author="rsand" created="Fri, 20 May 2016 03:28:02 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12816972" name="maven-javadoc-plugin-OnlySaveIfChanged.patch" size="12071" author="rsand" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 03:42:56 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12817013" name="maven-javadoc-plugin-RemoveUnknownThrowsOption.patch" size="1556" author="rsand" created="Sat, 9 Jul 2016 22:11:10 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>3.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[no_permission]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12310250" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multicheckboxes">
                        <customfieldname>Flags</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="10430"><![CDATA[Patch]]></customfieldvalue>
    <customfieldvalue key="10431"><![CDATA[Important]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            22 weeks, 1 day ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i2y6nz:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>