<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 19:38:03 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[LOG4J2-1653] CronTriggeringPolicy uses wrong naming and produces NPE</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1653</link>
                <project id="12310790" key="LOG4J2">Log4j 2</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;After having worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1649&quot; title=&quot;CronTriggeringPolicy breaks awefully when using &amp;quot;reconfigure&amp;quot; of LoggerContext&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1649&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1649&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; I found another serious issue in combination with the CronTriggeringPolicy.&lt;br/&gt;
The policy has some very weird behaviour when it comes to naming rolled over files and also creates a NPE on specific configurations.&lt;br/&gt;
The following is broken:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;when using &quot;evaluateOnStartup&quot; a NPE is the result of an immediate rollover&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;when no rollover is happing at startup the first rollover produces a file that uses the time of the rollover (e.g. rollover is happening at midnight 2010-05-05 producing a rolled over file named log-2010-05-05)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;but it becomes worse: all files after the first rollover are named using a date of the &quot;previous rollover date minus a second&quot; - when using the previous example this results in:
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;first rollover happening at midnight 2010-05-05, resulting in file log-2010-05-05&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;next rollover happening at 2010-05-06, resulting in file log-2010-05-04&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;next rollover happening at 2010-05-07, resulting in file log-2010-05-05 again &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/warning.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; so the previously saved file gets removed!&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I would expect the file to be named after the content it contains. E.g. a file rolled over at 2010-05-05 should be named log-2010-05-04 as it contains all the data of the 2010-05-04.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to write a patch for those problems too (again the sources of Log4J2 2.7 were used). Unfortunately I needed a method to calculate the last cron date. The CronExpression class has such a method (&quot;getTimeBefore&quot;) but nobody implemented this one since years.&lt;br/&gt;
The only quick solution I found: I used another 3rd party library to fix this called cronutils. The solution I wrote uses the latest version of this library which now only supports Java 8.&lt;br/&gt;
My guess is that you don&apos;t want Log4J2 to only support Java 8 - if this is the case you will have to use a different library/version or whatever to be able to calculate the last cron date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This patch should also fix the following bugs: &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1640&quot; title=&quot;RollingFileAppender with CronTriggeringPolicy broken?&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1640&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1640&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1621&quot; title=&quot;RollingFileAppender can&amp;#39;t generate daily file according to cron expressions &quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1621&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1621&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1487&quot; title=&quot;Log4j RollingFileAppender every minute&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1487&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1487&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1474&quot; title=&quot;CronTriggeringPolicy raise exception and fail to rollover log file when evaluateOnStartup is true.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1474&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1474&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (and maybe even more - I didn&apos;t feel like searching the whole Jira &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/wink.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13016106">LOG4J2-1653</key>
            <summary>CronTriggeringPolicy uses wrong naming and produces NPE</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="2" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/critical.svg">Critical</priority>
                        <status id="5" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/resolved.png" description="A resolution has been taken, and it is awaiting verification by reporter. From here issues are either reopened, or are closed.">Resolved</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="rgoers">Ralph Goers</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="GFriedrich">Georg Friedrich</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 10:38:04 +0000</created>
                <updated>Mon, 9 Jan 2017 07:07:55 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Mon, 9 Jan 2017 07:07:55 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>2.7</version>
                                    <fixVersion>2.8</fixVersion>
                                        <due></due>
                            <votes>1</votes>
                                    <watches>7</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="15789853" author="gfriedrich" created="Sat, 31 Dec 2016 18:27:54 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=garydgregory&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;garydgregory&quot;&gt;garydgregory&lt;/a&gt; can you give any update on this? You&apos;ve already fixed &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1474&quot; title=&quot;CronTriggeringPolicy raise exception and fail to rollover log file when evaluateOnStartup is true.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1474&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1474&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; but there are still several other flaws. Maybe you can check my patch. Please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1649&quot; title=&quot;CronTriggeringPolicy breaks awefully when using &amp;quot;reconfigure&amp;quot; of LoggerContext&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1649&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1649&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; too.&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15791886" author="ralph.goers@dslextreme.com" created="Mon, 2 Jan 2017 00:21:09 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I ended up implementing the getTimeBefore method so I didn&apos;t have to use cronutils. I used most of the other stuff in your patch but I found quite a few more issues besides what you found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please verify the fix and close if it works for you,&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15792863" author="gfriedrich" created="Mon, 2 Jan 2017 13:26:41 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Ralph,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;thank you for taking a look at it.&lt;br/&gt;
Even though I can test you code not before next week, I checked the changes you made and I have found some issues that might still arise with it (to say it again: I didn&apos;t execute your code - I just took a look into it).&lt;br/&gt;
The following things look weird to me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;There is a reason that &quot;getTimeBefore&quot; was not implemented in Quartz as it can&apos;t be easily implemented. Your solution will only work for some situations (even though these are the mainly appearing ones). Imagine the following cron expression: 0 0 35/10 * * *&lt;br/&gt;
This expression would be true on the minutes 35, 45 and 55 on every hour. As you are expecting that all intervals have the same size, you would get some problems here. E.g. when it&apos;s &quot;10:30 am&quot; you would calculate 35 and 45 as the next execution minutes. Then you would subtract  the differenct from the current time (&amp;#45;&amp;gt; 10:20 am) and then calculating the next valid time (&amp;#45;&amp;gt; 10:35 am). This is obviously not the expected time of &quot;9:55 am&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You didn&apos;t remove the &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot;-line from &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot;. This is problematic for the following reasons:
	&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; can still be called multiple times as it is used in &quot;setTriggeringPolicy(...)&quot; and in the &quot;initialize()&quot; method which results in multiple schedule calls and therefore multiple executions of the same trigger.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; might get called in &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot; even though &quot;compareAndSet&quot; fails. You should make sure that &quot;compareAndSet&quot; was executed successfully before changing any additional stuff that you&apos;ve just added (those new lifecycle lines).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think I&apos;ve also found an issue for the changes you made for &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1649&quot; title=&quot;CronTriggeringPolicy breaks awefully when using &amp;quot;reconfigure&amp;quot; of LoggerContext&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1649&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1649&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. But I will add the comment over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Oh I just saw that the &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; was a problem of &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/LOG4J2-1649&quot; title=&quot;CronTriggeringPolicy breaks awefully when using &amp;quot;reconfigure&amp;quot; of LoggerContext&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;LOG4J2-1649&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;LOG4J2-1649&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. So that should most probably fixed over there. Nevertheless it&apos;s a problem...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15793343" author="ralph.goers@dslextreme.com" created="Mon, 2 Jan 2017 19:05:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;1. The right solution is to make getTimeBefore work correctly.  I could do that using cron-utils but that would only fix the TriggeringPolicy for Java 8, which is not really acceptable. I&apos;ll have to look into what else can be done.&lt;br/&gt;
2. I modified the initialize method to only initialize once, which eliminates the problems you noted.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15793616" author="gfriedrich" created="Mon, 2 Jan 2017 22:28:49 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;1. I totally understand that you want to support more than Java 8 (what is already written in the ticket description) - but the current approach is not correct either.&lt;br/&gt;
2. I saw that but it does NOT fix the problem as the &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; is still written in the &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot;. Basically the &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot; is called first on the RollingFileManager and after that the normal &quot;initialize&quot; method of the same class is called. And so it is still called twice resulting in two calls of the scheduler. I would expect to have the &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; method only at one place. Is there a reason why you didn&apos;t want to remove the line from &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot; when &quot;initialize&quot; is called anyway? Then you wouldn&apos;t need the boolean flag stuff at all.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15793658" author="gfriedrich" created="Mon, 2 Jan 2017 23:01:25 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;1. Mhh it seems that all fixes of cron-utils 5.x are backported to 4.x which uses the old Date/Time handling of Java. So you could think about using cron-utils 4.x&lt;br/&gt;
2. Just checked the code again. I now understand that &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; is called from &quot;initialize&quot; on the first run and from &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot; on all further runs (e.g. when the Log4J context gets reconfigured). Even though this might work it makes the code much more complicated as it gets harder to understand. As said maybe you think about removing it from &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot;. And as also said you should make sure that &quot;compareAndSet&quot; worked successfully - otherwise using those CAS methods is quite useless.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15793746" author="remkop@yahoo.com" created="Tue, 3 Jan 2017 00:15:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Rather than introducing another external dependency just to support every nock and cranny in the cron syntax, we can also decide to support only a (large) subset of the cron syntax. &lt;br/&gt;
Ideally we&apos;d document what is not supported. For example, we only support regular intervals. That seems reasonable to me...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15793756" author="remkop@yahoo.com" created="Tue, 3 Jan 2017 00:23:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Based on the description,  &lt;tt&gt;getTimeBefore&lt;/tt&gt; is used to calculate the previous rollover time. A simpler alternative is to remember (cache) the time at which rollover occurred so it can be referenced during the next rollover. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15793777" author="gfriedrich" created="Tue, 3 Jan 2017 00:38:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;A good idea but the problem is that we need that time when the service was just started to get the information whether a rollover should have happened while the service was offline. So we don&apos;t have any cached values at this point in time ...&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15794181" author="ralph.goers@dslextreme.com" created="Tue, 3 Jan 2017 05:18:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;1. I now have a version of getTimeBefore that passes all my unit tests. It is pretty crude but it seems to work.  I still might consider using cron-utils 4.x if there are other problems with the solution I have implemented.&lt;br/&gt;
2. I have modified the code to verify the compare and swap worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take a look again.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15794618" author="gfriedrich" created="Tue, 3 Jan 2017 09:30:13 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for doing another change, but there is still something left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You could remove the &quot;findIncrement&quot; method in the &quot;CronExpression&quot; class as it is not used anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The &quot;shutdown&quot; method leaves all scheduled tasks scheduled, so you will most probably always run into the first timeout. In worst case a scheduled task started the execution while awaiting the first termination which again results in the interruption of this task as you call &quot;shutdownNow&quot; after the timeout. I don&apos;t see the reason why you don&apos;t clear the queue before calling &quot;shutdown&quot; (as in the patch).&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The new &quot;getTimeBefore&quot; method seems to have a slightly different contract than &quot;getTimeAfter&quot;. &quot;getTimeAfter&quot; only returns timestamps that are really after the given timestamp (even when the timestamp matches the cron expression). &quot;getTimeBefore&quot; might return the targetDate as the while loop only uses &quot;after&quot; without checking the equality of both timestamps.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;You should also consider some &quot;abort&quot; case. Just in case something is horribly wrong. &quot;getTimeAfter&quot; uses a case where year gets above 2999. Maybe use something like &quot;if year is below 1970 -&amp;gt; abort&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In &quot;setTriggeringPolicy&quot; &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot; might still be called without a successful &quot;compareAndSet&quot;. This results in a scheduled TriggeringPolicy which is not set in the RollingFileManager. You should move this line into the if-statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</comment>
                            <comment id="15795115" author="ralph.goers@dslextreme.com" created="Tue, 3 Jan 2017 13:55:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reviewing the code again. I will look at the changes you are suggesting and make one more commit.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15797306" author="ralph.goers@dslextreme.com" created="Wed, 4 Jan 2017 06:16:35 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I made more changes based on your feedback. Please take another look.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15797769" author="gfriedrich" created="Wed, 4 Jan 2017 09:31:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thanks Ralph. Looks fine to me now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just out of interest: Is there a reason why you decided not to move the &quot;triggeringPolicy.initialize(this)&quot;-line? I mean, there is still a very very very small chance that the scheduler starts executing the task directly after scheduling it (even though it&apos;s very unlikely).&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15798323" author="ralph.goers@dslextreme.com" created="Wed, 4 Jan 2017 13:58:21 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;If the triggeringPolicy is set in the Manager before it is initialized I am afraid that things like calling checkRollover might get some kind of exception.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15801716" author="gfriedrich" created="Thu, 5 Jan 2017 15:58:01 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will give you an update on Monday whether the new code is working for me or not.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="15810883" author="gfriedrich" created="Mon, 9 Jan 2017 07:07:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=ralph.goers%40dslextreme.com&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;ralph.goers@dslextreme.com&quot;&gt;ralph.goers@dslextreme.com&lt;/a&gt; I&apos;m happy to tell you that it&apos;s now working properly for me. &lt;img class=&quot;emoticon&quot; src=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/emoticons/smile.png&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot; align=&quot;absmiddle&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some basic tests with a rollover every minute and a possible rollover on startup. All files were named correctly and there were no exceptions or whatsoever.&lt;br/&gt;
Thanks for your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there already any release date set for 2.8?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                <issuelinks>
                            <issuelinktype id="12310060">
                    <name>Container</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="contains">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12992228">LOG4J2-1474</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12993501">LOG4J2-1487</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13008457">LOG4J2-1621</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13011020">LOG4J2-1640</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                            <issuelinktype id="10030">
                    <name>Reference</name>
                                            <outwardlinks description="relates to">
                                        <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13014727">LOG4J2-1649</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12992228">LOG4J2-1474</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="12993501">LOG4J2-1487</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
            <issuelink>
            <issuekey id="13011020">LOG4J2-1640</issuekey>
        </issuelink>
                            </outwardlinks>
                                                        </issuelinktype>
                    </issuelinks>
                <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12835786" name="ConfigurationScheduler.patch" size="1346" author="GFriedrich" created="Fri, 28 Oct 2016 10:39:45 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12835787" name="CronTriggeringPolicy.patch" size="3542" author="GFriedrich" created="Fri, 28 Oct 2016 10:39:45 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>2.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[false]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310250" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.customfieldtypes:multicheckboxes">
                        <customfieldname>Flags</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                                <customfieldvalue key="10430"><![CDATA[Patch]]></customfieldvalue>
    
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            8 years, 45 weeks, 2 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|i35jcf:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>