<!-- 
RSS generated by JIRA (8.20.10#820010-sha1:ace47f9899e9ee25d7157d59aa17ab06aee30d3d) at Wed Nov 12 07:16:43 UTC 2025

It is possible to restrict the fields that are returned in this document by specifying the 'field' parameter in your request.
For example, to request only the issue key and summary append 'field=key&field=summary' to the URL of your request.
-->
<rss version="0.92" >
<channel>
    <title>ASF Jira</title>
    <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira</link>
    <description>This file is an XML representation of an issue</description>
    <language>en-uk</language>    <build-info>
        <version>8.20.10</version>
        <build-number>820010</build-number>
        <build-date>22-06-2022</build-date>
    </build-info>


<item>
            <title>[SUREFIRE-1719] Race condition results in &quot;VM crash or System.exit called?&quot; failure</title>
                <link>https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SUREFIRE-1719</link>
                <project id="12317927" key="SUREFIRE">Maven Surefire (Moved to GitHub Issues)</project>
                    <description>&lt;p&gt;After upgrading surefire in our project (dCache) from 2.19.1 to 3.0.0-M3, unit tests started to fail with the message &quot;ExecutionException The forked VM terminated without properly saying goodbye. VM crash or System.exit called?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference, the command I am using to verify this problem is &quot;mvn -am -pl modules/common clean package&quot; and the surefire configuration is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&amp;lt;plugin&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160; &amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;org.apache.maven.plugins&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160; &amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;maven-surefire-plugin&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160; &amp;lt;configuration&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;includes&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;include&amp;gt;**/*Test.class&amp;lt;/include&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;include&amp;gt;**/*Tests.class&amp;lt;/include&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;/includes&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;!-- dCache uses the singleton anti-pattern in way&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; too many places. That unfortunately means we have&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; to accept the overhead of forking each test run. --&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;forkCount&amp;gt;1C&amp;lt;/forkCount&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160;&#160;&#160; &amp;lt;reuseForks&amp;gt;false&amp;lt;/reuseForks&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;tt&gt;&#160; &amp;lt;/configuration&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
{{ &amp;lt;/plugin&amp;gt;}}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;The complete pom.xml is attached.&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem is not always present. On our build machine, I&apos;ve seen the problem appear 6 out of 10 times when running the above mvn command. There is (apparently) little that seems to influence whether the build will succeed or fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;I&amp;#39;ve attached the complete output from running the above mvn command, both the normal output and including the -e -X options.&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem seems to appear only on machines with a &quot;large&quot; number of cores. Our build machine has 24 cores, and I&apos;ve seen a report of a similar problem where building dCache on a 48 core machine. On the other side, I have been unable to reproduce the problem with my desktop machine (8 core) or on my laptop (4 cores).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What seems to matter is the number of actually running JVM instances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not been able to reproduce the problem by increasing the forkCount on a machine with a small number of cores. However, I&apos;ve noticed that, on an 8 core machine, increasing the forkCount does not actually result in that many more JVM instances running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, experience shows that reducing the number of concurrent JVM instances &quot;fixes&quot; the problem. A forkCount of 6 seems to bring the likelihood of a problem below 10% (0 failures with 10 builds) on our build machine.  On this machine, the default configuration would try to run 24 JVM instances concurrently (forkCount of &quot;1C&quot; on a 24 core machine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem appears to have been introduced in surefire v2.20. When building with surefire v2.19.1, the above mvn command is always successful on our build machine.  Building with surefire v2.20 results in intermittent failures (~60% failure rate).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using git bisection (and with the criterion for &quot;good&quot; as zero failures in 10 build attempts), I was able to determine that commit da7ff6aa2 &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SUREFIRE-1342&quot; title=&quot;Acknowledge normal exit of JVM and drain shared memory between processes&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SUREFIRE-1342&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SUREFIRE-1342&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Acknowledge normal exit of JVM and drain shared memory between processes&quot; is the first commit where surefire has this intermittent failure behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a causal scan through the patch, my guess is that the BYE_ACK support it introduces is somehow racy (for example, reading or updating a field-member outside of a monitor) and problems are triggered if there are a large number of JVMs exiting concurrently.  So, with increased number of concurrent JVMs there is an increased risk of a thread loosing the race, and so triggering this error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such a problem would be consistent with observed behaviour.  However, I don&apos;t have any strong evidence that this is what is happening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <environment></environment>
        <key id="13268265">SUREFIRE-1719</key>
            <summary>Race condition results in &quot;VM crash or System.exit called?&quot; failure</summary>
                <type id="1" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/viewavatar?size=xsmall&amp;avatarId=21133&amp;avatarType=issuetype">Bug</type>
                                            <priority id="3" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/priorities/major.svg">Major</priority>
                        <status id="6" iconUrl="https://issues.apache.org/jira/images/icons/statuses/closed.png" description="The issue is considered finished, the resolution is correct. Issues which are not closed can be reopened.">Closed</status>
                    <statusCategory id="3" key="done" colorName="green"/>
                                    <resolution id="1">Fixed</resolution>
                                        <assignee username="tibordigana">Tibor Digana</assignee>
                                    <reporter username="paulmillar">Paul Millar</reporter>
                        <labels>
                    </labels>
                <created>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 09:53:40 +0000</created>
                <updated>Fri, 4 Jul 2025 07:34:42 +0000</updated>
                            <resolved>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 02:33:15 +0000</resolved>
                                    <version>2.20</version>
                    <version>2.20.1</version>
                    <version>2.21.0</version>
                    <version>2.22.0</version>
                    <version>2.22.1</version>
                    <version>2.22.2</version>
                    <version>3.0.0-M1</version>
                    <version>3.0.0-M2</version>
                    <version>3.0.0-M3</version>
                                    <fixVersion>3.0.0-M5</fixVersion>
                                    <component>Maven Surefire Plugin</component>
                        <due></due>
                            <votes>0</votes>
                                    <watches>4</watches>
                                                                                                                <comments>
                            <comment id="16975652" author="tibor17" created="Sat, 16 Nov 2019 09:41:22 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Thx for having a look into this issue.&lt;br/&gt;
I want to ask you to follow the test instruction from &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.apache.org/thread.html/6b9987be2fbd4d82daf8aaabbd1d58dfa2a533598770e0423d0b5ee0@%3Cdev.maven.apache.org%3E&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;current release vote&lt;/a&gt; and repeat the tests with the version 3.0.0-M4. Code changes have been made in those parts you described, &lt;tt&gt;ForkedBooter&lt;/tt&gt; and &lt;tt&gt;CommandReader&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
Regarding the fields, i checked the instance fields used by &lt;tt&gt;acknowledgedExit()&lt;/tt&gt; in the &lt;tt&gt;ForkedBooter&lt;/tt&gt;. I remember that i fixed a race in old version of the plugin one or two years ago, so i did not expect a new similar issue happening again. Pls see our code on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/maven-surefire/blob/master/surefire-booter/src/main/java/org/apache/maven/surefire/booter/ForkedBooter.java#L354&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and feel free to come with some findings. We will definitely have a look.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16975676" author="tibor17" created="Sat, 16 Nov 2019 11:13:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=paulmillar&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;paulmillar&quot;&gt;paulmillar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Pls configure your CI system so that you will be able to handle build files from the file system in CI and observe the dump files located in &lt;tt&gt;target/surefire-reports&lt;/tt&gt;. These streams use to be corrupted by native logs printed by JVM GC in the std/out and std/in. Try to make the GC quiet for to confirm this hypothesis. My suspicion is that GC corrupted the std/out stream and the BYE event was lost. This has happenedat the end after all tests completed and GC printed the messages at the time when the forked JVM sent BYE and the fork was waiting for next 30 seconds for the acknowledgement and killed itself if not arived.&lt;br/&gt;
We will introduce TCP connector instead of process pipes in 3.0.0-M5, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SUREFIRE-1658&quot; title=&quot;TCP/IP Channel for forked Surefire JVM. Extensions API and SPI. Polymorphism for remote and local process communication.&quot; class=&quot;issue-link&quot; data-issue-key=&quot;SUREFIRE-1658&quot;&gt;&lt;del&gt;SUREFIRE-1658&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile i would like you to confirm this problem with corrupted stream which can be seen in the dump file produced by Surefire.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16976582" author="paulmillar" created="Mon, 18 Nov 2019 14:07:53 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Tibor,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a quick update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve been able to reproduce the problem with Surefire v3.0.0-M4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running the same command (mvn -am -pl modules/common clean package), the unit-tests failed with a similar output as reported above.  I attempted building with v3.0.0-M4 ten times and all attempts failed.  This is seemingly a worse failure rate than described above; although, if this is a race-condition, external factors may be having an impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is building on a 24-core machine.  As before, updating the pom.xml to set forkCount from &quot;1C&quot; (== 24) to &quot;6&quot; results in all ten build attempts passing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the error message mentioning *.dump and *.dumpstream files, I see no such files in the target/surefire-reports directory.  I also checked /tmp and /var/tmp: no such files are there, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m not sure which options I should add to avoid GC logging: I believe this is off by default.  If you have a concrete suggestion, I&apos;d be happy to try it out.  I&apos;m using OpenJDK &quot;v1.8.0_232&quot; JRE &quot;1.8.0_232-b09&quot;, OpenJDK 64-bit server (build 25.232-b09, mixed mode).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One additional observation.  The &quot;modules/common&quot; module has 35 test  classes.  For each of the 35 classes, I see maven logs that is is running that class (lines like &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;INFO&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; Running org.dcache....&quot;).  However, there are &lt;b&gt;fewer&lt;/b&gt; logged test result lines (lines like &quot;&lt;span class=&quot;error&quot;&gt;&amp;#91;INFO&amp;#93;&lt;/span&gt; Tests run: x, Failures: x, Errors: x, ....&quot;).  So, maven/surefire is not logging a result line for some test classes, despite (apparently) starting that JVM. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specific &quot;missing&quot; results changes from run to run.  The precise number of missing test class results also changes: sometimes only one class is missing, sometimes it&apos;s two classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each test class with a test result line, there is a corresponding .txt and .xml file in results/surefire-reports directory.  However, the test classes that have no test result line also have no corresponding .txt or .xml file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTH,&lt;br/&gt;
Paul.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16976598" author="tibor17" created="Mon, 18 Nov 2019 14:31:34 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=paulmillar&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;paulmillar&quot;&gt;paulmillar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It&apos;s strange that you do not have the dump files. I do not have access to your system, so the best would be if you deploy Surefire with orthogonal SNAPSHOT version on your Nexus repo and let the CI to run the build. Comment out the parts of the code in ForkedBooter and ForkStarter where you have suspicions. I could do the same if i had to access your system. This is the way to confirm the bug. And then we have to investigate deeper.&lt;br/&gt;
Make sure that your system, especially the file system, is okay and the machine does not run out of resources.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16977849" author="tibor17" created="Tue, 19 Nov 2019 21:48:07 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I am analysing the latest code and the commit da7ff6aa2 as well but stil did not find anything with the error.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16977946" author="tibor17" created="Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:11:38 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=paulmillar&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;paulmillar&quot;&gt;paulmillar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I found the problem but it is horrible because this was not found in our internal tests and I believe that all people had to have this problem but nobody had reported it!&lt;br/&gt;
The whole problem is with the use and design of the interface &lt;tt&gt;ImmediateCommands.acknowledgeByeEventReceived()&lt;/tt&gt;. This is shared interface across all forks.&lt;br/&gt;
If you take a look in the ForkStarter, ForkClient and ForkedBooter you see BYE-&amp;gt;ACK-&amp;gt;EXIT0 and it is clearly logical what happens before and what happens after. The same code tells you that the ACK must be sent ouf of order in this bug - a kind of distributed race and this has really happened. Because the users do not use such fast CPUs therefore nobody found this race.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16978189" author="paulmillar" created="Wed, 20 Nov 2019 08:27:37 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Tibor,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good to hear you&apos;ve found the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there something I can do to confirm it?  For example, if you have a private branch of surefire with additional logging, I could build that version, deploy it as a snapshot in our private nexus and exercise building dCache.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="16978304" author="tibor17" created="Wed, 20 Nov 2019 10:44:06 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;I will inform you when i have something in a branch.&lt;br/&gt;
This is not the easiest part of the code but nevetheless I am asking everybody the same question if you are open to contribute with writing the code.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17004367" author="tibor17" created="Sat, 28 Dec 2019 01:15:20 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=paulmillar&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;paulmillar&quot;&gt;paulmillar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Hi Paul,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are in the office to check it out with a new snapshot version of Surefire &lt;tt&gt;3.0.0-SNAPSHOT&lt;/tt&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thx T&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17004616" author="tibor17" created="Sun, 29 Dec 2019 02:33:16 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=maven-surefire.git;a=commit;h=2e65fb28b2f0d2e731a16956b8abb14fcada6d01&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;https://gitbox.apache.org/repos/asf?p=maven-surefire.git;a=commit;h=2e65fb28b2f0d2e731a16956b8abb14fcada6d01&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17009517" author="paulmillar" created="Tue, 7 Jan 2020 08:51:40 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Hi Tibor,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve tested the 3.0.0-SNAPSHOT and it works perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all you help!&lt;br/&gt;
Paul.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17010135" author="tibor17" created="Tue, 7 Jan 2020 22:10:19 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=paulmillar&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;paulmillar&quot;&gt;paulmillar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
I am glad that it works for you. Pls use the version for some time because important changes have to be made in January and then we will cut a new release version.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17073728" author="tigran" created="Thu, 2 Apr 2020 13:33:03 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;As M5 is not released yet, can we just  set forkCount=1 as a workaround?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17074071" author="tibor17" created="Thu, 2 Apr 2020 20:34:26 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;You can do it meanwhile. We are finishing the biggest task and then we will be hopefully very fast with easy tasks.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17074781" author="tigran" created="Fri, 3 Apr 2020 18:19:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately even with current master I can see the error:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;code panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;codeContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&quot;code-java&quot;&gt;
[INFO] ------------------------------------------------------------------------
[ERROR] Failed to execute goal org.apache.maven.plugins:maven-surefire-plugin:3.0.0-SNAPSHOT:test (&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;default&lt;/span&gt;-test) on project dcache-common: There are test failures.
[ERROR] 
[ERROR] Please refer to /home/tigran/eProjects/dcache-git/modules/common/target/surefire-reports &lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; the individual test results.
[ERROR] Please refer to dump files (&lt;span class=&quot;code-keyword&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; any exist) [date].dump, [date]-jvmRun[N].dump and [date].dumpstream.
[ERROR] ExecutionException The forked VM terminated without properly saying goodbye. VM crash or &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;System&lt;/span&gt;.exit called?
[ERROR] Command was /bin/sh -c cd /home/tigran/eProjects/dcache-git/modules/common &amp;amp;&amp;amp; /usr/lib/jvm/java-11-openjdk-11.0.6.10-0.fc31.x86_64/bin/java &lt;span class=&quot;code-quote&quot;&gt;&apos;${argLine}&apos;&lt;/span&gt; --add-modules=java.security.jgss -jar /home/tigran/eProjects/dcache-git/modules/common/target/surefire/surefirebooter15798824340157134030.jar /home/tigran/eProjects/dcache-git/modules/common/target/surefire 2020-04-03T20-17-52_663-jvmRun1 surefire6874474157466927398tmp surefire_59109352228556929562tmp
[ERROR] Error occurred in starting fork, check output in log
[ERROR] &lt;span class=&quot;code-object&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/span&gt; Exit Code: 1


&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17074820" author="tibor17" created="Fri, 3 Apr 2020 18:58:30 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tigran&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tigran&quot;&gt;tigran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
99% of these logs are useless. You can simply call &lt;tt&gt;System.exit(0)&lt;/tt&gt; in your test and you get the same logs many other people have on this planet with totally different root cause.&lt;br/&gt;
So you should checkout the &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/browse/SUREFIRE-1719?focusedCommentId=17004616&amp;amp;page=com.atlassian.jira.plugin.system.issuetabpanels:comment-tabpanel#comment-17004616&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;commit&lt;/a&gt; and build the plugin locally using &lt;tt&gt;mvn install -DskipTests&lt;/tt&gt; and run your tests in your project in offline mode &lt;tt&gt;mvn -o test&lt;/tt&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
Again you may have error but root cause is maybe different from what &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=paulmillar&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;paulmillar&quot;&gt;paulmillar&lt;/a&gt; had. How can you prove that you have his root cause?&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17074932" author="tigran" created="Fri, 3 Apr 2020 22:14:56 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;Well, as Paul and I working together and on the same project I am pretty sure that this is the same issue.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17075060" author="tibor17" created="Sat, 4 Apr 2020 06:50:28 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tigran&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tigran&quot;&gt;tigran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My notices how to investigate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the commit. Please have a look and see the history of further changes on GitHuib whether there is some change which overrides these changes. I believe there are not such cases. But you should check it as many users do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, very important notice is that SNAPSHOT is always risky to take because we are working on PR #240 and this is still incomplete and this PR deploys the same SNAPSHOT version. Most probably you are testing with that. So my recommendation is to checkout the project on your side, build the project without tests which installs the artifacts to the local repo, and run your test on identical hardware Paul has used. If it fails then please see the dump file (the path is written in your log) and you may find the root cause.&lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17075061" author="tibor17" created="Sat, 4 Apr 2020 07:00:57 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.apache.org/jira/secure/ViewProfile.jspa?name=tigran&quot; class=&quot;user-hover&quot; rel=&quot;tigran&quot;&gt;tigran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
See the dump file. Your log talks about this advice too:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;preformatted panel&quot; style=&quot;border-width: 1px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;preformattedContent panelContent&quot;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Please refer to /home/tigran/eProjects/dcache-git/modules/common/target/surefire-reports for the individual test results.
Please refer to dump files (if any exist) [date].dump, [date]-jvmRun[N].dump and [date].dumpstream.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</comment>
                            <comment id="17995115" author="olamy" created="Fri, 4 Jul 2025 07:34:42 +0000"  >&lt;p&gt;This project has moved from Jira to GitHub Issues. This issue was migrated to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/apache/maven-surefire/issues/2058&quot; class=&quot;external-link&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;apache/maven-surefire#2058&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</comment>
                    </comments>
                    <attachments>
                            <attachment id="12985840" name="build-error-debug.out" size="579546" author="paulmillar" created="Thu, 14 Nov 2019 09:48:16 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12985841" name="build.out" size="18403" author="paulmillar" created="Thu, 14 Nov 2019 09:48:09 +0000"/>
                            <attachment id="12985839" name="pom.xml" size="60843" author="paulmillar" created="Thu, 14 Nov 2019 09:49:57 +0000"/>
                    </attachments>
                <subtasks>
                    </subtasks>
                <customfields>
                                                                            <customfield id="customfield_12310310" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:attachments">
                        <customfieldname>Attachment count</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>3.0</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12314020" key="com.atlassian.jira.plugins.jira-development-integration-plugin:devsummary">
                        <customfieldname>Development</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12313422" key="com.atlassian.jirafisheyeplugin:jobcheckbox">
                        <customfieldname>Enable Automatic Patch Review</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue><![CDATA[no_permission]]></customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    <customfield id="customfield_12310420" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Global Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                        <customfield id="customfield_12312521" key="com.atlassian.jira.toolkit:LastCommentDate">
                        <customfieldname>Last public comment date</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            18 weeks, 4 days ago
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12311820" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-lexo-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>0|z08lrc:</customfieldvalue>

                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                <customfield id="customfield_12310920" key="com.pyxis.greenhopper.jira:gh-global-rank">
                        <customfieldname>Rank (Obsolete)</customfieldname>
                        <customfieldvalues>
                            <customfieldvalue>9223372036854775807</customfieldvalue>
                        </customfieldvalues>
                    </customfield>
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            </customfields>
    </item>
</channel>
</rss>